<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> d6270c9f-0ee5-42ba-9263-a2ed3ad559c8 </guid><title><![CDATA[Cameco increases 2023 revenue outlook]]></title><description><![CDATA[Substantial uranium spot price improvements have contributed to higher average realised prices, CEO Tim Gitzel said in the company&#39;s third-quarter results announcement which also included updates on the progress of the first shipment of its share of 2023 production from Inkai in Kazakhstan and news of a new senior appointment to head its UK subsidiary.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 23:46:48 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Cameco-increases-2023-revenue-outlook?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a7c05d43-276c-4c47-bb0f-7062f0ab1523 </guid><title><![CDATA[Westinghouse, EDF and KHNP submit final Czech bids]]></title><description><![CDATA[ČEZ subsidiary&nbsp;Elektrárna Dukovany II has received final bids from the three potential suppliers for a new nuclear unit at Dukovany, as well as non-binding offers for three more future reactors.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 12:46:49 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Westinghouse,-EDF-and-KHNP-submit-final-Czech-bids?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 6926a636-000f-4e2f-91d3-338524147561 </guid><title><![CDATA[Moltex announces waste recycling breakthrough]]></title><description><![CDATA[Laboratory experiments carried out using simulated fuel have substantially derisked the Waste To Stable Salt - or WATSS - process, and experiments using real used fuel are currently ongoing.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 15:56:25 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Moltex-announces-waste-recycling-breakthrough?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 31c35ade-b6e2-4a46-9293-6ce248bd5905 </guid><title><![CDATA[Construction under way of new Dutch radwaste facility]]></title><description><![CDATA[Work has begun on the Multifunctional Storage Building - a new storage building for low and intermediate-level waste - in Nieuwdorp, in the municipality of Borssele, in the Netherlands, the Central Organisation for Radioactive Waste announced.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 15:46:34 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Construction-under-way-of-new-Dutch-radwaste-facil?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> cca695f7-c990-401d-9ab8-e04591caa545 </guid><title><![CDATA[X-energy, Ares drop merger plan]]></title><description><![CDATA[Small modular reactor and advanced fuel technology developer X-Energy Reactor Company - known as X-energy - and Ares Acquisition Corporation have &quot;mutually agreed to terminate their previously announced business combination agreement, effective immediately&quot;.&nbsp;]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 14:32:53 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/X-energy,-Ares-drop-merger-plan?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 5bfa3ef1-3d47-4214-ba7c-676822e56516 </guid><title><![CDATA[CNEA and Nucleoeléctrica sign CAREM SMR agreement]]></title><description><![CDATA[The National Atomic Energy Commission and Nucleoeléctrica Argentina have signed a framework agreement for technical assistance for the country&#39;s CAREM small modular reactor project.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 15:13:31 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Argentina-s-SMR-CNEA-and-Nucleoelectrica-sign-agre?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 2f80cc6a-9ec1-4def-883c-5aee0825f6b5 </guid><title><![CDATA[Estonia nuclear preparations well organised, IAEA mission finds]]></title><description><![CDATA[Estonia has developed a comprehensive assessment of its nuclear power infrastructure needs to enable the government to decide whether to launch a nuclear power programme, an international team of experts has concluded.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 16:04:20 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Estonia-nuclear-preparations-well-organised,-IAEA?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 72be9154-e468-4ceb-9b16-2ae9a90a8f35 </guid><title><![CDATA[Cameco announces supply contract at Beijing uranium forum]]></title><description><![CDATA[The supply agreement with China Nuclear International Corporation was finalised earlier this year, Cameco said. The <em>2023国际天然铀产业发展论坛还介绍了中国国内铀事业的最新进展。]]>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 15:02:59 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Cameco-announces-supply-contract-at-Beijing-uraniu?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> c0e9cbc0-d230-4bb0-98c6-740dbb47a80e </guid><title><![CDATA[Zoning permit issued for new nuclear at Dukovany]]></title><description><![CDATA[The application for a zoning decision for up to two new nuclear power units at Dukovany in the Czech Republic was submitted in 2021 and ČEZ says the approval by the Ministry of Industry and Trade is a &quot;key milestone&quot;.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 14:06:48 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Zoning-permit-issued-for-new-Dukovany-nuclear-unit?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 5b1731bc-7434-411e-a318-7620c280a9c6 </guid><title><![CDATA[Poland's Pomerania backs proposed nuclear plant location]]></title><description><![CDATA[The decision by the regional authorities to determine the territorial scope - on both land and sea - of Poland&#39;s first nuclear power plant in the&nbsp;Lubiatowo-Kopalino site in the Choczewo municipality in Pomerania<strong>意味着 Polskie Elektrownie Jądrowe 已获得使用该区域进行筹备工作的权利。]]>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 09:47:37 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Poland-s-Pomerania-backs-proposed-nuclear-plant-lo?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 849e3370-d6b3-4a84-97e6-0c881ca6f961 </guid><title><![CDATA[Satu Katajala becomes WANO regional centre director]]></title><description><![CDATA[The World Association of Nuclear Operators has appointed Satu Katajala as its next Paris Centre Director in what it describes as a &quot;significant milestone in support of diversity in the nuclear industry&quot;.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 15:02:27 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Satu-Katajala-becomes WANO-regional-centre-directo?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>