<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 6cd3f55d-f340-4b96-8d36-315a2fe9fbee </guid><title><![CDATA[Work on Xudabao unit 1 gets under way]]></title><description><![CDATA[Construction has started of the nuclear island for unit 1 at the Xudabao nuclear power plant in Liaoning Province, China National Nuclear Corporation announced.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 14:05:52 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Work-on-Xudabao-unit-1-gets-under-way?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 441c3327-3127-4768-a0a6-69c153952606</guid><title><![CDATA[Agreement on post-ARENH nuclear electricity pricing]]></title><description><![CDATA[The French government and state-owned EDF have reached an agreement to regulate the price at which the utility&#39;s nuclear-generated electricity is sold to an average of EUR70 (USD76)&nbsp;per MWh once the current ARENH mechanism expires at the end of 2025.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 15:02:29 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Agreement-on-post-ARENH-nuclear-electricity-pricin?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> eeab1ed4-853d-4141-92f1-3700fba42527 </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA team completes Romanian regulatory review]]></title><description><![CDATA[Romania is committed to maintaining and strengthening its regulatory framework for nuclear and radiation safety, an International Atomic Energy Agency team of experts has concluded. However, the Integrated Regulatory Review Service mission team recommended improving the coordination among government agencies concerned with radiation source facilities and activities.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 15:50:43 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-team-completes-Romanian-regulatory-review?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f0628ec9-7a59-4d56-9c48-d9a516cb34f7 </guid><title><![CDATA[Permit granted for construction of eighth Leningrad unit]]></title><description><![CDATA[The main construction period for the VVER-1200 unit will begin in 2025 after the go-ahead was given to begin the second stage of the construction project for what will be the seventh and eighth units at Leningrad nuclear power plants.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 15:03:02 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Permission-granted-for-Leningrad-8-construction?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> e88da978-e311-42a0-884b-37e2dfbd4eca </guid><title><![CDATA[Agreement to spur US production of iridium isotope]]></title><description><![CDATA[A joint product agreement between the US Department of Energy Isotope Program and QSA Global Inc is intended to lead to the re-establishment of domestic production of iridium-192. The USA has been dependent on imports of the isotope for the last 20 years.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 10:46:06 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Agreement-to-spur-US-production-of-iridium-isotope?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ae7eced8-4a82-4a5c-80e8-d8e92e60921a </guid><title><![CDATA[Vallecitos reactor removal complete]]></title><description><![CDATA[Nearly 60 years after shutting down for the last time, the reactor vessel of the prototype boiling water reactor in California has been removed from its containment and shipped for final disposal by NorthStar Group Services, Inc.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 15:29:59 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Vallecitos-reactor-removal-complete?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 5599b79b-8af2-461f-ae9e-48cbfdca0649 </guid><title><![CDATA[Sixth NuScale SMR simulator opens, in Korea]]></title><description><![CDATA[NuScale Power Corporation has announced the opening of the first privately-funded NuScale Energy Exploration Centre at Seoul National University in partnership with GS Energy Corporation, Doosan Enerbility and Samsung C&amp;T Corporation.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 15:43:53 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Sixth-NuScale-SMR-simulator-opens-in-Korea?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> be3470b7-5de1-45d9-bd76-499642d69fb5</guid><title><![CDATA[Construction schedule agreed for Paks II in Hungary]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hungarian Foreign Minister&nbsp;Péter Szijjártó and Rosatom&#39;s Director General Alexei Likhachev have signed an agreement on the schedule for the construction of the Paks II nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 15:21:38 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Construction-schedule-agreed-for-Paks-II-in-Hungar?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 15ca51b8-0f9c-4cc4-bbc7-5cf525f12c5d </guid><title><![CDATA[ASN to extend deadline for upgrades to 900 MWe reactors]]></title><description><![CDATA[France&#39;s nuclear safety regulator, the Autorité de Sûreté Nucléaire, has said it is prepared to give EDF more time in order to implement safety upgrades required at its fleet of 900 MWe nuclear power reactors.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 14:46:25 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/ASN-to-extend-deadline-for-upgrades-to-900-MWe-rea?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 49595fb2-fda7-4b28-ab68-866f4695b337 </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA sees enhancement of Swiss nuclear security]]></title><description><![CDATA[An International Atomic Energy Agency team of experts has completed a follow-up nuclear security advisory mission to Switzerland. The International Physical Protection Advisory Service mission concluded Switzerland has strengthened its nuclear security regime since a mission in 2018.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 12:09:06 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-sees-enhancement-of-Swiss-nuclear-security?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 185087ec-6732-4bf1-955f-45067ac34459</guid><title><![CDATA[Illinois to lift moratorium on nuclear construction]]></title><description><![CDATA[Governor JB Pritzker has said he will sign a new bill lifting Illinois&#39; ban on the construction of new nuclear reactors, after the state&#39;s lawmakers passed new legislation that will allow the construction of small modular reactors of up to 300 MWe capacity from 2026.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 15:37:32 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Illinois-to-lift-moratorium-on-nuclear-constructio?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>