<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> e7c9f362-96b7-4494-8a52-f243d9f1b6a0 </guid><title><![CDATA[Takahama 2 reactor restarted]]></title><description><![CDATA[Unit 2 of the Takahama nuclear power plant in Japan&#39;s Fukui Prefecture has been restarted after being taken offline more than 12 years ago, Kansai Electric Power Company announced. The 780 MWe (net) pressurised water reactor becomes the 12th Japanese reactor to resume operation.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 11:04:09 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Takahama-2-reactor-restarted?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 240e5ab1-ddc4-4746-a0ca-cedd189e5c82 </guid><title><![CDATA[Bruce 6 re-enters commercial operation]]></title><description><![CDATA[Unit 6 at the site in Ontario was declared commercially operational on 14 September - 39 years to the day after it was first declared in service on 14 September 1984.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 14:26:54 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Bruce-6-re-enters-commercial-operation?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> CB06656b-70ff-457a-8edd-6ead511212f4 </guid><title><![CDATA[Demonstration reactor to be built in Rwanda]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Rwanda Atomic Energy Board has signed an agreement with Dual Fluid to collaborate on the development of a demonstration Dual Fluid nuclear reactor in Rwanda. The demonstration reactor is expected to be operational by 2026.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 16:38:10 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Demonstration-reactor-to-be-built-in-Rwanda?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7c687ff5-009a-4f4f-80d3-1b5f564bcae0 </guid><title><![CDATA[Hyundai builds partnerships in Poland]]></title><description><![CDATA[South Korea&#39;s Hyundai Engineering &amp; Construction has signed a series of agreements with Polish institutions and construction companies in an effort to tap into the country&#39;s nuclear power and infrastructure markets. The company is also establishing an office in Warsaw to create &quot;a bridgehead&quot; for entering other Eastern European markets.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 13:52:44 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Hyundai-builds-partnerships-in-Poland?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> eb64e4e5-685b-41ee-9ff1-ef2b550f6100 </guid><title><![CDATA[Constellation, ComEd in landmark energy-matching deal]]></title><description><![CDATA[The hourly carbon-free energy matching agreement will see ComEd power all its offices and metered facilities with locally produced nuclear energy, in a &#39;first&#39; for an investor-owned US utility. Constellation earlier this year signed a similar hourly energy matching agreement to power a Microsoft data centre.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 13:46:53 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Constellation,-ComEd-in-landmark-energy-matching-d?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 24a09a57-a2f3-438d-a2eb-be8f7f65d656 </guid><title><![CDATA[Turkey 'at important point' in China nuclear plant talks]]></title><description><![CDATA[Turkey&#39;s Energy Minister Alparslan Bayraktar has said the country is in talks with Russia about a second nuclear plant, and with China for a third one - and has also held out the ambition of adding 5 GW of small modular reactor capacity to the country&#39;s energy system by 2050.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 13:23:20 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Turkey-at-important-point-in-China-nuclear-plant-t?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ca71feea-9584-4e3f-8d08-09cdae506fb7 </guid><title><![CDATA[X-energy to develop second Project Pele microreactor design]]></title><description><![CDATA[The US Department of Defense has awarded a contract option to X-energy, LLC to develop an enhanced engineering design for a transportable microreactor suitable for both commercial and defence use under the Project Pele initiative. This second design would be complementary to the prototype microreactor which is being built by BWX Technologies.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 14:14:16 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/X-energy-to-develop-second-Project-Pele-microreact?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 6f6a06c2-431e-4943-9574-b0bf685f4335 </guid><title><![CDATA[More funding to progress UK nuclear-generated hydrogen project]]></title><description><![CDATA[An EDF-led consortium has been awarded UK government funding to further develop plans to use heat and electricity from Heysham 2 to create hydrogen for use in the production of asphalt and cement. Earlier this year, a feasibility study demonstrated the significant benefit the project would bring in proving how nuclear could power hydrogen electrolysis.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 14:46:42 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/More-funding-to-progress-UK-nuclear-generated-hydr?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f9948f1c-6a69-4299-851c-5806f68bf145 </guid><title><![CDATA[Tokamak Energy reports Demo4 milestone cryogenic tests]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tokamak Energy says its engineers have successfully validated electromagnetic current test results of the first of 14 toroidal field limbs in liquid nitrogen at temperatures of -200 degrees Celsius.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 13:40:37 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Tokamak-Energy-reports-Demo4-milestone-cryogenic-t?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 1dc719a4-eefe-4d5b-9e9d-2d6c7de54950 </guid><title><![CDATA[Shelf-M project being developed for Sovinoye gold deposit]]></title><description><![CDATA[Rosatom&#39;s mining division Atomredmetzoloto JSC and RAOS JSC have signed an agreement to cooperate on plans for a Shelf-M small nuclear power plant project at the Sovinoye gold deposit in Chukotka in Russia&#39;s far east.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 10:36:39 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Shelf-M-project-being-developed-for-Sovinoye-gold?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f03abb47-41b7-4032-833a-8bc9d0279ea0 </guid><title><![CDATA[Palisades restart takes 'giant step' with Holtec-Wolverine deal]]></title><description><![CDATA[A long-term power purchase agreement signed between Holtec Palisades Energy and the non-profit Wolverine Power Cooperative is described as a &quot;significant milestone&quot; towards restarting the 800 MW Palisades nuclear power plant in the USA.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 11:08:13 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Palisades-restart-takes-giant-step-with-Holtec-Wol?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>