<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 5677181e-c5f5-454a-a459-ef511c9efe33 </guid><title><![CDATA[Bruce Power explores technology options for nuclear expansion]]></title><description><![CDATA[Bruce Power announced it is launching an Expression of Interest process to &quot;further understand nuclear technologies that could help meet growing demand for clean electricity and advance decarbonisation efforts in Ontario&quot;. In July, the provincial government said it was starting pre-development work to build up to 4800 MWe of new nuclear capacity at Bruce Power&#39;s existing site.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 11:31:41 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Bruce-Power-explores-technology-options-for-nuclea?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 975e92d9-82ac-4d58-8952-66a6148ffd3e </guid><title><![CDATA[Reactor vessel in place at Tianwan 7]]></title><description><![CDATA[The reactor vessel has been installed at unit 7 of the Tianwan nuclear power plant in China&#39;s Jiangsu province. Russia is constructing two VVER-1200 reactors as units 7 and 8 of the plant.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 14:34:13 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Reactor-vessel-in-place-at-Tianwan-7?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 86cf4af2-d451-453d-80fb-36fef03e3ad7 </guid><title><![CDATA[Canadian provinces announce collaborative coal phase-out plans]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Government of Canada has announced nearly CAD20 million (USD15 million) in federal funding to support the provinces of Nova Scotia and New Brunswick to help enable a phase-out of coal-fired electricity generation by 2030. The funding includes CAD7 million to support pre-development work for a small modular reactor at Point Lepreau in New Brunswick.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 14:59:15 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Canadian-provinces-announce-collaborative-coal-pha?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 6d682682-e0c6-43c2-8095-d65848bb8b8a </guid><title><![CDATA[Study to evaluate Lightbridge Fuel use in Candu reactors]]></title><description><![CDATA[Advanced nuclear fuel technology company Lightbridge Corporation is collaborating with Romania&#39;s Institutul de Cercetări Nucleare Pitești to perform an engineering study to assess the compatibility and suitability of its Lightbridge Fuel for use in Candu pressurised heavy water reactors.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 13:46:23 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Study-to-evaluate-Lightbridge-Fuel-use-in-Candu-re?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 97ad47dc-b7b0-46b9-88d1-fa633af6fdd9 </guid><title><![CDATA[MBIR reactor block roof completed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Construction of Russia&#39;s MBIR multipurpose sodium-cooled fast neutron research reactor has reached a fresh milestone with the installation of the building&#39;s dome.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 13:42:51 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/MBIR-reactor-block-roof-completed?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 5c31e559-3fcf-4370-ac78-1c8ce850ac38 </guid><title><![CDATA[Mochovce 3 successfully completes commissioning process]]></title><description><![CDATA[Slovenské elektrárne has announced that the new Mochovce 3 unit has successfully completed a 144-hour demonstration run at full reactor power - and been welcomed into their nuclear fleet.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 12:10:58 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Energy-start-up-of-Mochovce-3-completed?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> c10f1b65-65c4-4fdc-a672-9d7f9e39f043 </guid><title><![CDATA[Nuclear to be part of US clean hydrogen hubs]]></title><description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden and Energy Secretary Jennifer Granholm have announced seven regional clean hydrogen hubs that will share USD7 billion in federal funding to accelerate the commercial-scale deployment of low-cost, clean hydrogen. Nuclear energy features in the plans of several of them, including a large nuclear-powered clean hydrogen production facility at Constellation&#39;s LaSalle plant in Illinois.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 09:18:16 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Nuclear-to-be-part-of-US-clean-hydrogen-hubs?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ec12433b-68f1-4efe-b85e-b39a35f2d3d2 </guid><title><![CDATA[Podcast: World Nuclear Symposium 2023 special report]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>核燃料报告、融资、招聘、工厂寿命优化和净零核启动都是在伦敦举行的行业全球聚会上举行的高级别小组讨论的总结。</p> ]]>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 08:46:58 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Podcast-World-Nuclear-Symposium-2023-special-repor?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 11d788a7-7de6-4b8d-a7ae-3fec7e525831 </guid><title><![CDATA[Sweden and UK agree to enhance cooperation in nuclear]]></title><description><![CDATA[A strategic partnership has been signed between the UK and Sweden aimed at &quot;reinvigorated and deepened cooperation across the bilateral relationship, including on security and defence, innovation, science, energy and climate, people to people and trade and investment&quot;. It includes cooperation on nuclear reactor technologies, including small modular reactors, and diversifying nuclear fuel supplies.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 14:51:31 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Sweden-and-UK-agree-to-enhance-cooperation-in-nucl?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7a0c0a9e-07da-4a0c-93d9-9c14fa33af15 </guid><title><![CDATA[Full government support for Niger uranium project]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Government of Niger has confirmed its &quot;full support&quot; for Global Atomic Corporation&#39;s Dasa uranium project, the company has said. The project is still pencilled in to make its first yellowcake deliveries in 2025 and remains unimpaired by a recent US decision to put a hold on US Development Bank financing following the coup that took place in Niger earlier this year.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 14:05:36 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Full-government-support-for-Niger-uranium-project?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7966029c-b526-4922-ad23-7fac3f61c67f </guid><title><![CDATA[Nuclear fusion: New initiatives outlined at FEC 2023 conference]]></title><description><![CDATA[The first edition of <em>世界聚变展望和组建<em>世界聚变能源小组的</em>提议，以及整个行业的最新进展和英国东道主的新投资，已在<em>第 29 届国际原子能机构聚变能源会议</em>上公布。]]>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 12:54:30 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Nuclear-fusion-IAEA-sets-out-new-initiatives-at-FE?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>