<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a3e7f629-e598-4b3c-ad94-2b6b0f20cbe5 </guid><title><![CDATA[Swedish regulator proposes framework for expansion of nuclear]]></title><description><![CDATA[Sweden&#39;s Radiation Safety Authority has presented its final report to the government on how the regulatory framework for nuclear power should be developed and what other measures may be needed for nuclear power to be expanded in the country.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 11:56:38 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Swedish-regulator-proposes-framework-for-expansion?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> efb84472-a350-436b-9d52-05cf8501181c </guid><title><![CDATA[Bruce 6 restarted following refurbishment]]></title><description><![CDATA[Unit 6 of the Bruce nuclear power plant in Ontario has resumed operation following its Major Component Replacement project, Bruce Power announced. The Candu reactor, which was taken offline for the work in January 2020, is scheduled to resume commercial operation later this year.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 14:23:08 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Bruce-6-restarted-following-refurbishment?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 25a12e1d-d76f-498b-82e1-ae2ed71a00e4 </guid><title><![CDATA[First Light Fusion and Tractebel Machine 4 development agreement]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tractebel and First Light Fusion have signed a framework agreement for the development of the Machine 4 project designed to demonstrate net energy gain.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 14:43:21 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/First-Light-Fusion-and-Tractebel Machine-4-develop?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 0690cb58-b7e3-4b04-a77a-1644b36b8a82 </guid><title><![CDATA[Foundation slab completed at Akkuyu 4]]></title><description><![CDATA[The pouring of concrete for the foundation slab of the reactor building at Turkey&#39;s Akkuyu unit 4 has been finished - it involved 17,500 cubic metres of concrete mix.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:29:43 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Foundation-slab-concreting-completed-at-Akkuyu-4?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> c4188e30-5c44-4ad5-87ac-3d737e52615f </guid><title><![CDATA[Groups call on US regulator to finalise advanced reactor rules]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Breakthrough Institute, Clean Air Task Force, ClearPath, Nuclear Innovation Alliance, and Third Way say delays in finalising a regulatory rulemaking on risk-informed emergency preparedness has already caused significant regulatory uncertainty for developers.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 15:01:38 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Groups-call-on-US-regulator-to-finalise-advanced-r?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a02c27b2-5d2a-41b3-bd4b-ec28d1b61588 </guid><title><![CDATA[Marvel Fusion and CSU partner on US laser facility]]></title><description><![CDATA[German laser fusion developer Marvel Fusion and the USA&#39;s Colorado State University are to create a public-private partnership for the construction of a USD150 million high-power laser and fusion research facility on the CSU Foothills Campus.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 13:20:57 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Marvel-Fusion-and-CSU-partner-on-US-laser-facility?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 22bfaaa2-bf41-4f3f-b4b3-41e7e3e32062 </guid><title><![CDATA[LLNL researchers achieve fusion ignition for second time]]></title><description><![CDATA[Researchers at the National Ignition Facility at the Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory in California have reportedly achieved net energy gain in a fusion reaction for the second time. The milestone was first achieved last December.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 14:23:01 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/LLNL-researchers-achieve-fusion-ignition-for-secon?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> cea1fb7b-5714-43e2-8bf5-c22bb5e6c4cb </guid><title><![CDATA[UK adds security conditions to EDF purchase of GE unit]]></title><description><![CDATA[The UK government has imposed measures to mitigate national security concerns arising from the purchase by EDF of GE Steam Power Limited and GE Oil &amp; Gas Marine and Industrial UK Limited.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 13:41:46 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/UK-raises-concerns-over-EDF-purchase-of-GE-unit?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f7821866-8b6b-4788-8d2c-354c16a8c559 </guid><title><![CDATA[A guide: Uranium in Niger]]></title><description><![CDATA[Current events in Niger mean world attention is turning to the West African uranium-producing country. Here is an overview of Niger&#39;s uranium sector.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 14:25:10 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/A-guide-Uranium-in-Niger?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 369b71e3-862d-438f-8c6d-e0a038e285cd </guid><title><![CDATA[PEJ teams up with university for nuclear skills development]]></title><description><![CDATA[Polskie Elektrownie Jądrowe and Warsaw University of Technology have signed an agreement to cooperate on the training of personnel for Poland&#39;s nuclear sector. PEJ is to construct the country&#39;s first large-scale nuclear power plant in Pomerania.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 15:45:05 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/PEJ-teams-up-with-university-for-nuclear-skills-de?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> af06c9dd-0b48-40ff-813c-944bf36ed3c8 </guid><title><![CDATA[AEOI head outlines Iranian nuclear energy targets]]></title><description><![CDATA[Atomic Energy Organization of Iran head Mohammad Eslami said the country is looking to increase its nuclear power generation capacity to 20 GWe. The country&#39;s first nuclear power plant, Bushehr, has now generated more than 60 billion kilowatt-hours, he told a parliamentary council.<br /> ]]>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 15:14:32 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/AEOI-head-outlines-Iranian-nuclear-targets?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>