<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ffade7a4-f6b0-43c9-a7e5-9bff423194fb </guid><title><![CDATA[Enrichment operations start at US HALEU plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[US nuclear fuel and services company Centrus Energy Corp has begun enrichment operations at the American Centrifuge Plant in Piketon, Ohio. The company said it expects to begin withdrawing high-assay low-enriched uranium product later this month.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 10:46:20 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Enrichment-operations-start-at-US-HALEU-plant?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 23b273ad-4328-4472-8343-bc61625dfdfa</guid><title><![CDATA[Partnership to support nuclear deployment in Africa]]></title><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear Association and the African Commission on Nuclear Energy have signed a memorandum of understanding to support the economic growth and sustainable energy development of the African continent through the use of nuclear energy.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 14:59:15 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Partnership-to-support-nuclear-deployment-in-Afric?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f658f2cc-802d-437c-a115-964d4d2fb57a </guid><title><![CDATA[Construction of fusion materials testing facility under way]]></title><description><![CDATA[Construction has started in Granada, Spain, of the International Fusion Materials Irradiation Facility-Demo Oriented Neutron Source project. The facility will provide a fusion‐like neutron source for the qualification of the materials to be used in a fusion power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 13:58:53 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Construction-of-fusion-materials-testing-facility?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ebf628ea-9784-41f2-ad77-063f4e970601 </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA staff get access to roof of Zaporizhzhia unit 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[International Atomic Energy Agency experts at the Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant have inspected the rooftop of the second unit and did not observe any mines or explosives, but continue to seek access to the rooftops of all six reactor buildings and to the turbine halls.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 13:26:09 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-staff-get-access-to-roof-of-Zaporizhzhia-unit?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 1ad4db0a-29bd-4aa7-8c1b-4d8ff95d7a51 </guid><title><![CDATA[JEK2: Larger capacity considered, Westinghouse, EDF, KHNP in running]]></title><description><![CDATA[The proposed new nuclear energy plant for Slovenia could have a power of 2400 MW and there are three technology providers being considered, GEN Energy CEO Dejan Paravan has said.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 11:47:28 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/JEK2-Larger-capacity-considered,-Westinghouse,-ED?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a9a55f06-a872-423c-96bb-58b93821f81d </guid><title><![CDATA[Newcleo and Tosto Group team up on LFR development]]></title><description><![CDATA[Newcleo, the UK-headquartered developer of small modular lead-cooled fast reactors, has signed a cooperation and investment agreement with the Tosto Group to advance the industrialisation of Newcleo&#39;s reactors.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 15:23:00 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Newcleo-and-Tosto-Group-team-up-on-LFR-development?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> fe1335ee-08a0-47cb-bc57-aef23723be44 </guid><title><![CDATA[Rolls-Royce partners for SMR fuel design and analytics]]></title><description><![CDATA[Rolls-Royce SMR has awarded a contract to Westinghouse for the development of a fuel design for its small modular reactor. Meanwhile, it has partnered with the UK&#39;s National Physical Laboratory to investigate safe automated reactor operation for SMRs.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 14:21:42 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Rolls-Royce-partners-for-SMR-fuel-design-and-analy?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ad5d49e1-f382-4141-8faa-5b014d891b2a </guid><title><![CDATA[Mining activities recommence at Honeymoon]]></title><description><![CDATA[Wellfield pre-conditioning has started as the final step before uranium extraction at the Honeymoon in-situ leach uranium project in South Australia, Boss Energy Limited has announced. It said Honeymoon is on track to resume production by the end of this year.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 11:53:41 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Mining-activities-recommence-at-Honeymoon?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 75af9434-7d0e-48c0-a9b3-584e711c5a8d </guid><title><![CDATA[Myanmar and Russia sign nuclear infrastructure MoU]]></title><description><![CDATA[Determining the nuclear infrastructure development needs for Myanmar and identifying priority areas of work for the development of a small modular reactor project were the subject of a fresh memorandum of understanding signed with Russia.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 13:51:54 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Myanmar-and-Russia-sign-nuclear-infrastructure-MoU?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 5bc7ea50-07a5-491f-955f-92e630fadad9 </guid><title><![CDATA[TVO eyes extended, expanded use of Olkiluoto units]]></title><description><![CDATA[Finnish utility Teollisuuden Voima Oyj announced it has initiated an environmental impact assessment procedure for a possible operating licence extension and potential power uprating of units 1 and 2 at its Olkiluoto nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 12:09:39 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/TVO-eyes-extended,-expanded-use-of-Olkiluoto-units?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 520a5e51-cc12-49aa-a1df-8d63d4b79eba </guid><title><![CDATA[Complete dismantling of experimental  French reactor to proceed]]></title><description><![CDATA[EDF has been authorised to begin the third and final phase of the decommissioning of the Brennilis nuclear power plant in the Monts d&#39;Arée in Brittany, France. The plant is a unique 75 MWe gas-cooled heavy water reactor that operated between 1972 and 1981.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 15:08:55 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Complete-dismantling-of-experimental-French-reacto?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>