<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7d46f7d5-3304-4004-8e63-4a91ffab5f2f </guid><title><![CDATA[Wyoming to consider microreactors as SMR plans continue]]></title><description><![CDATA[A project led by BWXT Advanced Technologies LLC to assess the viability of deploying microreactors to supplement Wyoming&#39;s existing power generation resources is set to be one of the first recipients of matched funding under a state-appropriated programme. But TerraPower has put its plans to apply for a construction permit for a Natrium reactor in the state back by five months.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 14 Aug 2023 14:59:39 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Wyoming-to-consider-microreactors-as-SMR-plans-con?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ef5ef941-c93f-481e-9700-cd59988720fc </guid><title><![CDATA[Mochovce 3 reaches 90% power output]]></title><description><![CDATA[The power output of unit 3 at the Mochovce nuclear power plant in Slovakia has been increased from 75% to 90% as energy start-up tests continue, Slovenské elektrárne announced. The VVER-440 is expected to enter commercial operation in the coming months.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 14 Aug 2023 14:45:14 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Mochovce-3-reaches-90-power-output?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 91f8e7de-5c12-420e-b212-cb442067a922 </guid><title><![CDATA[Testing of ITER wall panels under way]]></title><description><![CDATA[Specialists at the St Petersburg-based JSC NIIEFA - part of the Russian state nuclear corporation Rosatom - have started acceptance tests of a full-scale prototype of the first wall panel for the International Thermonuclear Experimental Reactor fusion machine under construction in Cadarache, southern France.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 14 Aug 2023 13:30:22 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Testing-of-ITER-wall-panels-under-way?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> fb4b7905-89ca-49f7-bd8f-4e06380d7c9d </guid><title><![CDATA[Tricastin 1 cleared for ten more years]]></title><description><![CDATA[Unit 1 of the Tricastin nuclear power plant in southern France can operate for a further ten years, the country&#39;s nuclear safety regulator, the Autorité de Sûreté Nucléaire, has decided. It becomes the first French power reactor licensed to operate beyond 40 years.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 14 Aug 2023 11:42:01 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Tricastin-1-cleared-for-ten-more-years?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 928e0d83-afd6-42e5-b05b-dc0a62826c39 </guid><title><![CDATA[Hydro-Québec mulls Gentilly 2 recommissioning]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hydro-Québec has confirmed it is assessing the current state of the plant which closed in 2012, as it looks at options to increase its production of clean electricity.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 15:09:47 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Hydro-Quebec-mulls-Gentilly-2-recommissioning?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7abc3852-94ad-436d-9228-26dfd9fa1a76 </guid><title><![CDATA[Search resumes for site for Australian radwaste facility]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Australian government is no longer looking to site a national low and intermediate-level radioactive waste facility in Napandee near Kimba in South Australia. It said it will not appeal a Federal Court decision to dismiss a 2021 declaration naming Napandee the proposed site for the facility.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 14:28:18 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Search-resumes-for-site-for-Australian-radwaste-fa?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 3ebdeaa9-71a7-4b26-b11e-1636032ef654 </guid><title><![CDATA[Work continues at Dasa as Niger 'relatively calm']]></title><description><![CDATA[Global Atomic Corporation said the current circumstances in Niger could delay commissioning of the processing plant at its Dasa project by up to 12 months, but expects to be able to resume dialogue with the country&#39;s Ministry of Mines following the appointment of a new minister.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 15:51:06 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Work-continues-at-Dasa-as-Niger-relatively-calm?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> cba20c6a-f52e-4ad8-ac1c-65cc23823779 </guid><title><![CDATA[Zaporizhzhia 4 taken out of hot shutdown due to water leak]]></title><description><![CDATA[Unit 4 at the Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant is being switched from hot shutdown to cold shutdown following the detection of a water leak at one of its four steam generators. Meanwhile, unit 6 is being moved to hot shutdown to continue steam production on the site.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 11:50:01 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Zaporizhzhia-4-taken-out-of-hot-shutdown-due-to-wa?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b1f88d60-91c3-4052-946f-40b20e4d0080 </guid><title><![CDATA[Core module installed at Chinese SMR]]></title><description><![CDATA[The core module has been installed within the reactor building of the ACP100 small modular reactor demonstration project, China National Nuclear Corporation has announced.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 10 Aug 2023 11:06:35 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Core-module-installed-at-Chinese-SMR?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 94a9db98-3508-413e-9c1a-e54d1e594a61 </guid><title><![CDATA[General Fusion announces new fusion demo machine]]></title><description><![CDATA[Canadian private fusion developer General Fusion has announced plans for a new Magnetised Target Fusion machine designed to achieve fusion conditions of over 100 million degrees Celsius by 2025, and progress toward scientific breakeven by 2026.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 10 Aug 2023 15:00:20 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/General-Fusion-announces-new-fusion-demo-machine?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 467ef2e8-13f8-474b-b370-2fe371ca1437 </guid><title><![CDATA[Rooppur fuel passes inspection as onsite work progresses]]></title><description><![CDATA[The first fuel for Rooppur 1&#39;s initial load has been formally accepted by the Bangladesh Atomic Energy Commission after an inspection at the Novosibirsk Chemical Concentrates Plant in Russia. Meanwhile, installation of the unit&#39;s eight heat exchangers has been completed at the plant site in Bangladesh.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 10 Aug 2023 14:37:29 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Rooppur-fuel-passes-inspection-as-onsite-work-prog?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>