<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 604fcbbc-2dce-4236-9b0a-2e530d49065a </guid><title><![CDATA[Saskatchewan seeks to develop SMR supply chain]]></title><description><![CDATA[Saskatchewan&#39;s Crown Investments Corporation is providing CAD479,000 (USD352,296) to the Saskatchewan Industrial and Mining Suppliers Association and its partners to prepare local companies for their future participation in provincial, national and global small modular reactor development.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 14:01:54 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Saskatchewan-seeks-to-develop-SMR-supply-chain?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> bc9c191d-c419-447c-ba12-3576673d81e4 </guid><title><![CDATA[Xcel gets approval to expand used fuel storage at Monticello]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Minnesota Public Utilities Commission has approved Xcel Energy&#39;s application to allow increased storage of used nuclear fuel at the Monticello nuclear power plant site, enabling the plant to operate for at least ten more years. The utility has applied to extend the plant&#39;s operating licence until 2050.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 12:16:29 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Xcel-gets-OK-to-expand-used-fuel-storage-at-Montic?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a6f07c03-c87e-450f-b979-de7ccab8858c </guid><title><![CDATA[Orano completes first cut of Crystal River reactor vessel]]></title><description><![CDATA[Orano USA has completed work to separate and pack the top third of the reactor vessel, with its embedded internal components, using its patented Optimized Segmentation process. The reactor vessel will be cut into three segments as the company carries out accelerated decommissioning of the plant.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 22:50:56 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Orano-completes-first-cut-of-Crystal-River-reactor?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 28f2cd2c-c43d-4a55-be8c-c1abbeb2e023 </guid><title><![CDATA[Slovenské elektrárne and Westinghouse fuel supply agreement]]></title><description><![CDATA[A long-term agreement with Westinghouse for the licensing and supply of VVER-440 fuel assemblies has been signed as part of Slovenské elektrárne&#39;s&nbsp;efforts to diversify its supplies for power plants in Slovakia.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 11:59:49 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Slovenske-Elektrarne-and-Westinghouse-sign-fuel-su?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f1c9a5da-3320-431a-b35b-bb60e0c113c5 </guid><title><![CDATA[Concreting of outer dome completed at Kursk II]]></title><description><![CDATA[About 4000 cubic metres of concrete were used to complete the dome of the outer containment of the first unit at Kursk II nuclear power plant in Russia.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 13:42:12 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Concreting-of-outer-dome-completed-at-Kursk-II?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> e03a77a3-b0ae-4702-b3ef-57875b617ed6</guid><title><![CDATA[Japan starts discharging treated water into the sea]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tokyo Electric Power Company announced it has begun releasing treated water currently stored at the damaged Fukushima Daiichi nuclear power plant into the ocean. The operation - expected to take up to 30 years to complete - is being closely monitored by the International Atomic Energy Agency.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 11:12:26 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Japan-starts-discharging-treated-water-into-the-se?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b290ff66-e9cb-4f8d-8c9e-b7f3b1c74324</guid><title><![CDATA[Studsvik considers SMR deployment at Nyköping site]]></title><description><![CDATA[Swedish nuclear technical services provider Studsvik has signed a memorandum of understanding with small modular reactor project development company Kärnfull Next, which is investigating the possibility of constructing and operating SMRs on the Studsvik industrial site near Nyköping on Sweden&#39;s east coast.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 13:23:19 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Studsvik-considers-SMR-deployment-at-Nykoping-site?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b024d462-3165-4e0c-895e-2e81cbbe81c9 </guid><title><![CDATA[OPG ad campaign recasts nuclear]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ontario Power Generation has launched a new public education campaign that uses the power of movies to tackle misperceptions of nuclear power.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 14:29:45 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/OPG-ad-campaign-recasts-nuclear?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a12a968c-b5ac-4c3a-a66f-893f18152b9a </guid><title><![CDATA[Grafenrheinfeld reaches new decommissioning milestone]]></title><description><![CDATA[The process of treating, cleaning and emptying the 14-metre-deep fuel element storage pool at the Grafenrheinfeld nuclear power plant in Germany has been completed. It follows the emptying and cleaning of the reactor pool at the end of last year.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 12:05:53 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Grafenrheinfeld-reaches-new-decommissioning-milest?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> eb5fba7a-18bd-46ba-a530-e428f1311894 </guid><title><![CDATA[UK funding to ensure Ukrainian nuclear fuel supplies]]></title><description><![CDATA[The UK government has announced it will provide a GBP192 million (USD243 million) loan guarantee to enable UK-headquartered Urenco to supply Energoatom, Ukraine&#39;s national nuclear company, with uranium enrichment services. The UK government also agreed a Memorandum of Understanding committing support to Ukraine&#39;s energy sector and green energy future.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 12:20:58 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/UK-funding-to-ensure-Ukrainian-nuclear-fuel-suppli?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a543b997-97c4-49cd-ac51-2c18de48e239 </guid><title><![CDATA[Groundwater extraction begins at Zaporizhzhia]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant has started pumping water from a new groundwater well and plans to build more at the site as part of efforts to ensure sufficient cooling for its six reactors after the destruction of Ukraine&#39;s Kakhovka dam in early June.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 14:44:19 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Groundwater-extraction-begins-at-Zaporizhzhia?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>