<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> faf42571-aa55-4844-8eb1-f17dea8047fc </guid><title><![CDATA[Preparations begin for Fukushima water discharge]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Japanese government has requested Tokyo Electric Power Company begin preparations for the release of treated water currently stored at the damaged Fukushima Daiichi nuclear power plant into the ocean. The first treated water is set to be discharged on or after 24 August.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 13:31:36 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Preparations-begin-for-Fukushima-water-discharge?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 85311ae5-0067-452d-b4ee-01988d677a6a </guid><title><![CDATA[PEJ seeks siting decision for Pomeranian plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[Polskie Elektrownie Jądrowe has submitted an application to the head of the Pomeranian Voivodeship for issuing a location decision for Poland&#39;s first nuclear power plant, to be built in the Choczewo municipality in the province of Pomerania.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 14:26:26 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/PEJ-seeks-siting-decision-for-Pomeranian-plant?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7f16772e-5e51-498c-8527-47471161a134 </guid><title><![CDATA[NexGen's Rook I proceeds to provincial public review]]></title><description><![CDATA[NexGen Energy has completed the Provincial Environmental Assessment technical review process and submission of the Final Provincial Environmental Impact Statement for its flagship Rook I project to the Saskatchewan Ministry of Environment.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 15:09:34 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/NexGen-s-Rook-I-proceeds-to-provincial-public-revi?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> dacc914b-8a95-44a6-9ea2-ffa65ca6a25c </guid><title><![CDATA[Microreactor company looks to INL for fuel fabrication site]]></title><description><![CDATA[Microreactor technology company NANO Nuclear Energy Inc has begun the due diligence for locating a nuclear fuel fabrication capability at Idaho National Laboratory, which it says could begin production as soon as 2027.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 14:19:23 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Microreactor-company-looks-to-INL-for-fuel-fabrica?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 73822fa5-e2d4-41e6-9a20-b02bd5310131 </guid><title><![CDATA[Supply chain must expand to meet new build plans, report warns]]></title><description><![CDATA[The expansion of the nuclear power sector at the speed and scale required to meet net-zero, energy security and sustainable development targets will necessitate sustained and coordinated investment in the global nuclear supply chain, according to World Nuclear Association.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 15:48:37 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Supply-chain-must-expand-to-meet-new-build-plans,?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b94c38c3-cd8d-4332-aa74-1521e9ea64be </guid><title><![CDATA[Federal funds announced for Saskatchewan SMR project]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Canadian government has approved CAD74 million (USD55 million) of federal funding for small modular reactor development in Saskatchewan. The funding - including over CAD24 million from the proceeds of Canada&#39;s pollution pricing system - will support work to advance the project led by utility SaskPower.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 14:22:24 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Federal-funds-announced-for-Saskatchewan-SMR-proje?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> bd15f5fc-7334-4154-92fb-2ccfc4c8ec71 </guid><title><![CDATA[Bolivia takes delivery of research reactor vessel]]></title><description><![CDATA[The vessel of the research reactor that Russia is supplying to Bolivia has arrived at the construction site in El Alto. The Bolivian Nuclear Energy Agency said its arrival marks the project&#39;s transition from the construction phase to the equipment assembly phase.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 15:04:55 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Bolivia-takes-delivery-of-research-reactor-vessel?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f7df5158-39f3-466e-bc14-41645694536f </guid><title><![CDATA[Canadian, Ukrainian regulators agree to cooperate]]></title><description><![CDATA[A memorandum of understanding on cooperation and the exchange of information in nuclear regulatory matters has been signed between the Canadian Nuclear Safety Commission and the State Nuclear Regulatory Inspectorate of Ukraine.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 11:44:50 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Canadian,-Ukrainian-regulators-agree-to-cooperate?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 4174aa1e-f25f-4575-b3f0-ef0b4af7d013 </guid><title><![CDATA[Projects secure power for fuel cycle operators]]></title><description><![CDATA[Nuclear fuel cycle companies in Namibia, Kazakhstan and the USA are working on projects to ensure secure, sustainable power supplies for their operations and the communities where they are located.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 15:25:10 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Projects-secure-power-for-fuel-cycle-operators?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> d81fbe7d-63c4-4681-96d4-b22f44ceba17 </guid><title><![CDATA[Fuel loading begins at Vogtle 4]]></title><description><![CDATA[The process of loading the 157 fuel assemblies into the core of the second AP1000 reactor at the site is pivotal for the reactor, which has a projected in-service date of late this year or early in 2024.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 13:52:07 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Fuel-loading-begins-at-Vogtle-4?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 21bafb65-bcdb-41f8-bb56-33c6bc274427 </guid><title><![CDATA[NRC completes Hermes environmental review]]></title><description><![CDATA[The US Nuclear Regulatory Commission has completed its Final Environmental Impact Statement on Kairos Power&#39;s application for a construction permit for the Hermes demonstration molten salt reactor in Oak Ridge, Tennessee. Based on their review, NRC staff have recommended that the permit should be issued.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 11:37:05 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/NRC-completes-Hermes-environmental-review?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>