<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 43fc9280-1bb3-4a48-871a-df4103fc4522 </guid><title><![CDATA[Feasibility study for Korean reactors at Borssele]]></title><description><![CDATA[Korea Hydro &amp; Nuclear Power has been contracted to conduct a feasibility study into the construction of two Korean-supplied reactors at the Borssele nuclear power plant site in the Netherlands. The contract comes as the South Korean and Dutch governments sign a memorandum of understanding to cooperate on nuclear energy.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Dec 2023 14:13:51 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Feasibility-study-for-Korean-reactors-at-Borssele?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> eadf62dc-6ce4-423a-9393-fabd6244cd86 </guid><title><![CDATA[Urenco to expand capacity at Dutch facility]]></title><description><![CDATA[Uranium enrichment services provider Urenco has announced plans to increase capacity at its plant in Almelo in the Netherlands by 15% in response to new commitments from customers.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Dec 2023 15:45:23 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Urenco-to-expand-capacity-at-Dutch-facility?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7e8cf296-e60c-44a4-9cfb-9006b764aad1 </guid><title><![CDATA[Indian regulator gives go-ahead for reactor start-up]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Atomic Energy Regulatory Board has given its permission for the first approach to criticality of unit 4 at the Kakrapar nuclear power plant. The unit is the second of two Indian-designed 700 MWe pressurised heavy water reactors being built at the site in Gujarat. &nbsp;]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Dec 2023 13:20:21 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Indian-regulator-gives-go-ahead-for-reactor-start?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 6e983b5c-606a-457a-9e06-63bc83f253c8 </guid><title><![CDATA[COP28 agreement recognises nuclear's role]]></title><description><![CDATA[The 28th UN Climate Change Conference of the Parties has ended in Dubai with a Global Stocktake - unanimously agreed by all parties - calling for a transitioning away from fossil fuels and an acceleration of zero- and low-emission technologies, including nuclear.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Dec 2023 15:13:04 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/COP28-agreement-recognises-nuclear-s-role?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 70daddd0-a992-4452-8b0d-3c1541665280 </guid><title><![CDATA[Final accord reached on Belgian reactor operations]]></title><description><![CDATA[A final agreement has been signed between the Belgian government and French utility Engie to extend the operation of the Tihange 3 and Doel 4 nuclear power reactors by 10 years and on all obligations related to radioactive waste.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Dec 2023 12:37:17 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Final-accord-reached-on-Belgian-reactor-operations?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> bcc4dad2-738e-4e93-8295-633bcd67096d </guid><title><![CDATA[Podcast: Making nuclear power plants look great]]></title><description><![CDATA[We hear from an award-winning architect on the benefits of designing nuclear power plants that make people feel good ... plus Sweden&#39;s nuclear expansion features in the news round-up.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 10:44:45 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Podcast-Building-beautiful-nuclear-power-plants?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 4cc2b2da-cb80-4e8c-bd1b-4adb51c08935 </guid><title><![CDATA[NRC approves Hermes construction permit]]></title><description><![CDATA[Kairos Power will build the Hermes molten salt-cooled demonstration reactor at the Heritage Center Industrial Park in Oak Ridge, Tennessee. It is the first non-water cooled reactor to be approved for construction in the USA in more than 50 years.<br /> ]]>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:24:05 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/NRC-approves-Hermes-construction-permit?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 6030e5a5-5e82-4304-abe9-d9bf6ebc5016 </guid><title><![CDATA[China develops fast reactor used fuel container]]></title><description><![CDATA[China has developed a 100-tonne transport container for used fuel from large fast reactors, the China Institute of Atomic Energy announced. Following test verification of a full-scale prototype container, the design has obtained design licence approval.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Dec 2023 16:09:20 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/China-develops-fast-reactor-used-fuel-container?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 1a2cb19f-a862-4dcf-831e-18f3c2f9c98b </guid><title><![CDATA[South Africa to begin new nuclear procurement]]></title><description><![CDATA[As the second unit at the Koeberg nuclear power plant goes offline for an extended maintenance outage, South Africa&#39;s Department of Mineral Resources and Energy has confirmed it will go ahead with the procurement of 2500 MWe of new nuclear capacity with plans to issue requests for proposals by March 2024.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Dec 2023 15:48:25 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/South-Africa-to-begin-new-nuclear-procurement?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f5da3ee5-b607-4b28-aec5-b3cd4ddbc951 </guid><title><![CDATA[Decommissioning of Grohnde set to begin]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Lower Saxony Ministry for the Environment, Energy and Climate Protection has issued the first decommissioning and dismantling permit to PreussenElektra for the Grohnde nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Dec 2023 12:54:18 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Decommissioning-of-Grohnde-set-to-begin?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 4771a0e8-91be-44d5-989a-6d1acac6b177 </guid><title><![CDATA[ENEC, NPPA to explore cooperation opportunities]]></title><description><![CDATA[The company responsible for implementing the UAE&#39;s civil nuclear power programme and the owner of Egypt&#39;s first nuclear power plant are to explore potential areas for cooperation in the peaceful uses of nuclear energy under a new agreement signed during COP28.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Dec 2023 11:47:14 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/ENEC,-NPPA-to-explore-cooperation-opportunities?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>