<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 05dd0074-a11d-4d84-8fd3-a0c619725e9a </guid><title><![CDATA[Multinational consortium formed for Cernavoda work]]></title><description><![CDATA[Korea Hydro &amp; Nuclear Power announced it has signed an agreement with Canada&#39;s Candu Energy and Italy&#39;s Ansaldo Nucleare to jointly carry out a refurbishment of unit 1 at the Cernavoda nuclear power plant in Romania.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 14:09:18 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Multinational-consortium-formed-for-Cernavoda-work?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> e4f0df7f-81fe-4cc0-a2b9-d3b188a05416</guid><title><![CDATA[Bruce Power-backed hydrogen study wins IESO funding]]></title><description><![CDATA[The study by Kinectrics and FuelCell Energy, supported by Bruce Power, will explore the potential of using nuclear-generated electricity to produce hydrogen and is one of six projects selected to receive a share of the first CAD7.5 million (USD5.5 million) of funding from the Ontario government&#39;s new Hydrogen Innovation Fund.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 15:06:20 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Bruce-Power-backed-hydrogen-study-wins-IESO-fundin?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f87b58e2-8164-493e-9178-43eaaf98e32c </guid><title><![CDATA[Floating nuclear power plant set for first refuelling]]></title><description><![CDATA[Nuclear fuel has been delivered to Russia&#39;s floating nuclear power plant&nbsp;<em>罗蒙诺索夫院士将在今年年底前开始具有里程碑意义的加油工作。]]>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 14:55:02 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Floating-nuclear-power-plant-set-for-first-refuell?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 712d2a20-6a7d-4f46-b9ca-ac6ee4098035 </guid><title><![CDATA[Franco-Mongolian protocol lays foundations for uranium project]]></title><description><![CDATA[An agreement between Orano and Mongolian state-owned investment company Erdenes Mongol LLC sets out the framework for an investment agreement that will lay the foundations for a long-term relationship for the development and industrial operation of the Zuuvch-Ovoo uranium project in south-western Mongolia. The investment agreement is expected to be signed by the end of the year.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 13:55:43 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Franco-Mongolian-protocol-lays-foundations-for-ura?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 53e5320a-cad7-465d-9bb6-ce5f4f486e5a </guid><title><![CDATA[Sheffield Forgemasters joins UK Xe-100 deployment effort]]></title><description><![CDATA[Sheffield Forgemasters, X-energy and Cavendish Nuclear have signed a memorandum of understanding on collaborating to explore opportunities around the deployment of a fleet of Xe-100 high temperature gas-cooled reactors in the UK.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 11:41:17 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Sheffield-Forgemasters-joins-UK-Xe-100-deployment?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ffade7a4-f6b0-43c9-a7e5-9bff423194fb </guid><title><![CDATA[Enrichment operations start at US HALEU plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[US nuclear fuel and services company Centrus Energy Corp has begun enrichment operations at the American Centrifuge Plant in Piketon, Ohio. The company said it expects to begin withdrawing high-assay low-enriched uranium product later this month.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 10:46:20 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Enrichment-operations-start-at-US-HALEU-plant?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 23b273ad-4328-4472-8343-bc61625dfdfa</guid><title><![CDATA[Partnership to support nuclear deployment in Africa]]></title><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear Association and the African Commission on Nuclear Energy have signed a memorandum of understanding to support the economic growth and sustainable energy development of the African continent through the use of nuclear energy.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 14:59:15 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Partnership-to-support-nuclear-deployment-in-Afric?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f658f2cc-802d-437c-a115-964d4d2fb57a </guid><title><![CDATA[Construction of fusion materials testing facility under way]]></title><description><![CDATA[Construction has started in Granada, Spain, of the International Fusion Materials Irradiation Facility-Demo Oriented Neutron Source project. The facility will provide a fusion‐like neutron source for the qualification of the materials to be used in a fusion power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 13:58:53 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Construction-of-fusion-materials-testing-facility?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ebf628ea-9784-41f2-ad77-063f4e970601 </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA staff get access to roof of Zaporizhzhia unit 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[International Atomic Energy Agency experts at the Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant have inspected the rooftop of the second unit and did not observe any mines or explosives, but continue to seek access to the rooftops of all six reactor buildings and to the turbine halls.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 13:26:09 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-staff-get-access-to-roof-of-Zaporizhzhia-unit?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 1ad4db0a-29bd-4aa7-8c1b-4d8ff95d7a51 </guid><title><![CDATA[JEK2: Larger capacity considered, Westinghouse, EDF, KHNP in running]]></title><description><![CDATA[The proposed new nuclear energy plant for Slovenia could have a power of 2400 MW and there are three technology providers being considered, GEN Energy CEO Dejan Paravan has said.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 11:47:28 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/JEK2-Larger-capacity-considered,-Westinghouse,-ED?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a9a55f06-a872-423c-96bb-58b93821f81d </guid><title><![CDATA[Newcleo and Tosto Group team up on LFR development]]></title><description><![CDATA[Newcleo, the UK-headquartered developer of small modular lead-cooled fast reactors, has signed a cooperation and investment agreement with the Tosto Group to advance the industrialisation of Newcleo&#39;s reactors.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 15:23:00 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Newcleo-and-Tosto-Group-team-up-on-LFR-development?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>