<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> e7c9f362-96b7-4494-8a52-f243d9f1b6a0 </guid><title><![CDATA[Takahama 2 reactor restarted]]></title><description><![CDATA[Unit 2 of the Takahama nuclear power plant in Japan&#39;s Fukui Prefecture has been restarted after being taken offline more than 12 years ago, Kansai Electric Power Company announced. The 780 MWe (net) pressurised water reactor becomes the 12th Japanese reactor to resume operation.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 11:04:09 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Takahama-2-reactor-restarted?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> CB06656b-70ff-457a-8edd-6ead511212f4 </guid><title><![CDATA[Demonstration reactor to be built in Rwanda]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Rwanda Atomic Energy Board has signed an agreement with Dual Fluid to collaborate on the development of a demonstration Dual Fluid nuclear reactor in Rwanda. The demonstration reactor is expected to be operational by 2026.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 16:38:10 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Demonstration-reactor-to-be-built-in-Rwanda?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ca71feea-9584-4e3f-8d08-09cdae506fb7 </guid><title><![CDATA[X-energy to develop second Project Pele microreactor design]]></title><description><![CDATA[The US Department of Defense has awarded a contract option to X-energy, LLC to develop an enhanced engineering design for a transportable microreactor suitable for both commercial and defence use under the Project Pele initiative. This second design would be complementary to the prototype microreactor which is being built by BWX Technologies.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 14:14:16 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/X-energy-to-develop-second-Project-Pele-microreact?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 6f6a06c2-431e-4943-9574-b0bf685f4335 </guid><title><![CDATA[More funding to progress UK nuclear-generated hydrogen project]]></title><description><![CDATA[An EDF-led consortium has been awarded UK government funding to further develop plans to use heat and electricity from Heysham 2 to create hydrogen for use in the production of asphalt and cement. Earlier this year, a feasibility study demonstrated the significant benefit the project would bring in proving how nuclear could power hydrogen electrolysis.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 14:46:42 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/More-funding-to-progress-UK-nuclear-generated-hydr?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f9948f1c-6a69-4299-851c-5806f68bf145 </guid><title><![CDATA[Tokamak Energy reports Demo4 milestone cryogenic tests]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tokamak Energy says its engineers have successfully validated electromagnetic current test results of the first of 14 toroidal field limbs in liquid nitrogen at temperatures of -200 degrees Celsius.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 13:40:37 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Tokamak-Energy-reports-Demo4-milestone-cryogenic-t?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 1dc719a4-eefe-4d5b-9e9d-2d6c7de54950 </guid><title><![CDATA[Shelf-M project being developed for Sovinoye gold deposit]]></title><description><![CDATA[Rosatom&#39;s mining division Atomredmetzoloto JSC and RAOS JSC have signed an agreement to cooperate on plans for a Shelf-M small nuclear power plant project at the Sovinoye gold deposit in Chukotka in Russia&#39;s far east.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 10:36:39 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Shelf-M-project-being-developed-for-Sovinoye-gold?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f03abb47-41b7-4032-833a-8bc9d0279ea0 </guid><title><![CDATA[Palisades restart takes 'giant step' with Holtec-Wolverine deal]]></title><description><![CDATA[A long-term power purchase agreement signed between Holtec Palisades Energy and the non-profit Wolverine Power Cooperative is described as a &quot;significant milestone&quot; towards restarting the 800 MW Palisades nuclear power plant in the USA.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 11:08:13 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Palisades-restart-takes-giant-step-with-Holtec-Wol?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 448d4fcd-d9f9-4a49-ab65-77fe24055e6a</guid><title><![CDATA[BWXT to evaluate microreactor deployment in Wyoming]]></title><description><![CDATA[BWX Technologies Inc has been contracted by the Wyoming Energy Authority to assess the viability of deploying microreactors in the state. The value of the contract was not disclosed.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 11:13:45 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/BWXT-to-evaluate-microreactor-deployment-in-Wyomin?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> c86d971d-8226-4142-b7a9-67a0434947d9 </guid><title><![CDATA[UK nuclear workforce at highest for 20 years, says NIA]]></title><description><![CDATA[The number of people employed in the civil nuclear sector in the UK has risen to 77,413, according to the Nuclear Industry Association&#39;s annual Jobs Map survey.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 14:55:50 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/UK-nuclear-workforce-at-highest-for-20-years,-says?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b96e5b2d-5191-4171-834f-c874abb28e9d </guid><title><![CDATA[Clean-up work begins at Uzbek legacy uranium sites]]></title><description><![CDATA[Remediation work at legacy uranium mining sites in Uzbekistan is under way, bolstered by a EUR9 million (USD11 million) grant from the Environmental Remediation Account for Central Asia set up on the initiative of the European Union and managed by the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 15:26:56 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Clean-up-work-begins-at-Uzbek-legacy-uranium-sites?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 9b4b88a2-a7d0-4026-8a2b-145a36f7651e</guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA to run out of money within weeks, Grossi warns]]></title><description><![CDATA[Member states of the International Atomic Energy Agency now owe more than EUR200 million (USD214 million), and Director General Rafael Mariano Grossi has warned that unless payments are made, then in a month&#39;s time &quot;we will run out of money ... I will not be able to pay salaries or for the lights ... we will grind to a halt&quot;.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 12:22:48 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-to-run-out-of-money-within-weeks,-Grossi-warn?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>