<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 400c19f1-16ed-4cde-ba71-a0d211fa1833 </guid><title><![CDATA[Industry groups and governments pledge to back new nuclear]]></title><description><![CDATA[Representatives of the nuclear industry in OECD nations, and representatives of the governments of 20 countries, have issued communiqués committing to work together to expand nuclear energy capacity, after the inaugural <em>经合组织核能机构和法国政府组织的新核会议路线图。]]>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 11:22:07 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Nuclear-groups-and-ministers-pledge-to-back-new-nu?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 8e8fc695-bf40-435e-b1da-edcf02a8a2e1 </guid><title><![CDATA[Canadian and Romanian firms collaborate on medical isotopes]]></title><description><![CDATA[Laurentis Energy Partners and Nuclearelectrica are to collaborate on the production of medical isotopes at the Cernavoda Nuclear Power Plant and explore the possibility of heavy water production in Romania.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 15:07:46 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Canadian-and-Romanian-firms-collaborate-on-medical?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 3d153e7a-30e4-4e56-a581-17a071660b33 </guid><title><![CDATA[Kazatomprom plans 2025 uranium production increase]]></title><description><![CDATA[The board of the Kazakh uranium producer has approved a strategy to increase production volumes in 2025, returning to a 100% level relative to its subsoil use agreements for the first time since 2018 and adding up to 6,000 tU to anticipated global primary supply.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 11:56:46 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Kazatomprom-plans-2025-uranium-production-increase?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 5bd0dbc5-f2fe-4497-b118-4d20541714db </guid><title><![CDATA[Cumbrian community exits repository site search]]></title><description><![CDATA[Allerdale - one of four locations being evaluated - has been removed from the UK geological disposal facility siting process due to limited suitable geology, Nuclear Waste Services announced. It is expected that a final site selection could be a process which takes 10-15 years.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 14:45:28 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Cumbrian-community-exits-repository-site-search?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 4456dfcd-a580-4a2b-92c8-0e242cc78fac </guid><title><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia reiterates plans for nuclear energy]]></title><description><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia has announced it intends to move towards implementing full International Atomic Energy Agency nuclear safeguards as it works towards building its first nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 14:46:17 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Saudi-Arabia-reiterates-plans-for-nuclear-energy?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a18e6d2c-dca0-467b-9764-4590887ea5b8 </guid><title><![CDATA[Argentina and France extend nuclear collaboration]]></title><description><![CDATA[Argentina&#39;s National Atomic Energy Commission and the French Alternative Energies &amp; Atomic Energy Commission have signed a cooperation agreement on the peaceful use of nuclear technology and new energy technologies that expands on one signed in 2010.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 14:27:56 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Argentina-and-France-extend-nuclear-collaboration?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> e7cb0c6d-326b-4793-ab41-c841c2a43c8f </guid><title><![CDATA[Completion of Finnish repository review delayed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Finland&#39;s Radiation and Nuclear Safety Authority said its review of Posiva Oy&#39;s operating licence application for the world&#39;s first used fuel disposal facility is taking longer than expected and will not be completed by the end of this year as planned.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 13:56:59 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Completion-of-Finnish-repository-review-delayed?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> e42aba92-4999-4b88-b431-9ddfeaf65b59 </guid><title><![CDATA[Contract signed for design of Polish nuclear power plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[Polish power company Polskie Elektrownie Jądrowe has signed an engineering services contract with US firms Westinghouse Electric Company and Bechtel for the country&#39;s first nuclear power plant, to be constructed at the Lubiatowo-Kopalino site in the Choczewo municipality in Pomerania.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 13:07:57 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Contract-signed-for-design-of-Polish-nuclear-power?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ce5e1eb5-c6c5-4496-b686-d6298db47d7a </guid><title><![CDATA[New working group aims to speed JEK2 project in Slovenia]]></title><description><![CDATA[A new working group of Slovenian government ministers and industry officials has met with the aim of preparing &quot;all the necessary bases for citizens to make high-quality and informed decisions about supporting the JEK2 project&quot;, with a planned timeline of a final investment decision by 2028 &quot;at the latest&quot;.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 12:03:52 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/New-working-group-aims-to-speed-JEK2-project-in-Sl?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 8dbf059e-8955-4152-8ce7-4be26fd4891f </guid><title><![CDATA[Innovation is driving nuclear optimism, panel findsar innovation driving optimism, panel finds]]></title><description><![CDATA[Innovation has been, and will continue to be, an essential driver in propelling the nuclear energy sector forward - but the industry must be prepared to embrace innovation in all areas, not just technological innovations. These were the messages from speakers in the high-level closing panel at the International Atomic Energy Agency&#39;s <em>2023 年科学论坛。]]>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 15:49:16 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Innovation-is-driving-nuclear-optimism,-panel-find?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b1380777-a3fb-4a96-92ac-ca4090df63ad </guid><title><![CDATA[IEA sees greater role for nuclear in attaining net-zero by 2050]]></title><description><![CDATA[In an update to its<em>国际能源署于 2021 年发布的净零路线图表示，鉴于最近的政策支持，核电的作用已被向上修改。在更新的净零排放情景中，核发电量到 2050 年将达到 916 GWe，高于 2021 年版本中给出的 812 GWe。]]>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 15:08:06 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IEA-sees-greater-role-for-nuclear-in-attaining-net?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>