<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7dc93ca7-2a34-4c65-a2ea-5ee694ab2897 </guid><title><![CDATA[Westinghouse expands fuel offerings of Columbia plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[Westinghouse has announced the creation of a centre of excellence for Low Enriched Uranium Plus fuel manufacturing at its Columbia Fuel Fabrication Facility in Hopkins, South Carolina.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 29 Aug 2023 14:25:40 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Westinghouse-expands-fuel-offerings-of-Columbia-pl?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 39f8d9ba-ad93-4125-9d26-ff4747ccd83c </guid><title><![CDATA[Construction of Lufeng unit 6 begins]]></title><description><![CDATA[The first safety-related concrete has been poured for the nuclear island of the unit 6 HPR1000 (Hualong One) at the Lufeng nuclear power plant in China&#39;s Guangdong province. It is the second HPR1000 under construction at the site, where four CAP1000s are also planned.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 29 Aug 2023 12:23:23 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Construction-of-Lufeng-unit-6-begins?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 747f9714-f00a-441b-893a-8822da283311 </guid><title><![CDATA[Oklo and Centrus Energy broaden links with MoU]]></title><description><![CDATA[Advanced reactor plant developer Oklo has expanded its partnership with Centrus Energy with a memorandum of understanding covering the development of the Aurora powerhouses and High-Assay, Low Enriched Uranium fuel supply.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 29 Aug 2023 13:34:04 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Oklo-and-Centrus-Energy-broaden-links-with-MoU?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 604fcbbc-2dce-4236-9b0a-2e530d49065a </guid><title><![CDATA[Saskatchewan seeks to develop SMR supply chain]]></title><description><![CDATA[Saskatchewan&#39;s Crown Investments Corporation is providing CAD479,000 (USD352,296) to the Saskatchewan Industrial and Mining Suppliers Association and its partners to prepare local companies for their future participation in provincial, national and global small modular reactor development.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 14:01:54 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Saskatchewan-seeks-to-develop-SMR-supply-chain?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> bc9c191d-c419-447c-ba12-3576673d81e4 </guid><title><![CDATA[Xcel gets approval to expand used fuel storage at Monticello]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Minnesota Public Utilities Commission has approved Xcel Energy&#39;s application to allow increased storage of used nuclear fuel at the Monticello nuclear power plant site, enabling the plant to operate for at least ten more years. The utility has applied to extend the plant&#39;s operating licence until 2050.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 12:16:29 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Xcel-gets-OK-to-expand-used-fuel-storage-at-Montic?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a6f07c03-c87e-450f-b979-de7ccab8858c </guid><title><![CDATA[Orano completes first cut of Crystal River reactor vessel]]></title><description><![CDATA[Orano USA has completed work to separate and pack the top third of the reactor vessel, with its embedded internal components, using its patented Optimized Segmentation process. The reactor vessel will be cut into three segments as the company carries out accelerated decommissioning of the plant.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 22:50:56 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Orano-completes-first-cut-of-Crystal-River-reactor?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 28f2cd2c-c43d-4a55-be8c-c1abbeb2e023 </guid><title><![CDATA[Slovenské elektrárne and Westinghouse fuel supply agreement]]></title><description><![CDATA[A long-term agreement with Westinghouse for the licensing and supply of VVER-440 fuel assemblies has been signed as part of Slovenské elektrárne&#39;s&nbsp;efforts to diversify its supplies for power plants in Slovakia.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 11:59:49 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Slovenske-Elektrarne-and-Westinghouse-sign-fuel-su?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b94221af-a487-46c8-8195-3012c74d4c7d </guid><title><![CDATA[Podcast: World Nuclear Performance Report]]></title><description><![CDATA[The 2023 edition of <em>《世界核性能报告》充满了统计数据 - 其作者乔纳森·科布 (Jonathan Cobb) 介绍了头条新闻并讨论了调查结果揭示的有关总输出以及反应堆不同类型和寿命的信息。]]>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 08:37:29 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Podcast-World-Nuclear-Performance-Report?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f1c9a5da-3320-431a-b35b-bb60e0c113c5 </guid><title><![CDATA[Concreting of outer dome completed at Kursk II]]></title><description><![CDATA[About 4000 cubic metres of concrete were used to complete the dome of the outer containment of the first unit at Kursk II nuclear power plant in Russia.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 13:42:12 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Concreting-of-outer-dome-completed-at-Kursk-II?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> e03a77a3-b0ae-4702-b3ef-57875b617ed6</guid><title><![CDATA[Japan starts discharging treated water into the sea]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tokyo Electric Power Company announced it has begun releasing treated water currently stored at the damaged Fukushima Daiichi nuclear power plant into the ocean. The operation - expected to take up to 30 years to complete - is being closely monitored by the International Atomic Energy Agency.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 11:12:26 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Japan-starts-discharging-treated-water-into-the-se?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b290ff66-e9cb-4f8d-8c9e-b7f3b1c74324</guid><title><![CDATA[Studsvik considers SMR deployment at Nyköping site]]></title><description><![CDATA[Swedish nuclear technical services provider Studsvik has signed a memorandum of understanding with small modular reactor project development company Kärnfull Next, which is investigating the possibility of constructing and operating SMRs on the Studsvik industrial site near Nyköping on Sweden&#39;s east coast.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 13:23:19 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Studsvik-considers-SMR-deployment-at-Nykoping-site?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>