<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> fff03455-1bb1-4162-9189-378a23224ff4 </guid><title><![CDATA[World needs nuclear for net zero: John Kerry]]></title><description><![CDATA[Nuclear will be essential for the world to accelerate its transition away from fossil fuels, US Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry said at a New York summit this week. He also praised the recently launched Net Zero Nuclear Initiative - which has now welcomed GE Hitachi Nuclear Energy as its first corporate partner.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 21:34:04 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/World-needs-nuclear-for-net-zero-Kerry?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 2875c173-0761-4487-ad11-834e5b896bf8 </guid><title><![CDATA[Fuel loading completed at second Shin Hanul unit]]></title><description><![CDATA[The loading of fuel has been completed at unit 2 of the Shin Hanul nuclear power plant, Korea Hydro &amp; Nuclear Power announced. The unit - the second of two APR1400 reactors at the site - is expected to enter commercial operation in about six months&#39; time following the completion of test runs.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 11:03:26 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Fuel-loading-completed-at-second-Shin-Hanul-unit?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 17964d12-aa10-4bf0-8c1a-b6232621cb0d </guid><title><![CDATA[Canada offers CAD3 billion finance for nuclear in Romania]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Canadian Minister of Energy and Natural Resources Jonathan Wilkinson has announced CAD3 billion (USD2.2 billion) of export financing to Nuclearelectrica to support the building of two CANDU-6 reactors at the Cernavoda nuclear power plant in Romania.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 11:39:48 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Canada-offers-CAD3-billion-finance-for-new-nuclear?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> e0318ef9-0d2a-4449-9875-45ac41f79ade </guid><title><![CDATA[Rooppur 2 outer dome progress, nuclear fuel set for October delivery]]></title><description><![CDATA[The lower tier of the outer dome of the second unit of the Rooppur nuclear power plant in Bangladesh has been lifted into place. Meanwhile Rosatom says it expects to deliver the first fuel to the plant in October.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 13:51:18 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Rooppur-progress-update,-nuclear-fuel-set-for-Octo?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 0b19a1b7-1684-4571-b8ce-945f90cb9bc5 </guid><title><![CDATA[US court dismisses Westinghouse case against Korea]]></title><description><![CDATA[A US district court has dismissed a lawsuit filed by Westinghouse Electric Company seeking to prevent Korea Hydro &amp; Nuclear Power and its parent company Korea Electric Power Corporation from exporting the APR1400 reactor design without its permission.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 15:07:36 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/US-court-dismisses-Westinghouse-case-against-Korea?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> cdf1628a-4d0c-426d-888b-eb3e784ab8d3 </guid><title><![CDATA[Polish regulator ready for nuclear programme, IAEA says]]></title><description><![CDATA[Poland&#39;s nuclear regulatory framework is in line with International Atomic Energy Agency safety standards and its regulatory body is competent and prepared for the launch of the country&#39;s nuclear power programme, an IAEA team of experts has concluded.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 13:31:26 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Polish-regulator-ready-for-nuclear-programme,-IAEA?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7a197250-83f9-4620-bbd6-5ffb85019043 </guid><title><![CDATA[ČEZ extends deadline for final bids for new unit]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Czech company&nbsp;ČEZ has pushed back the deadline to the end of October for final bids to be submitted to construct a new nuclear unit at the Dukovany nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 13:04:05 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/CEZ-extends-deadline-for-final-bids-for-new-unit?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 760a9b38-386e-4ed6-8c0e-b1d108d73f25 </guid><title><![CDATA[US university builds facility for first-of-a-kind research reactor]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Gayle and Max Dillard Science and Engineering Research Center at Abilene Christian University in Texas will host the Nuclear Energy eXperimental Testing Laboratory and a first-of-a-kind advanced reactor facility.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 15:09:01 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/US-university-builds-facility-for-first-of-a-kind?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 90083726-e56e-4f0f-a266-8e5296b46f3a </guid><title><![CDATA[Private investment sought for Sizewell C project]]></title><description><![CDATA[The UK&#39;s Department for Energy Security and Net Zero has launched a pre-qualification for potential investors as the first stage of an equity raise process for the Sizewell C nuclear power plant project in Suffolk, England.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 11:54:40 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Private-investment-sought-for-Sizewell-C-project?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b8ac10f8-8a62-41a4-a39c-d597bdd347b5 </guid><title><![CDATA[Iran withdraws further IAEA inspector designations]]></title><description><![CDATA[International Atomic Energy Agency Director General Rafael Mariano Grossi has called for the Iranian government to reconsider the decision which affects the planning and conducting of nuclear safeguards verification activities.<br /> ]]>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 13:38:14 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Iran-withdraws-further-IAEA-inspector-designations?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> cf08f08f-146b-439b-a32f-014f20f8190a </guid><title><![CDATA[Long-term safety of Ascó plant reviewed by IAEA]]></title><description><![CDATA[An International Atomic Energy Agency team of experts has completed a follow-up review of long-term operational safety at the Ascó nuclear power plant in Spain. The team reviewed the plant&#39;s response to recommendations and suggestions made during a Safety Aspects of Long-Term Operation mission in 2021.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 15:07:28 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Long-term-safety-of-Asco-plant-reviewed-by-IAEA?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>