<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> cbb2e35a-c215-4c04-bd80-4ed812e0b5bf </guid><title><![CDATA[Tribal council, First Nations take stake in SMR companies]]></title><description><![CDATA[The North Shore Mi&#39;kmaq Tribal Council and its seven First Nation member communities are making financial investments in small modular reactor developers Moltex Energy Canada Inc and ARC Clean Technology Canada Inc under historic equity agreements.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 14:22:50 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Tribal-council,-First-Nations-take-stake-in-SMR-co?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b1f282d3-fd3c-4a9c-b2bf-94034c6a1910 </guid><title><![CDATA[Hot testing starts of second CGN Hualong One unit]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tests that simulate the temperatures and pressures which the reactor systems will be subjected to during normal operation have begun at unit 4 of the Fangchenggang nuclear power plant in China&#39;s Guangxi Autonomous Region. The unit is the second of two demonstration China General Nuclear-designed Hualong One (HPR1000) reactors at the site.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 14:11:24 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Hot-testing-starts-of-second-CGN-Hualong-One-unit?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 6ee51380-2373-4abd-943b-e370382d9341 </guid><title><![CDATA[New Slovak reactor reaches full power]]></title><description><![CDATA[The power output of unit 3 at the Mochovce nuclear power plant in Slovakia has been increased from 90% to 100% as energy start-up tests continue, Slovenské elektrárne announced.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 13:55:59 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/New-Slovak-reactor-reaches-full-power?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 91d96daf-b820-4079-80a7-12b29041f076 </guid><title><![CDATA[More countries set to join Nuward SMR joint early review]]></title><description><![CDATA[The pilot phase of the joint early regulatory review of France&#39;s Nuward small modular reactor design has led to positive lessons for all sides, and three more European regulators are set to join the next phase, a meeting at the <em>第 67 届国际原子能机构大会已获悉。]]>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 11:30:39 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/More-countries-to-join-Nuward-SMR-joint-early-revi?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 718b8bfa-b1c8-4620-98b2-0ec3ddfb4da9 </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA assesses operational safety at Penly plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[The operator of the two-unit Penly nuclear power plant in Normandy, France, has demonstrated a commitment to operational safety, an International Atomic Energy Agency mission has concluded. The team also encouraged the operator, EDF, to continue improvements in areas such as the implementation of maintenance work.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 13:45:33 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-assesses-operational-safety-at-Penly-plant?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 3698e885-6cb2-4d83-9899-c1daabc86204 </guid><title><![CDATA[Grossi stresses positive role of nuclear at IAEA General Conference]]></title><description><![CDATA[Director General Rafael Mariano Grossi opened the <em>第 67 届国际原子能机构大会表示，民意调查显示公众对核能的态度“潮流正在转变”，但各国“仍然需要公开、主动地让利益相关者参与”其核电计划。]]>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 09:29:54 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Grossi-urges-vocal-backing-of-nuclear-as-IAEA-gath?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 006d8ceb-47f0-45fd-ae31-a75d9aab06a8 </guid><title><![CDATA[Outer containment dome in place at Rooppur 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[The installation of the steel structures of the outer containment dome has been completed in record time at unit 2 of the Rooppur nuclear power plant in Bangladesh, Russia&#39;s state nuclear corporation Rosatom announced.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 11:02:36 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Outer-containment-dome-in-place-at-Rooppur-2?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 69b33ad6-c1ab-4134-b7a0-a5aa1cd75bef </guid><title><![CDATA[Successful nuclear projects key for future investments]]></title><description><![CDATA[Being able to refer to success stories of nuclear power projects being completed on time and on budget, whether refurbishments or new build, will be key to securing finance for future projects, panelists in a session of the recent <em>2023 年世界核研讨会同意。]]>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 13:51:49 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Successful-nuclear-projects-key-for-future-investm?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 676fd9f7-9b88-4205-99d9-2270bbf01bb2 </guid><title><![CDATA[US microreactor apparatus begins tests]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tests now under way using an electric-powered prototype of the US Department of Energy&#39;s MARVEL microreactor will demonstrate the natural circulation that will be a critical part of the reactor&#39;s heat removal system.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 14:09:49 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/US-microreactor-apparatus-begins-tests?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> aca01563-a4bd-4c80-82e3-3a3a76711704 </guid><title><![CDATA[Nuclear groups propose ‘stepwise’ approach to increased regulatory efficiency]]></title><description><![CDATA[A new joint report from World Nuclear Association, the Nuclear Energy Institute and the Canadian Nuclear Association proposes regulatory steps which can be taken to minimise the time and cost for large-scale deployment of a fleet of standardised reactor designs that are acceptable in multiple countries around the world.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 11:35:48 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Nuclear-groups-propose-stepwise-approach-to-increa?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 38f721a7-0305-402e-8e3c-4a67134eb5d6</guid><title><![CDATA[Environmental permit granted for first Polish plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[Poland&#39;s General Director for Environmental Protection has issued to Polskie Elektrownie Jadrowe its decision on the environmental conditions for the construction of a nuclear power plant in the province of Pomerania.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 14:58:30 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Environmental-permit-granted-for-first-Polish-plan?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>