<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 0f64f635-2dfd-4799-b963-acadeb983caf </guid><title><![CDATA[INL produces HALEU pellets for testing]]></title><description><![CDATA[Researchers at Idaho National Laboratory recently fabricated about two dozen commercial-grade high-assay low-enriched uranium fuel pellets for testing. A further 100-150 pellets are to be made for irradiation tests in the Advanced Test Reactor.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 14:55:51 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/INL-produces-HALEU-pellets-for-testing?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 432667e7-6581-46d8-a6b6-d270709b4ef3 </guid><title><![CDATA[Technology evaluation for Bruce expansion to begin early 2024]]></title><description><![CDATA[Bruce Power is to launch a Request for Information to evaluate potential new nuclear technologies as part of its preliminary engagement and long-term review of expanding nuclear generation on its existing Ontario site. It has also set up a new advisory panel drawn from business, industry and labour leaders that will work in parallel with the RFI timetable.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 14:27:14 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Technology-evaluation-for-Bruce-expansion-to-begin?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 77c25fa5-9825-4fbf-ad75-4563c7c310c5 </guid><title><![CDATA[South Korea, UK agree to bolster nuclear cooperation]]></title><description><![CDATA[A new Clean Energy Partnership between the UK and South Korea, together with nine memorandums of understanding regarding cooperation in nuclear energy, have been signed during a state visit by Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol to the UK. The construction of Korean-designed reactors in the UK will be considered.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 14:28:00 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/South-Korea,-UK-agree-to-bolster-nuclear-cooperati?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f29be086-b888-45d4-a9f1-2af9644d14e0</guid><title><![CDATA[MEPs fully include nuclear in Net-Zero Industry Act]]></title><description><![CDATA[The European Parliament has adopted its position on the proposed Net-Zero Industry Act, which is intended to bolster Europe&#39;s manufacturing output in technologies needed for decarbonisation. MEPs included nuclear fission and fusion among a list of 17 technologies covered by the legislation.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 15:48:43 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/MEPs-fully-include-nuclear-in-Net-Zero-Industry-Ac?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 3f040e82-c65e-4ddd-9fcf-51a362e1a665 </guid><title><![CDATA[Last fuel assembly unloaded at Kursk unit 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[The first stage of decommissioning of the Kursk nuclear power plant&#39;s first unit has been completed with the last used fuel assembly unloaded from the reactor core.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 16:01:19 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Last-fuel-assembly-unloaded-at-Kursk-unit-1?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 8b725da3-c2d4-468c-8e5f-9952410b5eb8 </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA says Zaporizhzhia unit 5 switched to cold shutdown]]></title><description><![CDATA[The International Atomic Energy Agency says the fifth unit at the Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant is switching from hot to cold shutdown to allow investigation of why boron had been detected in a cooling circuit.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 14:52:05 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-says-Zaporizhzhia-unit-5-switched-to-cold-shu?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 1d14d2c3-5795-4f05-ac12-3b46de4ad2af </guid><title><![CDATA[Corporate agreement furthers Canadian SMR collaboration]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ontario Power Generation subsidiary Laurentis Energy Partners and Saskatchewan utility SaskPower have announced details of a Master Services Agreement that will see them collaborate to advance the deployment of small modular reactors in Saskatchewan.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 15:22:55 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Corporate-agreement-furthers-Canadian-SMR-collabor?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 456b10ab-88e7-4162-9c6b-24e8e05d2c05 </guid><title><![CDATA[Sri Lankan government has plans for nuclear, minister says]]></title><description><![CDATA[Sri Lanka&#39;s government intends to include nuclear energy in its long-term plans, the country&#39;s Minister of Power and Energy said as the country&#39;s cabinet approved electricity sector reforms.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 15:52:45 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Sri-Lankan-government-has-plans-for-nuclear,-minis?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> eee0e3c5-f85c-44a6-b466-655f3aea6e33 </guid><title><![CDATA[NuScale, ORNL to assess SMR use by industry]]></title><description><![CDATA[NuScale Power and the US Department of Energy&#39;s Oak Ridge National Laboratory are to collaborate on a techno-economic assessment, studying a NuScale small modular reactor&#39;s ability to implement a cost-effective steam heat augmentation design.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 14:22:32 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/NuScale,-ORNL-to-assess-SMR-use-by-industry?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 886b0774-f8ef-42d2-b939-8ad6665bc2d3 </guid><title><![CDATA[Reactor vessel delivered to Kursk II's second unit]]></title><description><![CDATA[The 340-tonne reactor vessel could now be installed before the end of the year at the new unit being built by Rosatom at the Kursk nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 12:41:08 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Reactor-vessel-delivered-to-Kursk-II-s-second-unit?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> aabe209b-c051-4250-8cd0-73b2f4f5ca1c </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA assesses long-term safety at Forsmark]]></title><description><![CDATA[An International Atomic Energy Agency team of experts has completed a Safety Aspects of Long-Term Operation mission to units 1 and 2 of the Forsmark nuclear power plant in Sweden, which operator Vattenfall plans to operate for 60 years.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 15:26:04 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-assesses-long-term-safety-at-Forsmark?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>