<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 70daddd0-a992-4452-8b0d-3c1541665280 </guid><title><![CDATA[Final accord reached on Belgian reactor operations]]></title><description><![CDATA[A final agreement has been signed between the Belgian government and French utility Engie to extend the operation of the Tihange 3 and Doel 4 nuclear power reactors by 10 years and on all obligations related to radioactive waste.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Dec 2023 12:37:17 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Final-accord-reached-on-Belgian-reactor-operations?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 4cc2b2da-cb80-4e8c-bd1b-4adb51c08935 </guid><title><![CDATA[NRC approves Hermes construction permit]]></title><description><![CDATA[Kairos Power will build the Hermes molten salt-cooled demonstration reactor at the Heritage Center Industrial Park in Oak Ridge, Tennessee. It is the first non-water cooled reactor to be approved for construction in the USA in more than 50 years.<br /> ]]>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:24:05 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/NRC-approves-Hermes-construction-permit?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 6030e5a5-5e82-4304-abe9-d9bf6ebc5016 </guid><title><![CDATA[China develops fast reactor used fuel container]]></title><description><![CDATA[China has developed a 100-tonne transport container for used fuel from large fast reactors, the China Institute of Atomic Energy announced. Following test verification of a full-scale prototype container, the design has obtained design licence approval.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Dec 2023 16:09:20 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/China-develops-fast-reactor-used-fuel-container?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 1a2cb19f-a862-4dcf-831e-18f3c2f9c98b </guid><title><![CDATA[South Africa to begin new nuclear procurement]]></title><description><![CDATA[As the second unit at the Koeberg nuclear power plant goes offline for an extended maintenance outage, South Africa&#39;s Department of Mineral Resources and Energy has confirmed it will go ahead with the procurement of 2500 MWe of new nuclear capacity with plans to issue requests for proposals by March 2024.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Dec 2023 15:48:25 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/South-Africa-to-begin-new-nuclear-procurement?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f5da3ee5-b607-4b28-aec5-b3cd4ddbc951 </guid><title><![CDATA[Decommissioning of Grohnde set to begin]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Lower Saxony Ministry for the Environment, Energy and Climate Protection has issued the first decommissioning and dismantling permit to PreussenElektra for the Grohnde nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Dec 2023 12:54:18 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Decommissioning-of-Grohnde-set-to-begin?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 4771a0e8-91be-44d5-989a-6d1acac6b177 </guid><title><![CDATA[ENEC, NPPA to explore cooperation opportunities]]></title><description><![CDATA[The company responsible for implementing the UAE&#39;s civil nuclear power programme and the owner of Egypt&#39;s first nuclear power plant are to explore potential areas for cooperation in the peaceful uses of nuclear energy under a new agreement signed during COP28.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Dec 2023 11:47:14 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/ENEC,-NPPA-to-explore-cooperation-opportunities?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> df70426b-5288-44fe-9124-df628f5748e7 </guid><title><![CDATA[Akkuyu unit 1 gets commissioning permit]]></title><description><![CDATA[Turkey&#39;s Nuclear Regulatory Agency has issued permission to the Akkuyu nuclear power plant to commission the first power unit.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Dec 2023 11:46:51 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Akkuyu-unit-1-gets-commissioning-permit?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 64a77366-274b-4d45-8237-ac656bd3d375 </guid><title><![CDATA[ENEC signs multiple SMR MoUs]]></title><description><![CDATA[The company responsible for implementing the UAE&#39;s civil nuclear power programme has signed separate agreements with several small modular reactor developers on the sidelines of the COP28 climate conference in Dubai.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Dec 2023 16:20:37 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/ENEC-signs-multiple-SMR-MoUs?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 55258cf4-5661-4532-a120-57116de40ff7 </guid><title><![CDATA[Hyundai, KAERI team up for export of SMART SMR]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hyundai Engineering and the Korea Atomic Energy Research Institute have signed a memorandum of understanding to collaborate on the commercialisation and export of the Korean-designed SMART small modular reactor overseas.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Dec 2023 14:34:31 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Hyundai,-KAERI-team-up-for-export-of-SMART-SMR?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b2f5863b-e893-410f-9aae-e427766b1ff9 </guid><title><![CDATA[Nuclear included in NZIA by European Council]]></title><description><![CDATA[The European Council has adopted its position on the proposed Net-Zero Industry Act, which is intended to bolster Europe&#39;s manufacturing output in technologies needed for decarbonisation. As with the European Parliament&#39;s position, issued last month, nuclear power has been included in the list of &quot;strategic&quot; technologies.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Dec 2023 15:35:39 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Nuclear-included-in-NZIA-by-European-Council?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 05c143fb-1b77-4878-9fac-404def00b34d </guid><title><![CDATA[Sheffield Forgemasters set to regain key nuclear accreditation]]></title><description><![CDATA[The UK company says it is on track to regain ASME status as a supplier of heavy forgings and castings to the civil nuclear market, to position it for the proposed large-scale expansion of nuclear capacity in the country.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Dec 2023 14:54:59 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Shefield-Forgemasters-aims-to-regain-key-nuclear-a?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>