<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 11d788a7-7de6-4b8d-a7ae-3fec7e525831 </guid><title><![CDATA[Sweden and UK agree to enhance cooperation in nuclear]]></title><description><![CDATA[A strategic partnership has been signed between the UK and Sweden aimed at &quot;reinvigorated and deepened cooperation across the bilateral relationship, including on security and defence, innovation, science, energy and climate, people to people and trade and investment&quot;. It includes cooperation on nuclear reactor technologies, including small modular reactors, and diversifying nuclear fuel supplies.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 14:51:31 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Sweden-and-UK-agree-to-enhance-cooperation-in-nucl?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7a0c0a9e-07da-4a0c-93d9-9c14fa33af15 </guid><title><![CDATA[Full government support for Niger uranium project]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Government of Niger has confirmed its &quot;full support&quot; for Global Atomic Corporation&#39;s Dasa uranium project, the company has said. The project is still pencilled in to make its first yellowcake deliveries in 2025 and remains unimpaired by a recent US decision to put a hold on US Development Bank financing following the coup that took place in Niger earlier this year.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 14:05:36 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Full-government-support-for-Niger-uranium-project?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7966029c-b526-4922-ad23-7fac3f61c67f </guid><title><![CDATA[Nuclear fusion: New initiatives outlined at FEC 2023 conference]]></title><description><![CDATA[The first edition of <em>世界聚变展望和组建<em>世界聚变能源小组的</em>提议，以及整个行业的最新进展和英国东道主的新投资，已在<em>第 29 届国际原子能机构聚变能源会议</em>上公布。]]>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 12:54:30 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Nuclear-fusion-IAEA-sets-out-new-initiatives-at-FE?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 1da68c03-817f-4f02-8248-e7dde2715745 </guid><title><![CDATA[Another Zaporizhzhia unit to be put into hot shutdown]]></title><description><![CDATA[The International Atomic Energy Agency said it has been informed that a second reactor at the Russian-occupied Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant in Ukraine is being brought into hot shutdown in order to provide hot water and district heating over the coming winter.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 11:21:36 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Second-Zaporizhzhia-unit-to-be-put-into-hot-shutdo?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 797df574-3c88-45c4-90ec-8ca5d725cee3 </guid><title><![CDATA[Rosatom expands cooperation in West Africa]]></title><description><![CDATA[Russian state nuclear corporation Rosatom has signed a memorandum of understanding with Burkina Faso and another with Mali on cooperation in the field of the use of nuclear energy for peaceful purposes.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 13:45:52 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Rosatom-expands-cooperation-in-West-Africa?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> fb531f82-487d-40c7-bf52-6e85fd6d437b </guid><title><![CDATA[France and Brazil discuss nuclear energy links]]></title><description><![CDATA[France and Brazil are looking to &quot;rebuild cooperation&quot; in the energy sector with an emphasis on nuclear energy, after energy ministers from the two countries held talks in Paris.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 10:54:45 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/France-and-Brazil-discuss-nuclear-energy-links?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 712d2a20-6a7d-4f46-b9ca-ac6ee4098035 </guid><title><![CDATA[Franco-Mongolian protocol lays foundations for uranium project]]></title><description><![CDATA[An agreement between Orano and Mongolian state-owned investment company Erdenes Mongol LLC sets out the framework for an investment agreement that will lay the foundations for a long-term relationship for the development and industrial operation of the Zuuvch-Ovoo uranium project in south-western Mongolia. The investment agreement is expected to be signed by the end of the year.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 13:55:43 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Franco-Mongolian-protocol-lays-foundations-for-ura?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 53e5320a-cad7-465d-9bb6-ce5f4f486e5a </guid><title><![CDATA[Sheffield Forgemasters joins UK Xe-100 deployment effort]]></title><description><![CDATA[Sheffield Forgemasters, X-energy and Cavendish Nuclear have signed a memorandum of understanding on collaborating to explore opportunities around the deployment of a fleet of Xe-100 high temperature gas-cooled reactors in the UK.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 11:41:17 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Sheffield-Forgemasters-joins-UK-Xe-100-deployment?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 05dd0074-a11d-4d84-8fd3-a0c619725e9a </guid><title><![CDATA[Multinational consortium formed for Cernavoda work]]></title><description><![CDATA[Korea Hydro &amp; Nuclear Power announced it has signed an agreement with Canada&#39;s Candu Energy and Italy&#39;s Ansaldo Nucleare to jointly carry out a refurbishment of unit 1 at the Cernavoda nuclear power plant in Romania.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 14:09:18 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Multinational-consortium-formed-for-Cernavoda-work?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f87b58e2-8164-493e-9178-43eaaf98e32c </guid><title><![CDATA[Floating nuclear power plant set for first refuelling]]></title><description><![CDATA[Nuclear fuel has been delivered to Russia&#39;s floating nuclear power plant&nbsp;<em>罗蒙诺索夫院士将在今年年底前开始具有里程碑意义的加油工作。]]>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 14:55:02 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Floating-nuclear-power-plant-set-for-first-refuell?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> e4f0df7f-81fe-4cc0-a2b9-d3b188a05416</guid><title><![CDATA[Bruce Power-backed hydrogen study wins IESO funding]]></title><description><![CDATA[The study by Kinectrics and FuelCell Energy, supported by Bruce Power, will explore the potential of using nuclear-generated electricity to produce hydrogen and is one of six projects selected to receive a share of the first CAD7.5 million (USD5.5 million) of funding from the Ontario government&#39;s new Hydrogen Innovation Fund.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 15:06:20 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Bruce-Power-backed-hydrogen-study-wins-IESO-fundin?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>