<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ebf97e87-e0bf-42da-a872-31a31142f22f </guid><title><![CDATA[Kazakh people to decide on nuclear plant construction]]></title><description><![CDATA[Kazakhstan is to hold a referendum on the construction of a nuclear power plant in the country, President Kassym-Jomart Tokayev announced during a state-of-the-nation address. The date of the vote has yet to be determined.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 14:30:11 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Kazakh-people-to-decide-on-nuclear-plant-construct?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 54e28ba5-07e8-453f-b803-44dc7aea4071 </guid><title><![CDATA[Peninsula unveils revised strategy for Lance]]></title><description><![CDATA[Peninsula Energy says it expects to commence uranium production at its flagship uranium project in Wyoming at the end of 2024 under a newly released revised Life-of-Mine plan which features a new on-site recovery plant.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 14:27:14 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Peninsula-unveils-revised-strategy-for-Lance?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 2434f7c3-ed8f-4afa-ae4d-86466eddc2e2 </guid><title><![CDATA[Czech PM suggests four new nuclear units needed]]></title><description><![CDATA[In a speech to open a conference discussing future strategy for the Czech Republic, Prime Minister Petr Fiala said the country would need as many as four new nuclear power units.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 13:15:54 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Czech-PM-suggests-four-new-nuclear-units-needed?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> c6f60cab-f86b-4bb0-9e46-94ad60eae85c </guid><title><![CDATA[Defuelling completed at Mühleberg]]></title><description><![CDATA[All the nuclear fuel at the shut down Mühleberg nuclear power plant has now been transported to the Zwilag interim storage facility in Würenlingen, Swiss utility BKW announced. The removal of the fuel marks the completion of the first of three stages of decommissioning of the plant.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 11:41:07 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Defuelling-completed-at-Muhleberg?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 58f171ad-42ca-4aef-98b4-9ce8a33305de </guid><title><![CDATA[Walking robot tested in Finnish repository]]></title><description><![CDATA[A four-legged robot designed for autonomous operation in challenging environments has been put through its paces at a depth of more than 400 metres in the tunnels of the Onkalo underground used nuclear fuel repository near Olkiluoto, Finland.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 31 Aug 2023 15:33:02 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Walking-robot-tested-in-Finnish-repository?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> fcdbda94-f4e9-4365-adde-0863d6338da1 </guid><title><![CDATA[Permit issued for construction of fourth Egyptian unit]]></title><description><![CDATA[Egypt&#39;s Nuclear Power Plants Authority has been granted a licence by the country&#39;s nuclear regulator for the construction of the fourth and final unit at the El Dabaa nuclear power plant. Construction of unit 4 is scheduled to begin by the end of this year.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 31 Aug 2023 11:38:36 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Permit-issued-for-construction-of-fourth-Egyptian?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 98875b4d-dfe6-471e-9855-78683bfe32f7 </guid><title><![CDATA[EDF and JAVYS sign cooperation agreement]]></title><description><![CDATA[EDF and JAVYS have signed a framework cooperation agreement covering new nuclear in Slovakia, including both large nuclear power plants and small modular reactors.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 31 Aug 2023 12:06:09 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/EDF-and-JAVYS-sign-cooperation-agreement?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a97cc377-5aba-4256-a688-29a340330d92 </guid><title><![CDATA[US projects to look at nuclear role in carbon capture]]></title><description><![CDATA[Two projects to explore the feasibility of using nuclear energy in systems to remove carbon dioxide directly from the atmosphere - one led by GE Vernova and one led by Northwestern University - are included in a list of 19 projects selected to receive US Department of Energy support.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 31 Aug 2023 14:36:57 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/US-projects-to-look-at-nuclear-role-in-carbon-capt?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 0eb6ed70-981f-4e91-8a2d-99f365101415 </guid><title><![CDATA[Tractebel, Hatch team up for nuclear new build]]></title><description><![CDATA[Belgian engineering firm Tractebel and Canadian engineering, project management, and professional services firm Hatch have agreed to cooperate on supporting the deployment of small and large nuclear technologies in North America and Europe.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 31 Aug 2023 13:23:01 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Tractebel,-Hatch-team-up-for-nuclear-new-build?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ba958926-489d-4de6-8bbb-ddd82a4ba889 </guid><title><![CDATA[Court annuls licence for Texas used fuel store]]></title><description><![CDATA[The licence issued for the construction and operation of a consolidated interim storage facility for used nuclear fuel in Texas has been cancelled by a US appeals court. The court ruled that the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission does not have the authority to license a private storage facility away from nuclear reactors.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 30 Aug 2023 13:12:17 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Court-annuls-licence-for-Texas-used-fuel-store?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 996e9df9-abf4-4e32-98da-9570dba8eaca </guid><title><![CDATA[Atucha II returns to service after completing repairs]]></title><description><![CDATA[Argentina&#39;s Atucha II nuclear unit is delivering power again after the successful completion of repairs prompted by the October 2022 inspection discovery that one of the four internal supports of the reactor had detached and moved from its design location.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 30 Aug 2023 12:35:16 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Atucha-II-returns-to-service-after-unique-repairs?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>