<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ddaa2262-23b9-42ed-a52f-8f743c9e15dd </guid><title><![CDATA[Westinghouse to expand fuel offerings from UK facility]]></title><description><![CDATA[Westinghouse has been awarded three grants totalling GBP10.5 million (USD13.6 million) from the UK government&#39;s Nuclear Fuel Fund to upgrade and expand the Springfields fuel fabrication facility in Lancashire in northwest England.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 13:33:37 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Westinghouse-to-expand-fuel-offerings-from-UK-faci?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 33dfa9ae-3a2c-47fd-8fd9-944b426a38db</guid><title><![CDATA[British-Japanese partnership for fusion development]]></title><description><![CDATA[UK-based nuclear fusion company Tokamak Energy and Japan&#39;s Sumitomo Corporation have agreed to collaborate on the development, implementation and scaling-up of commercial fusion energy in Japan and worldwide.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 11:31:06 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/British-Japanese-partnership-for-fusion-developmen?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 116d7178-5a18-444c-8a89-8ddbd3daa645</guid><title><![CDATA[Burundi and Russia agreement on nuclear cooperation]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Republic of Burundi and Russia have signed a memorandum of cooperation on peaceful uses of nuclear technology. It was signed as the&nbsp;<em>俄罗斯-非洲经济和人道主义论坛在圣彼得堡举行。]]>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 10:29:26 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Burundi-and-Ethiopia-among-Russia-Africa-nuclear-c?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 56e5ee39-6811-480b-床1-8bbab964e9d6 </guid><title><![CDATA[CNL eyes dramatic increase in Ac-225 production]]></title><description><![CDATA[Canadian Nuclear Laboratories has announced an agreement with the Sylvia Fedoruk Centre for Nuclear Innovation - part of the University of Saskatchewan - that will enable it to increase by more than 30 times its current production of the rare actinium-225 radioisotope.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 14:50:11 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/CNL-eyes-dramatic-increase-in-Ac-225-production?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 226751e2-1999-466b-ba7b-71ed02a48fa8 </guid><title><![CDATA[BWXT to begin work on cislunar nuclear rocket engine and fuel]]></title><description><![CDATA[The USA&#39;s Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency has finalised an agreement with Lockheed Martin to begin work on the fabrication and design of an experimental nuclear thermal rocket and its engine. BWX Technologies, one of Lockheed Martin&#39;s partners in the effort, will develop the nuclear reactor and fabricate the HALEU fuel.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 14:27:21 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/BWXT-to-begin-work-on-DRACO-engine-and-fuel?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 62457a56-1476-4851-b412-86f5efa1d501 </guid><title><![CDATA[Dome hoisted into place on Xudapu 3]]></title><description><![CDATA[The dome has been hoisted into place on the reactor building of Xudapu unit 3 in a single stage process, six months ahead of schedule, with China National Nuclear Corporation describing the project as &quot;a model of global energy cooperation&quot;.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 13:49:17 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Dome-hoisted-into-place-on-Xudapu-3?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> feac4774-feba-40b4-9274-379329aabbdd </guid><title><![CDATA[Framatome EATF completes first cycle in US reactor]]></title><description><![CDATA[A lead assembly of Framatome&#39;s 100% Enhanced Accident Tolerant Fuel has successfully completed its first cycle of operation at a US nuclear power plant. The assembly was inserted into unit 2 of the Calvert Cliffs plant in Maryland during a refueling outage in early 2021.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 11:56:57 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Framatome-EATF-completes-first-cycle-in-US-reactor?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 93f58c18-9709-45bb-a6dd-fd4b77c1a518 </guid><title><![CDATA[MHI to lead development of Japanese HTGR]]></title><description><![CDATA[Japan&#39;s Agency for Natural Resources and Energy - part of the Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry - has selected Mitsubishi Heavy Industries as the core company to lead the development of a high temperature gas-cooled reactor programme.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:38:20 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/MHI-to-lead-development-of-Japanese-HTGR?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ac7a4d96-3c96-4c90-95e8-952b035ef47e </guid><title><![CDATA[Key upgrade completed at Darlington]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ontario Power Generation has completed a major 10-year project to install three new emergency power generators at its Darlington nuclear power plant to support the continued operation of the plant for decades to come.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 15:12:02 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Key-upgrade-completed-at-Darlington?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> c36e9e54-5f05-4bf9-90dd-b013573dfe41 </guid><title><![CDATA[Bugey chosen to host two EPR2 reactors]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Bugey nuclear power plant site in eastern France has been selected by the country&#39;s Nuclear Policy Council for the installation of the third pair of EPR2 reactors, after the Penly and Gravelines sites.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 15:00:28 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Bugey-chosen-to-host-two-EPR2-reactors?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> c0f45288-6843-4f4c-9f4d-1c566378d44f </guid><title><![CDATA[Kairos seeks construction licence for two-unit Hermes plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[Kairos Power has submitted an application to the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission for permission to build the Hermes 2 plant next to the Hermes molten salt test reactor it plans to build at Oak Ridge, Tennessee. The two-unit demonstration plant would produce and sell electricity.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 14:35:12 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Kairos-seeks-construction-licence-for-two-unit-Her?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>