<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 928e0d83-afd6-42e5-b05b-dc0a62826c39 </guid><title><![CDATA[Hydro-Québec mulls Gentilly 2 recommissioning]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hydro-Québec has confirmed it is assessing the current state of the plant which closed in 2012, as it looks at options to increase its production of clean electricity.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 15:09:47 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Hydro-Quebec-mulls-Gentilly-2-recommissioning?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7abc3852-94ad-436d-9228-26dfd9fa1a76 </guid><title><![CDATA[Search resumes for site for Australian radwaste facility]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Australian government is no longer looking to site a national low and intermediate-level radioactive waste facility in Napandee near Kimba in South Australia. It said it will not appeal a Federal Court decision to dismiss a 2021 declaration naming Napandee the proposed site for the facility.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 14:28:18 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Search-resumes-for-site-for-Australian-radwaste-fa?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 3ebdeaa9-71a7-4b26-b11e-1636032ef654 </guid><title><![CDATA[Work continues at Dasa as Niger 'relatively calm']]></title><description><![CDATA[Global Atomic Corporation said the current circumstances in Niger could delay commissioning of the processing plant at its Dasa project by up to 12 months, but expects to be able to resume dialogue with the country&#39;s Ministry of Mines following the appointment of a new minister.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 15:51:06 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Work-continues-at-Dasa-as-Niger-relatively-calm?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> cba20c6a-f52e-4ad8-ac1c-65cc23823779 </guid><title><![CDATA[Zaporizhzhia 4 taken out of hot shutdown due to water leak]]></title><description><![CDATA[Unit 4 at the Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant is being switched from hot shutdown to cold shutdown following the detection of a water leak at one of its four steam generators. Meanwhile, unit 6 is being moved to hot shutdown to continue steam production on the site.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 11:50:01 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Zaporizhzhia-4-taken-out-of-hot-shutdown-due-to-wa?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b1f88d60-91c3-4052-946f-40b20e4d0080 </guid><title><![CDATA[Core module installed at Chinese SMR]]></title><description><![CDATA[The core module has been installed within the reactor building of the ACP100 small modular reactor demonstration project, China National Nuclear Corporation has announced.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 10 Aug 2023 11:06:35 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Core-module-installed-at-Chinese-SMR?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 94a9db98-3508-413e-9c1a-e54d1e594a61 </guid><title><![CDATA[General Fusion announces new fusion demo machine]]></title><description><![CDATA[Canadian private fusion developer General Fusion has announced plans for a new Magnetised Target Fusion machine designed to achieve fusion conditions of over 100 million degrees Celsius by 2025, and progress toward scientific breakeven by 2026.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 10 Aug 2023 15:00:20 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/General-Fusion-announces-new-fusion-demo-machine?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 467ef2e8-13f8-474b-b370-2fe371ca1437 </guid><title><![CDATA[Rooppur fuel passes inspection as onsite work progresses]]></title><description><![CDATA[The first fuel for Rooppur 1&#39;s initial load has been formally accepted by the Bangladesh Atomic Energy Commission after an inspection at the Novosibirsk Chemical Concentrates Plant in Russia. Meanwhile, installation of the unit&#39;s eight heat exchangers has been completed at the plant site in Bangladesh.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 10 Aug 2023 14:37:29 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Rooppur-fuel-passes-inspection-as-onsite-work-prog?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 385566a5-f6e7-4c20-b8ce-fc22e38c3a0e </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA conducts first mission on disused sources]]></title><description><![CDATA[The International Atomic Energy Agency has carried out the inaugural mission, in Thailand, of the Disused Sealed Radioactive Sources Technical Centre peer review service. This new service aims to enlarge the global pool of resources and support for countries in the sustainable management of these sources.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 10 Aug 2023 13:33:18 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-conducts-first-mission-on-disused-sources?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a3e7f629-e598-4b3c-ad94-2b6b0f20cbe5 </guid><title><![CDATA[Swedish regulator proposes framework for expansion of nuclear]]></title><description><![CDATA[Sweden&#39;s Radiation Safety Authority has presented its final report to the government on how the regulatory framework for nuclear power should be developed and what other measures may be needed for nuclear power to be expanded in the country.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 11:56:38 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Swedish-regulator-proposes-framework-for-expansion?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> efb84472-a350-436b-9d52-05cf8501181c </guid><title><![CDATA[Bruce 6 restarted following refurbishment]]></title><description><![CDATA[Unit 6 of the Bruce nuclear power plant in Ontario has resumed operation following its Major Component Replacement project, Bruce Power announced. The Candu reactor, which was taken offline for the work in January 2020, is scheduled to resume commercial operation later this year.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 14:23:08 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Bruce-6-restarted-following-refurbishment?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 25a12e1d-d76f-498b-82e1-ae2ed71a00e4 </guid><title><![CDATA[First Light Fusion and Tractebel Machine 4 development agreement]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tractebel and First Light Fusion have signed a framework agreement for the development of the Machine 4 project designed to demonstrate net energy gain.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 14:43:21 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/First-Light-Fusion-and-Tractebel Machine-4-develop?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>