<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 64a77366-274b-4d45-8237-ac656bd3d375 </guid><title><![CDATA[ENEC signs multiple SMR MoUs]]></title><description><![CDATA[The company responsible for implementing the UAE&#39;s civil nuclear power programme has signed separate agreements with several small modular reactor developers on the sidelines of the COP28 climate conference in Dubai.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Dec 2023 16:20:37 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/ENEC-signs-multiple-SMR-MoUs?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 55258cf4-5661-4532-a120-57116de40ff7 </guid><title><![CDATA[Hyundai, KAERI team up for export of SMART SMR]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hyundai Engineering and the Korea Atomic Energy Research Institute have signed a memorandum of understanding to collaborate on the commercialisation and export of the Korean-designed SMART small modular reactor overseas.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Dec 2023 14:34:31 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Hyundai,-KAERI-team-up-for-export-of-SMART-SMR?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b2f5863b-e893-410f-9aae-e427766b1ff9 </guid><title><![CDATA[Nuclear included in NZIA by European Council]]></title><description><![CDATA[The European Council has adopted its position on the proposed Net-Zero Industry Act, which is intended to bolster Europe&#39;s manufacturing output in technologies needed for decarbonisation. As with the European Parliament&#39;s position, issued last month, nuclear power has been included in the list of &quot;strategic&quot; technologies.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Dec 2023 15:35:39 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Nuclear-included-in-NZIA-by-European-Council?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 05c143fb-1b77-4878-9fac-404def00b34d </guid><title><![CDATA[Sheffield Forgemasters set to regain key nuclear accreditation]]></title><description><![CDATA[The UK company says it is on track to regain ASME status as a supplier of heavy forgings and castings to the civil nuclear market, to position it for the proposed large-scale expansion of nuclear capacity in the country.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Dec 2023 14:54:59 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Shefield-Forgemasters-aims-to-regain-key-nuclear-a?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> d683ce9b-8d45-4b47-bd41-d39c1eb44294 </guid><title><![CDATA[Six SMR power plants approved in Poland]]></title><description><![CDATA[Poland&#39;s Ministry of Climate and Environment has issued decisions-in-principle for the construction of power plants based on GE Hitachi Nuclear Energy&#39;s BWRX-300 small modular reactor at six locations. A total of 24 BWRX-300 reactors are planned at the sites.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 08 Dec 2023 12:15:19 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Six-SMR-power-plants-approved-in-Poland?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> bcc49065-ea8a-44c9-ac61-8426fd0fac86 </guid><title><![CDATA[Chernobyl gets six-year extension for work on original shelter]]></title><description><![CDATA[An extension has been agreed for the dismantling of the parts of the original shelter facility most at risk of collapse. The structure was built in 206 days following the 1986 accident at Ukraine&#39;s Chernobyl nuclear power plant.&nbsp;]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 07 Dec 2023 16:08:51 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Chernobyl-s-original-shelter-gets-six-year-extensi?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b5020a45-b11e-41db-a50d-d7aac4b9bab7 </guid><title><![CDATA[Crystal River reactor vessel removal completed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Work to segment, package and remove the reactor vessel and its internal components has been completed in less than two years thanks to Orano&#39;s use of its patented Optimised Segmentation process. The operation included industry-first lifts carried out by Mammoet.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 08 Dec 2023 16:13:13 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Crystal-River-reactor-vessel-removal-completed?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 315faaaf-d656-42f8-98ac-5a635ba3ec69 </guid><title><![CDATA[Peregrine falcon from Czech nuclear plant being cared for after shooting]]></title><description><![CDATA[One of the first peregrine falcons hatched at the Dukovany nuclear power plant, in 2020, is in a rescue centre after being discovered with shotgun injuries.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 08 Dec 2023 15:28:23 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Peregrine-falcon-from-Czech-nuclear-plant-being-ca?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 380ad89a-8cbe-4fdb-988f-f00f8af3fee0 </guid><title><![CDATA[Pilot plant for Lightbridge fuel mooted for Ohio]]></title><description><![CDATA[Lightbridge Corporation and Centrus Energy Corp are to carry out a front-end engineering and design study to add a dedicated fabrication facility for Lightbridge&#39;s next-generation nuclear fuel at the American Centrifuge Plant in Piketon, Ohio.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 08 Dec 2023 14:50:45 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Pilot-plant-for-Lightbridge-fuel-mooted-for-Ohio?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 9e6eb6db-2704-4dd9-b0dd-fe62d2cb0257 </guid><title><![CDATA[Further contracts awarded to progress UK's fusion effort]]></title><description><![CDATA[The United Kingdom Atomic Energy Authority has awarded 10 contracts worth a total GBP11.6 million (USD14.6 million) to nine organisations to develop their innovative technologies for fusion energy.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 08 Dec 2023 13:15:22 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Further-contracts-awarded-to-progress-UK-s-fusion?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 75afbbb1-badf-4d04-8741-2d0ada251485 </guid><title><![CDATA[Hungary aims to extend life of Paks nuclear plant by 20 years]]></title><description><![CDATA[The operator of the Paks nuclear power plant in Hungary has notified the European Union of the country&#39;s intention to extend the operating lifetime of the four units to 70 years.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 07 Dec 2023 14:49:16 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Hungary-aims-to-extend-life-of-Paks-nuclear-plant?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>