<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 46d3bf47-187d-458b-a08d-58e434a7b52e </guid><title><![CDATA[Chinese long-distance nuclear heating project begins operation]]></title><description><![CDATA[China&#39;s first project to bring nuclear-generated heat to multiple prefecture-level cities has begun operation in Shandong province, supplying heat from the Haiyang nuclear power plant to the cities of Haiyang and Rushan through a 23 km pipeline.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 14:32:58 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Chinese-long-distance-nuclear-heating-project-begi?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 9f06140d-5d80-405b-9011-0dd3c8af41b1 </guid><title><![CDATA[Second large Polish nuclear plant gets approval]]></title><description><![CDATA[Poland&#39;s Ministry of Climate and Environment has issued a decision-in-principle for the country&#39;s second large nuclear power plant. Two South Korean-supplied APR1400 reactors are planned in the Patnów-Konin region.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 13:25:38 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Second-large-Polish-nuclear-plant-gets-approval?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b8844839-b3d1-42d8-a875-c3c714ff8b3d </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA reports rockets fired from near Zaporizhzhia plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[International Atomic Energy Agency staff at the Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant say they heard what sounded like rockets &quot;fired from a Multiple Launch Rocket System nearby&quot; - it came on the same day the site lost connection to its main off-site power line.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 13:20:51 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-reports-rockets-fired-from-near-Zaporizhzhia?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> cd3b5420-89fe-4874-a259-5be479675dc6 </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA finds commitment to safety at Russian fast reactor]]></title><description><![CDATA[An International Atomic Energy Agency team of experts have reviewed operational safety at unit 4 of Russia&#39;s Beloyarsk nuclear power plant. It marks the first Operational Safety Review Team mission to a fast neutron reactor.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 14:32:41 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-finds-commitment-to-safety-at-Russian-fast-re?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 2d1de023-bf35-4838-a93b-a0b3032abcc9 </guid><title><![CDATA[Bruce completes largest-to-date radioisotope delivery]]></title><description><![CDATA[October&#39;s harvest of cobalt-60, used worldwide to sterilise medical equipment, was the largest since the company began producing the isotope in the 1980s and included two shipments of medical-grade material for therapeutic use.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 13:41:22 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Bruce-completes-largest-to-date-radioisotope-deliv?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b877e0a5-db29-4413-8dfb-8ac64dfbb22a </guid><title><![CDATA[First refuelling at floating nuclear power plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[Fresh nuclear fuel has been loaded into the starboard side reactor on the&nbsp;<em> Rosatom 表示，罗蒙诺索夫院士进行了首次此类手术，该过程将于今年年底完成。]]>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 15:19:08 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Refuelling?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 5d554e34-1296-4b87-8d53-44b2e746567b </guid><title><![CDATA[Hungary to consider alternative sources for nuclear fuel]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Hungarian Parliament has reportedly supported an amendment to the country&#39;s nuclear energy policy that would allow alternative sources to be used for fuel for the Paks nuclear power plant, which has until now relied on Russian-supplied fuel.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 12:47:51 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Hungary-to-consider-alternative-sources-for-nuclea?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 56e8fda5-a95c-4f42-ac97-f03e01690f54 </guid><title><![CDATA[Eletronuclear outlines clean hydrogen production plan]]></title><description><![CDATA[A project to produce 100 tonnes a year of clean hydrogen from the operation of the Angra nuclear power plant&#39;s two units was detailed at a seminar on sustainable hydrogen production in Brazil.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 12:40:13 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Eletronuclear-plans-clean-hydrogen-production?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 432667e7-6581-46d8-a6b6-d270709b4ef3 </guid><title><![CDATA[Technology evaluation for Bruce expansion to begin early 2024]]></title><description><![CDATA[Bruce Power is to launch a Request for Information to evaluate potential new nuclear technologies as part of its preliminary engagement and long-term review of expanding nuclear generation on its existing Ontario site. It has also set up a new advisory panel drawn from business, industry and labour leaders that will work in parallel with the RFI timetable.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 14:27:14 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Technology-evaluation-for-Bruce-expansion-to-begin?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 5f8fb6ba-0228-4749-b373-2f9152bf96f4 </guid><title><![CDATA[Commissioning of WIPP ventilation system begins]]></title><description><![CDATA[Commissioning of the new large-scale ventilation system at the Waste Isolation Pilot Plant is at the top of the list of the US Department of Energy Office of Environmental Management&#39;s priorities for 2023.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 15:27:09 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Commissioning-of-WIPP-ventilation-system-begins?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 0f64f635-2dfd-4799-b963-acadeb983caf </guid><title><![CDATA[INL produces HALEU pellets for testing]]></title><description><![CDATA[Researchers at Idaho National Laboratory recently fabricated about two dozen commercial-grade high-assay low-enriched uranium fuel pellets for testing. A further 100-150 pellets are to be made for irradiation tests in the Advanced Test Reactor.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 14:55:51 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/INL-produces-HALEU-pellets-for-testing?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>