<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 58f171ad-42ca-4aef-98b4-9ce8a33305de </guid><title><![CDATA[Walking robot tested in Finnish repository]]></title><description><![CDATA[A four-legged robot designed for autonomous operation in challenging environments has been put through its paces at a depth of more than 400 metres in the tunnels of the Onkalo underground used nuclear fuel repository near Olkiluoto, Finland.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 31 Aug 2023 15:33:02 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Walking-robot-tested-in-Finnish-repository?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> fcdbda94-f4e9-4365-adde-0863d6338da1 </guid><title><![CDATA[Permit issued for construction of fourth Egyptian unit]]></title><description><![CDATA[Egypt&#39;s Nuclear Power Plants Authority has been granted a licence by the country&#39;s nuclear regulator for the construction of the fourth and final unit at the El Dabaa nuclear power plant. Construction of unit 4 is scheduled to begin by the end of this year.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 31 Aug 2023 11:38:36 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Permit-issued-for-construction-of-fourth-Egyptian?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 98875b4d-dfe6-471e-9855-78683bfe32f7 </guid><title><![CDATA[EDF and JAVYS sign cooperation agreement]]></title><description><![CDATA[EDF and JAVYS have signed a framework cooperation agreement covering new nuclear in Slovakia, including both large nuclear power plants and small modular reactors.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 31 Aug 2023 12:06:09 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/EDF-and-JAVYS-sign-cooperation-agreement?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a97cc377-5aba-4256-a688-29a340330d92 </guid><title><![CDATA[US projects to look at nuclear role in carbon capture]]></title><description><![CDATA[Two projects to explore the feasibility of using nuclear energy in systems to remove carbon dioxide directly from the atmosphere - one led by GE Vernova and one led by Northwestern University - are included in a list of 19 projects selected to receive US Department of Energy support.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 31 Aug 2023 14:36:57 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/US-projects-to-look-at-nuclear-role-in-carbon-capt?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 0eb6ed70-981f-4e91-8a2d-99f365101415 </guid><title><![CDATA[Tractebel, Hatch team up for nuclear new build]]></title><description><![CDATA[Belgian engineering firm Tractebel and Canadian engineering, project management, and professional services firm Hatch have agreed to cooperate on supporting the deployment of small and large nuclear technologies in North America and Europe.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 31 Aug 2023 13:23:01 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Tractebel,-Hatch-team-up-for-nuclear-new-build?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ba958926-489d-4de6-8bbb-ddd82a4ba889 </guid><title><![CDATA[Court annuls licence for Texas used fuel store]]></title><description><![CDATA[The licence issued for the construction and operation of a consolidated interim storage facility for used nuclear fuel in Texas has been cancelled by a US appeals court. The court ruled that the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission does not have the authority to license a private storage facility away from nuclear reactors.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 30 Aug 2023 13:12:17 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Court-annuls-licence-for-Texas-used-fuel-store?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 996e9df9-abf4-4e32-98da-9570dba8eaca </guid><title><![CDATA[Atucha II returns to service after completing repairs]]></title><description><![CDATA[Argentina&#39;s Atucha II nuclear unit is delivering power again after the successful completion of repairs prompted by the October 2022 inspection discovery that one of the four internal supports of the reactor had detached and moved from its design location.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 30 Aug 2023 12:35:16 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Atucha-II-returns-to-service-after-unique-repairs?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 94ef4539-1427-4124-8636-13a320060616 </guid><title><![CDATA[More funding for Sizewell C preparations]]></title><description><![CDATA[The UK government has made available a further GBP341 million (USD434 million) of previously allocated funding for development work on the Sizewell C nuclear power plant project in Suffolk, England. It said the extra money will help prepare the site for construction, procuring key components from the project&#39;s supply chain, and expanding its workforce.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 30 Aug 2023 14:53:20 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/More-funding-for-Sizewell-C-preparations?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7dc93ca7-2a34-4c65-a2ea-5ee694ab2897 </guid><title><![CDATA[Westinghouse expands fuel offerings of Columbia plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[Westinghouse has announced the creation of a centre of excellence for Low Enriched Uranium Plus fuel manufacturing at its Columbia Fuel Fabrication Facility in Hopkins, South Carolina.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 29 Aug 2023 14:25:40 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Westinghouse-expands-fuel-offerings-of-Columbia-pl?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 39f8d9ba-ad93-4125-9d26-ff4747ccd83c </guid><title><![CDATA[Construction of Lufeng unit 6 begins]]></title><description><![CDATA[The first safety-related concrete has been poured for the nuclear island of the unit 6 HPR1000 (Hualong One) at the Lufeng nuclear power plant in China&#39;s Guangdong province. It is the second HPR1000 under construction at the site, where four CAP1000s are also planned.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 29 Aug 2023 12:23:23 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Construction-of-Lufeng-unit-6-begins?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 747f9714-f00a-441b-893a-8822da283311 </guid><title><![CDATA[Oklo and Centrus Energy broaden links with MoU]]></title><description><![CDATA[Advanced reactor plant developer Oklo has expanded its partnership with Centrus Energy with a memorandum of understanding covering the development of the Aurora powerhouses and High-Assay, Low Enriched Uranium fuel supply.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 29 Aug 2023 13:34:04 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Oklo-and-Centrus-Energy-broaden-links-with-MoU?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>