<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 369b71e3-862d-438f-8c6d-e0a038e285cd </guid><title><![CDATA[PEJ teams up with university for nuclear skills development]]></title><description><![CDATA[Polskie Elektrownie Jądrowe and Warsaw University of Technology have signed an agreement to cooperate on the training of personnel for Poland&#39;s nuclear sector. PEJ is to construct the country&#39;s first large-scale nuclear power plant in Pomerania.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 15:45:05 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/PEJ-teams-up-with-university-for-nuclear-skills-de?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> af06c9dd-0b48-40ff-813c-944bf36ed3c8 </guid><title><![CDATA[AEOI head outlines Iranian nuclear energy targets]]></title><description><![CDATA[Atomic Energy Organization of Iran head Mohammad Eslami said the country is looking to increase its nuclear power generation capacity to 20 GWe. The country&#39;s first nuclear power plant, Bushehr, has now generated more than 60 billion kilowatt-hours, he told a parliamentary council.<br /> ]]>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 15:14:32 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/AEOI-head-outlines-Iranian-nuclear-targets?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a0abc198-484c-4843-a031-4951288092ad </guid><title><![CDATA[Chernobyl's stray dogs population tackled]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Clean Futures Fund&#39;s Dogs of Chernobyl project says that its sterilisation and vaccination campaign helped lead to no puppies being born at the site in the seven months to June.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 14:48:48 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Chernobyl-s-stray-dogs-population-tackled?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 447375c7-941e-4766-b93a-8098b1a91f36 </guid><title><![CDATA[T-Pylons in place in Hinkley Point C connection]]></title><description><![CDATA[All 116 of the novel T-pylons on National Grid&#39;s Hinkley Connection in the UK have now been completed. The 57-kilometre connection route will connect low-carbon energy from EDF Energy&#39;s Hinkley Point C nuclear power plant to six million UK homes and businesses whilst also allowing for more capacity on the network for renewable energy from the South West peninsular.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 12:58:14 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/T-Pylons-in-place-in-HPC-connection?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 2f763aee-bda3-4c85-bc89-439234a0a3ac </guid><title><![CDATA[Contract signed for IMSR fuel pilot plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[Terrestrial Energy has signed a manufacturing and supply contract with Westinghouse subsidiary Springfields Fuels Limited to deliver a pilot Integral Molten Salt Reactor fuel plant in the UK, paving the way to provide the fuel to support future fleet deployment of such reactors. The project is receiving support from the UK government&#39;s Nuclear Fuel Fund.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 04 Aug 2023 12:34:40 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Contract-signed-for-IMSR-fuel-pilot-plant?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 4fae951a-42a8-40ff-9795-392663213dd7 </guid><title><![CDATA[Final environmental assessment issued for US reactor experiment]]></title><description><![CDATA[The US Department of Energy has released a final environmental assessment and draft finding of no significant impact for the design, construction, and operation of the Molten Chloride Reactor Experiment, which is to be built by Southern Company at Idaho National Laboratory.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 04 Aug 2023 13:50:32 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Final-environmental-assessment-issued-for-US-react?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> eac2c1c3-a6b7-4989-a196-0a5dad1bfd3b </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA experts see no explosives on roof of Zaporizhzhia units 3 and 4]]></title><description><![CDATA[International Atomic Energy Agency staff have, after weeks of requests, been given access to the rooftops of reactor units 3 and 4 at the occupied Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant and &quot;observed no mines or explosives&quot;.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 04 Aug 2023 14:20:19 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-experts-see-no-explosives-on-roof-of-Zaporizh?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f1b7bf1b-50e5-46fa-a84b-844333755305 </guid><title><![CDATA[SHINE demonstrates Cherenkov radiation from fusion]]></title><description><![CDATA[SHINE Technologies of the USA says it has demonstrated clearly visible Cherenkov radiation produced by fusion for what is believed to be the first time. Historically, fusion has been demonstrated and detected with instruments instead of a visible light.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 04 Aug 2023 11:35:50 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/SHINE-demonstrates-Cherenkov-radiation-from-fusion?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> d3a171f9-a38c-41c0-9529-13ed4fb61020 </guid><title><![CDATA[Drones put into use at Sellafield site]]></title><description><![CDATA[Drone pilots have successfully completed two flight firsts on the UK&#39;s Sellafield site which are expected to lead the way to increased safety of employees during decommissioning. Sellafield has now become the first UK nuclear site to employ a drone equipped with a radiation monitor.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 04 Aug 2023 10:18:48 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Drones-put-into-use-at-Sellafield-site?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> e37cde37-5e9d-428f-a20a-1ed7df62cfd4 </guid><title><![CDATA[Reactor vessel arrives for Tianwan 7]]></title><description><![CDATA[The reactor vessel for unit 7 of Tianwan nuclear power plant in Jiangsu province, China, has arrived at the site after a two month journey by sea from Russia.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 04 Aug 2023 10:54:09 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Reactor-vessel-arrives-for-Tianwan-7?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 58f946d6-c00d-4817-96ff-52889f5cd161 </guid><title><![CDATA[India eyes SMRs but focuses on large reactors]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Indian government is exploring options for small modular reactors, but large-size plants are still the mainstay of the country&#39;s plans to expand its nuclear generating capacity, Minister of State Jitendra Singh has told the country&#39;s parliament.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 13:59:36 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/India-eyes-SMRs-but-focuses-on-large-reactors?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>