<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 2467f366-cc4f-4019-ad17-fe6caedb7b81 </guid><title><![CDATA[US computing infrastructure provider announces SMR plans]]></title><description><![CDATA[Standard Power plans to develop small modular reactor facilities in Ohio and Pennsylvania using NuScale&#39;s reactor technology to power nearby data centres.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 15:34:55 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/US-computing-infrastructure-provider-announces-SMR?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7ebb4a4f-e24a-4110-b5e1-79c9cc6a590e</guid><title><![CDATA[Holtec applies to restart shuttered Palisades plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Palisades plant in Michigan could become the first successfully restarted nuclear power plant in the USA following Holtec International&#39;s submission of a filing with the Nuclear Regulatory Commission to formally begin the process of seeking reauthorisation of power operations at the plant, which was shut down in May 2022.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 15:29:21 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Holtec-applies-to-restart-shuttered-Palisades-plan?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 84bb1da8-3eae-44fd-b10c-ae7313e83bb9 </guid><title><![CDATA[Egypt's first nuclear unit has core catcher installed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Officials from Egypt&#39;s Nuclear Power Plants Authority and Russia&#39;s Rosatom have held a ceremony to mark the installation of the core catcher in the first unit at the El Dabaa nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 13:22:57 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Egypt-s-first-nuclear-unit-has-core-catcher-instal?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 4d232096-8086-4621-8348-4c73c4397ebb </guid><title><![CDATA[Edison eyes SMR deployment in Italy]]></title><description><![CDATA[Leading Italian energy player Edison has announced its ambition to construct two nuclear power plants based on EDF&#39;s small modular reactor technology between 2030 and 2040, if the conditions are created for the return of nuclear energy to Italy.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 13:07:55 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Edison-eyes-SMR-deployment-in-Italy?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 598624a8-d849-4666-a787-91acc0d1ae82 </guid><title><![CDATA[Canadian integrated radioactive waste management strategy accepted]]></title><description><![CDATA[The strategy for radioactive waste other than used nuclear fuel will see Canada&#39;s Nuclear Waste Management Organization take responsibility for the disposal of intermediate-level waste and non-fuel high-level waste in a deep geological repository. Low-level waste will be disposed of in near-surface disposal facilities.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 12:37:49 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Canadian-integrated-radioactive-waste-management-s?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 852858e7-6a12-4d22-aba6-e791ed133b8e </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA assesses Jordanian plans for SMR deployment]]></title><description><![CDATA[An International Atomic Energy Agency expert mission has concluded that reports compiled by the Jordan Atomic Energy Commission will provide a good basis for a feasibility study into the country&#39;s use of small modular reactors for electricity generation and seawater desalination.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 15:15:28 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-assesses-Jordanian-plans-for-SMR-deployment?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 8eb8beec-5706-4f7e-8396-8dc2b7eaa4aa </guid><title><![CDATA[Bangladesh joins nuclear club as first fuel delivered]]></title><description><![CDATA[Bangladesh&#39;s Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, Russian President Vladimir Putin and International Atomic Energy Agency Director General Rafael Mariano Grossi have taken part in a ceremony to mark the arrival of the first batch of nuclear fuel at the Rooppur nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 10:41:19 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/First-nuclear-fuel-delivered-as-Bangladesh-joins-n?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> db47523d-7cf2-4c44-9ee2-2eaf97af9ee7 </guid><title><![CDATA[Release of second batch of Fukushima water begins]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tokyo Electric Power Company has begun releasing the second batch of treated water at the damaged Fukushima Daiichi nuclear power plant into the ocean. During the latest discharge, expected to last about 17 days, some 7800 cubic metres of treated water will be diluted and released into the sea.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 14:01:42 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Release-of-second-batch-of-Fukushima-water-begins?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 351fbbfd-f8fe-4024-900b-4566fd5f7b1d </guid><title><![CDATA[Australian government funding to 'futureproof' radioisotope supplies]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Australian government has officially outlined plans for a new nuclear medicine manufacturing facility at ANSTO&rsquo;s Lucas Heights campus, replacing an existing facility that is now reaching the end of its operating life. The new facility is expected to be completed by the early to mid-2030s.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 13:48:06 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Australian-government-funding-to-futureproof-radio?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f6d88cdc-e356-40be-9a64-8dfa19d13bca </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA seeks access to all Zaporizhzhia turbine halls on same day]]></title><description><![CDATA[International Atomic Energy Agency experts at the occupied Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant &quot;continue to request&quot; access to all the six turbine halls &quot;one after the other to be able confirm the absence of any materials and equipment&quot; that contravenes the agreed safety and security principles.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 13:33:17 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-seeks-access-to-all-Zaporizhzhia-turbine-hall?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 07195c28-f363-474b-8dba-dad12b0c487c </guid><title><![CDATA[Swedish nuclear: Government moves to change law]]></title><description><![CDATA[A bill to amend Sweden&#39;s legislation on nuclear power has been introduced by the country&#39;s government in parliament. It aims to remove the current law limiting the number of reactors in operation to ten, as well as allowing reactors to be built on new sites, rather than just existing ones.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 11:33:00 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Swedish-nuclear-Government-moves-to-change legisl?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>