<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> cdf1628a-4d0c-426d-888b-eb3e784ab8d3 </guid><title><![CDATA[Polish regulator ready for nuclear programme, IAEA says]]></title><description><![CDATA[Poland&#39;s nuclear regulatory framework is in line with International Atomic Energy Agency safety standards and its regulatory body is competent and prepared for the launch of the country&#39;s nuclear power programme, an IAEA team of experts has concluded.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 13:31:26 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Polish-regulator-ready-for-nuclear-programme,-IAEA?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 760a9b38-386e-4ed6-8c0e-b1d108d73f25 </guid><title><![CDATA[US university builds facility for first-of-a-kind research reactor]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Gayle and Max Dillard Science and Engineering Research Center at Abilene Christian University in Texas will host the Nuclear Energy eXperimental Testing Laboratory and a first-of-a-kind advanced reactor facility.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 15:09:01 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/US-university-builds-facility-for-first-of-a-kind?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 90083726-e56e-4f0f-a266-8e5296b46f3a </guid><title><![CDATA[Private investment sought for Sizewell C project]]></title><description><![CDATA[The UK&#39;s Department for Energy Security and Net Zero has launched a pre-qualification for potential investors as the first stage of an equity raise process for the Sizewell C nuclear power plant project in Suffolk, England.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 11:54:40 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Private-investment-sought-for-Sizewell-C-project?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b8ac10f8-8a62-41a4-a39c-d597bdd347b5 </guid><title><![CDATA[Iran withdraws further IAEA inspector designations]]></title><description><![CDATA[International Atomic Energy Agency Director General Rafael Mariano Grossi has called for the Iranian government to reconsider the decision which affects the planning and conducting of nuclear safeguards verification activities.<br /> ]]>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 13:38:14 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Iran-withdraws-further-IAEA-inspector-designations?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> cf08f08f-146b-439b-a32f-014f20f8190a </guid><title><![CDATA[Long-term safety of Ascó plant reviewed by IAEA]]></title><description><![CDATA[An International Atomic Energy Agency team of experts has completed a follow-up review of long-term operational safety at the Ascó nuclear power plant in Spain. The team reviewed the plant&#39;s response to recommendations and suggestions made during a Safety Aspects of Long-Term Operation mission in 2021.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 15:07:28 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Long-term-safety-of-Asco-plant-reviewed-by-IAEA?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b50a3856-ee6f-451c-a47c-2efcc51b057f </guid><title><![CDATA[Energoatom sends first batch of Ukrainian-mined uranium to Canada]]></title><description><![CDATA[The first batch of uranium mined at the Eastern Mining and Enrichment Plant in Ukraine has been sent to Canada where it will be converted into natural uranium hexafluoride as part of the company&#39;s agreement with Cameco.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 14:50:13 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Energoatom-sends-first-uranium-mined-in-Ukraine-to?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> e7c9f362-96b7-4494-8a52-f243d9f1b6a0 </guid><title><![CDATA[Takahama 2 reactor restarted]]></title><description><![CDATA[Unit 2 of the Takahama nuclear power plant in Japan&#39;s Fukui Prefecture has been restarted after being taken offline more than 12 years ago, Kansai Electric Power Company announced. The 780 MWe (net) pressurised water reactor becomes the 12th Japanese reactor to resume operation.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 11:04:09 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Takahama-2-reactor-restarted?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 240e5ab1-ddc4-4746-a0ca-cedd189e5c82 </guid><title><![CDATA[Bruce 6 re-enters commercial operation]]></title><description><![CDATA[Unit 6 at the site in Ontario was declared commercially operational on 14 September - 39 years to the day after it was first declared in service on 14 September 1984.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 14:26:54 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Bruce-6-re-enters-commercial-operation?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> CB06656b-70ff-457a-8edd-6ead511212f4 </guid><title><![CDATA[Demonstration reactor to be built in Rwanda]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Rwanda Atomic Energy Board has signed an agreement with Dual Fluid to collaborate on the development of a demonstration Dual Fluid nuclear reactor in Rwanda. The demonstration reactor is expected to be operational by 2026.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 16:38:10 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Demonstration-reactor-to-be-built-in-Rwanda?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7c687ff5-009a-4f4f-80d3-1b5f564bcae0 </guid><title><![CDATA[Hyundai builds partnerships in Poland]]></title><description><![CDATA[South Korea&#39;s Hyundai Engineering &amp; Construction has signed a series of agreements with Polish institutions and construction companies in an effort to tap into the country&#39;s nuclear power and infrastructure markets. The company is also establishing an office in Warsaw to create &quot;a bridgehead&quot; for entering other Eastern European markets.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 13:52:44 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Hyundai-builds-partnerships-in-Poland?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> eb64e4e5-685b-41ee-9ff1-ef2b550f6100 </guid><title><![CDATA[Constellation, ComEd in landmark energy-matching deal]]></title><description><![CDATA[The hourly carbon-free energy matching agreement will see ComEd power all its offices and metered facilities with locally produced nuclear energy, in a &#39;first&#39; for an investor-owned US utility. Constellation earlier this year signed a similar hourly energy matching agreement to power a Microsoft data centre.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 13:46:53 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Constellation,-ComEd-in-landmark-energy-matching-d?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>