<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 60e12043-3249-4135-b8ba-9e58df3b81d1 </guid><title><![CDATA[Chugoku, Kansai consider joint development of used fuel store]]></title><description><![CDATA[Japanese utilities Chugoku Electric Power Company and Kansai Electric Power Company plan to jointly investigate the construction of a used fuel interim storage facility in Kaminoseki town in Yamaguchi prefecture. The facility would be built on land Chugoku acquired to build a nuclear power plant, plans for which have stalled.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 12:03:51 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Chugoku,-Kansai-consider-joint-development-of-used?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> d6bd6108-fae6-4b3b-b8d2-d9ab7acfef98 </guid><title><![CDATA[Argentina and India continue to develop nuclear cooperation]]></title><description><![CDATA[A variety of meetings and tours, including to nuclear fuel producer Combustibles Nucleares Argentino and the site of the RA-10 reactor, have taken place within the framework of the second meeting of India and Argentina&#39;s Joint Coordination Committee.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 12:35:34 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Argentina-and-India-continue-to-develop-nuclear-co?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 76b45e51-68a1-4956-b14a-2368f52de001</guid><title><![CDATA[Tender issued for removal of Italian reactor vessel]]></title><description><![CDATA[Societa Gestione Impianti Nucleari SpA, the Italian state-owned company responsible for decommissioning the country&#39;s nuclear power plants, has announced the launch of a tender for the dismantling of the reactor vessel and internals of the Garigliano nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 08:39:27 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Tender-issued-for-removal-of-Italian-reactor-vesse?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 97fc53b1-b6d7-4aa8-82de-d6cb67bed448 </guid><title><![CDATA[TerraPower selects suppliers for Natrium demo project]]></title><description><![CDATA[TerraPower has awarded contracts to four companies to supply services and equipment for the Natrium reactor demonstration project being developed in Kemmerer, Wyoming.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 02 Aug 2023 14:25:26 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/TerraPower-selects-suppliers-for-Natrium-demo-proj?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 07ddd621-89c2-4bc5-918c-36ec6380fddd </guid><title><![CDATA[Fuel flexibility gives MMR range of power outputs]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ultra Safe Nuclear Corporation announced that a technology breakthrough in its patented Fully Ceramic Microencapsulated fuel allows a fuel geometry that results in both higher power and increased safety, enabling its Micro-Modular Reactor to produce three times more power.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 02 Aug 2023 13:36:24 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Fuel-flexibility-gives-MMR-range-of-power-outputs?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 35d88e06-5bfd-4339-9d3f-1c29654f5906 </guid><title><![CDATA[UK competition watchdog looks at Cameco-Westinghouse deal]]></title><description><![CDATA[The UK&#39;s Competition and Markets Authority has invited comments on the proposed Cameco and Brookfield Renewable Partners acquisition of Westinghouse Electric Company as it considers whether the deal &quot;may be expected to result in a substantial lessening of competition&quot; in the United Kingdom.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 02 Aug 2023 14:13:52 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/UK-competition-watchdog-looks-at-Cameco-Westinghou?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 6018508e-b242-44ff-a429-b9d633c97ca4 </guid><title><![CDATA[South Africa's Necsa and Russia's TVEL sign nuclear fuel MoU]]></title><description><![CDATA[The South African Nuclear Energy Corporation and Russia&#39;s TVEL have signed a memorandum of understanding to cooperate in the manufacture of nuclear fuel and its components.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 02 Aug 2023 11:51:42 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Russia-and-South-Africa-sign-MoU-on-nuclear-fuel?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b3e0230e-acd3-46f6-a05e-f4facdea8574 </guid><title><![CDATA[Pakistan formalises Chashma 5 approval]]></title><description><![CDATA[Pakistan&#39;s Executive Committee of the National Economic Council has formally given its approval to the project to build unit 5 of the Chashma nuclear power plant, two weeks after Pakistan&#39;s Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif took part in a ground-breaking ceremony for the reactor.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 22:15:31 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Pakistan-formalises-Chashma-5-approval?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 37c3761d-ac1f-4371-910a-8c930006ce29</guid><title><![CDATA[UK government urged to firm up nuclear plans by MPs]]></title><description><![CDATA[The UK government must develop a comprehensive, detailed and specific strategy for meeting its ambition of having 24 GWe of nuclear capacity in place by 2050, the House of Commons&nbsp;Science, Innovation and Technology Committee has stated.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 15:07:52 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Committee-calls-on-UK-government-to-firm-up-nuclea?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f30f897e-3826-4a56-9fdc-1a6b5d6afbc7 </guid><title><![CDATA[First part of Idaho SMR licence application submitted]]></title><description><![CDATA[CFPP LLC has applied to the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission for a Limited Work Authorisation (LWA) to begin early construction activities for the proposed Carbon Free Power Plant on a site at the Idaho National Laboratory. Early-scope construction is expected to begin in mid-2025, with a view to commercial operation of the first NuScale power module at the site by the end of 2029.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 15:04:56 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/First-part-of-Idaho-SMR-licence-application-submit?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f7821866-8b6b-4788-8d2c-354c16a8c559 </guid><title><![CDATA[A guide: Uranium in Niger]]></title><description><![CDATA[Current events in Niger mean world attention is turning to the West African uranium-producing country. Here is an overview of Niger&#39;s uranium sector.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 14:25:10 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/A-guide-Uranium-in-Niger?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>