<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> e03a77a3-b0ae-4702-b3ef-57875b617ed6</guid><title><![CDATA[Japan starts discharging treated water into the sea]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tokyo Electric Power Company announced it has begun releasing treated water currently stored at the damaged Fukushima Daiichi nuclear power plant into the ocean. The operation - expected to take up to 30 years to complete - is being closely monitored by the International Atomic Energy Agency.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 11:12:26 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Japan-starts-discharging-treated-water-into-the-se?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> eb5fba7a-18bd-46ba-a530-e428f1311894 </guid><title><![CDATA[UK funding to ensure Ukrainian nuclear fuel supplies]]></title><description><![CDATA[The UK government has announced it will provide a GBP192 million (USD243 million) loan guarantee to enable UK-headquartered Urenco to supply Energoatom, Ukraine&#39;s national nuclear company, with uranium enrichment services. The UK government also agreed a Memorandum of Understanding committing support to Ukraine&#39;s energy sector and green energy future.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 12:20:58 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/UK-funding-to-ensure-Ukrainian-nuclear-fuel-suppli?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a543b997-97c4-49cd-ac51-2c18de48e239 </guid><title><![CDATA[Groundwater extraction begins at Zaporizhzhia]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant has started pumping water from a new groundwater well and plans to build more at the site as part of efforts to ensure sufficient cooling for its six reactors after the destruction of Ukraine&#39;s Kakhovka dam in early June.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 14:44:19 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Groundwater-extraction-begins-at-Zaporizhzhia?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 4bbe6fe8-47b9-422f-a1f5-6cc4347c8bc1 </guid><title><![CDATA[Second Leningrad unit defuelled]]></title><description><![CDATA[Defuelling of the second of two shut-down RBMK reactors at the Leningrad nuclear power plant in Russia has now been completed, an important step in the process to decommission the units.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 14:59:32 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Second-Leningrad-unit-defuelled?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> e810fa4d-3814-442c-83b1-6a05b5800614 </guid><title><![CDATA[First loading campaign complete at Krško dry storage facility]]></title><description><![CDATA[Holtec International has completed its first used fuel loading campaign at a newly commissioned dry storage facility at the Slovenian nuclear power plant earlier than expected. Sixteen casks holding a total of 592 used fuel rods have now been placed in the facility.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 12:13:44 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/First-loading-campaign-complete-at-Krsko-dry-stora?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> faf42571-aa55-4844-8eb1-f17dea8047fc </guid><title><![CDATA[Preparations begin for Fukushima water discharge]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Japanese government has requested Tokyo Electric Power Company begin preparations for the release of treated water currently stored at the damaged Fukushima Daiichi nuclear power plant into the ocean. The first treated water is set to be discharged on or after 24 August.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 13:31:36 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Preparations-begin-for-Fukushima-water-discharge?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 85311ae5-0067-452d-b4ee-01988d677a6a </guid><title><![CDATA[PEJ seeks siting decision for Pomeranian plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[Polskie Elektrownie Jądrowe has submitted an application to the head of the Pomeranian Voivodeship for issuing a location decision for Poland&#39;s first nuclear power plant, to be built in the Choczewo municipality in the province of Pomerania.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 14:26:26 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/PEJ-seeks-siting-decision-for-Pomeranian-plant?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7f16772e-5e51-498c-8527-47471161a134 </guid><title><![CDATA[NexGen's Rook I proceeds to provincial public review]]></title><description><![CDATA[NexGen Energy has completed the Provincial Environmental Assessment technical review process and submission of the Final Provincial Environmental Impact Statement for its flagship Rook I project to the Saskatchewan Ministry of Environment.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 15:09:34 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/NexGen-s-Rook-I-proceeds-to-provincial-public-revi?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> dacc914b-8a95-44a6-9ea2-ffa65ca6a25c </guid><title><![CDATA[Microreactor company looks to INL for fuel fabrication site]]></title><description><![CDATA[Microreactor technology company NANO Nuclear Energy Inc has begun the due diligence for locating a nuclear fuel fabrication capability at Idaho National Laboratory, which it says could begin production as soon as 2027.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 14:19:23 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Microreactor-company-looks-to-INL-for-fuel-fabrica?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 73822fa5-e2d4-41e6-9a20-b02bd5310131 </guid><title><![CDATA[Supply chain must expand to meet new build plans, report warns]]></title><description><![CDATA[The expansion of the nuclear power sector at the speed and scale required to meet net-zero, energy security and sustainable development targets will necessitate sustained and coordinated investment in the global nuclear supply chain, according to World Nuclear Association.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 15:48:37 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Supply-chain-must-expand-to-meet-new-build-plans,?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b94c38c3-cd8d-4332-aa74-1521e9ea64be </guid><title><![CDATA[Federal funds announced for Saskatchewan SMR project]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Canadian government has approved CAD74 million (USD55 million) of federal funding for small modular reactor development in Saskatchewan. The funding - including over CAD24 million from the proceeds of Canada&#39;s pollution pricing system - will support work to advance the project led by utility SaskPower.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 14:22:24 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Federal-funds-announced-for-Saskatchewan-SMR-proje?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>