<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 9efd5b14-ed76-47ca-b6e6-f6732efe144a</guid><title><![CDATA[Orano to expand capacity of French enrichment plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[The board of directors of Orano has approved an investment of some EUR1.7 billion (USD1.8 billion) to raise the production capacity of the Georges Besse II uranium enrichment plant at the Tricastin site in southern France by more than 30%.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 12:56:21 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Orano-to-expand-capacity-of-French-enrichment-plan?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 28f598db-2ad3-4801-bef6-e737c71e5f10 </guid><title><![CDATA[Nuclear companies sign up for space technology missions]]></title><description><![CDATA[With nuclear technology set to underpin new developments in space travel, NASA has awarded Ultra Safe Nuclear Corporation a contract to manufacture and test fuel and develop the design of a nuclear thermal propulsion engine for near-term missions. Separately, Space Nuclear Power Corporation has partnered with Lockheed Martin Corporation and BWX Technologies for the US Space Force/Air Force&#39;s JETSON nuclear electric propulsion demonstration project, while Framatome has announced the creation of a new brand, Framatome Space.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Nuclear-companies-sign-up-for-space-technology-mis?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 19e9c8b7-4726-4c1a-9109-59bac1306cd1 </guid><title><![CDATA[Ukraine brings in new pre-licensing assessment for nuclear projects]]></title><description><![CDATA[The large increase in proposed new nuclear energy projects has led the State Nuclear Regulatory Inspectorate of Ukraine to establish a pre-licensing system based on the approach used by the Canadian Nuclear Safety Commission.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 13:39:40 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Ukraine-brings-in-pre-licensing-assessment-for-nuc?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> d953b8a8-1f5a-42c3-90e5-0d0513cf900d </guid><title><![CDATA[Westinghouse signs Bulgaria supplier MoUs]]></title><description><![CDATA[A series of memorandums of understanding have been signed by Westinghouse Electric Company with suppliers in Bulgaria for the proposed new units at the Kozloduy nuclear power plant and other potential projects.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 14:57:09 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Westinghouse-signs-Bulgaria-supplier-MoUs?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ee4eb5d0-1aa0-4f76-8231-69827de0d91a </guid><title><![CDATA[European Council agrees stance on electricity market reform]]></title><description><![CDATA[Following months of negotiations, the European Council has reached an agreement on a proposal to amend the EU&#39;s electricity market design, agreeing to include existing nuclear plants in the reform. The agreement could result in France dropping a scheme forcing state-controlled utility EDF to sell a portion of its nuclear energy production to competitors below market-level prices.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 12:25:42 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/European-Council-agrees-stance-on-electricity-mark?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> fa1bf55a-fea4-4612-a60c-0f5bd334e7fc </guid><title><![CDATA[ITER director general promises 'realistic' project timeline]]></title><description><![CDATA[International Thermonuclear Experimental Reactor Director General Pietro Barabaschi has outlined the progress made, and issues faced, by the multinational project as the process of drawing up a revised schedule takes place.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 12:34:43 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/ITER-director-general-promises-realistic-project?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 12a73899-c537-4376-80aa-1aeaee226792 </guid><title><![CDATA[CNL, ITM join up to produce rare medical isotope]]></title><description><![CDATA[Germany-based radiopharmaceutical biotech company ITM Isotope Technologies Munich SE and Canadian Nuclear Laboratories have launched Actineer, a joint venture for the industrial-scale production of actinium-225.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 15:05:06 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/CNL,-ITM-join-up-to-produce-rare-medical-radioisot?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ec12433b-68f1-4efe-b85e-b39a35f2d3d2 </guid><title><![CDATA[Podcast: World Nuclear Symposium 2023 special report]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>核燃料报告、融资、招聘、工厂寿命优化和净零核启动都是在伦敦举行的行业全球聚会上举行的高级别小组讨论的总结。</p> ]]>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 08:46:58 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Podcast-World-Nuclear-Symposium-2023-special-repor?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7df67505-9018-4823-a932-7f4485ced438 </guid><title><![CDATA[Contract to decommission historic US reactor re-awarded]]></title><description><![CDATA[Aptim-Amentum Alaska Decommissioning (A3D) has been awarded a six-year, USD95.5 million contract by the US Army Corps of Engineers to decommission and dismantle the SM-1A reactor in Alaska. The contract had earlier been given to Westinghouse, but A3D contested that decision.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 14:42:09 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Contract-to-decommission-US-prototype-reactor-re-a?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 804d181b-5553-49b1-900f-f3466892e80a </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA reviews Italy's management of radioactive waste]]></title><description><![CDATA[Italy is committed to addressing the challenges of safely managing its radioactive waste, an International Atomic Energy Agency team of experts has concluded. The review identified areas for additional efforts.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 14:54:48 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-reviews-Italy-s-management-of-radioactive-was?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 5677181e-c5f5-454a-a459-ef511c9efe33 </guid><title><![CDATA[Bruce Power explores technology options for nuclear expansion]]></title><description><![CDATA[Bruce Power announced it is launching an Expression of Interest process to &quot;further understand nuclear technologies that could help meet growing demand for clean electricity and advance decarbonisation efforts in Ontario&quot;. In July, the provincial government said it was starting pre-development work to build up to 4800 MWe of new nuclear capacity at Bruce Power&#39;s existing site.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 11:31:41 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Bruce-Power-explores-technology-options-for-nuclea?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>