<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 1e62a743-2278-45d8-8b3a-ab58eb526cc0 </guid><title><![CDATA[Oklo selected for Alaska airbase microreactor]]></title><description><![CDATA[The US Department of the Air Force, in partnership with the Defense Logistics Agency Energy, has selected Oklo Inc to site, design, construct, own and operate a microreactor facility to deliver electricity and steam at the Eielson Air Force Base in Alaska.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Sep 2023 12:35:23 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Oklo-selected-for-Alaska-airbase-microreactor?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 13962547-79d8-4e89-a650-2e29d9b10b71</guid><title><![CDATA[Fourth new reactor shows record pace of production, says Rosatom]]></title><description><![CDATA[The 340-tonne reactor vessel for the second unit at Kursk II is being shipped by AEM-Technology JSC, marking what Russia&#39;s nuclear corporation Rosatom says is a record for annual reactor production.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Sep 2023 13:11:52 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Four-new-reactors-in-year-is-a-record,-says-Rosato?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 05128755-9afb-4ee0-801e-9efce2ba7230 </guid><title><![CDATA[Robot navigates Dounreay evaporator cell]]></title><description><![CDATA[Spot, a robotic quadruped, has completed a trial at the Dounreay site in Scotland, UK, where it successfully navigated an evaporator cell in the Fuel Cycle Area that has been shut off for 25 years.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Sep 2023 14:54:08 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Robot-navigates-Dounreay-evaporator-cell?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 665731d4-b490-4a65-b8bb-6236b16c915a </guid><title><![CDATA[What to do with the UK's civil plutonium?]]></title><description><![CDATA[The UK&#39;s 140-tonne stockpile of civil plutonium could be used as fuel for thermal reactors or combined with the country&#39;s 100,000-tonne supply of depleted, natural and low-enriched uranium to fuel new fast reactors - or disposed of as waste in a future geological disposal facility -&nbsp;says a new report from The University of Manchester&#39;s Dalton Nuclear Institute exploring the options.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Sep 2023 13:38:43 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/What-to-do-with-the-UK-s-civil-plutonium-stockpile?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 333e6c5c-f704-4b25-abe5-c2999570fa68 </guid><title><![CDATA[Cameco revises 2023 Canadian production forecast]]></title><description><![CDATA[In what it describes as an &quot;unplanned event&quot;, the company has revised downwards this year&#39;s expected production for its Canadian uranium mining operations, citing equipment reliability issues at Cigar Lake and continued uncertainty over planned production at Key Lake as it ramps up after a lengthy period in care and maintenance.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Sep 2023 14:18:45 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Cameco-revises-2023-Canadian-production-forecast?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 509d7274-a2ab-4f1d-afd6-1534a02df26b </guid><title><![CDATA[Studsvik, GNS collaborate on waste technology]]></title><description><![CDATA[Swedish nuclear technical services provider Studsvik and German radioactive waste specialist GNS Gesellschaft für Nuklear-Service mbH have formed a strategic and exclusive cooperation to implement Studsvik&#39;s inDRUM technology for the German market. inDRUM is a patented technology for the treatment of problematic wastes, such as legacy wastes in aging drums.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Sep 2023 13:29:32 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Studsvik,-GNS-collaborate-on-waste-technology?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 25444ca3-1755-4e0d-9a20-b5a53e34ca02 </guid><title><![CDATA[BWXT announces HALEU contract]]></title><description><![CDATA[BWX Technologies, Inc is to process thousands of kilograms of US government-owned scrap material containing enriched uranium to produce high-assay low enriched uranium - or HALEU - feedstock for fuel for advanced nuclear reactors.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 15:45:34 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/BWXT-announces-HALEU-contract?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 8a98f5a6-d335-44dd-a74d-14644f29ef82 </guid><title><![CDATA[Grossi stresses importance of IAEA presence at Zaporizhzhia]]></title><description><![CDATA[International Atomic Energy Agency Director General Rafael Mariano Grossi says that the arrival of its experts at Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant a year ago was &quot;crucial&quot; and their presence continues to be of &quot;paramount importance&quot;.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Sep 2023 10:43:40 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Grossi-stresses-importance-of-IAEA-presence-at-Zap?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ebf97e87-e0bf-42da-a872-31a31142f22f </guid><title><![CDATA[Kazakh people to decide on nuclear plant construction]]></title><description><![CDATA[Kazakhstan is to hold a referendum on the construction of a nuclear power plant in the country, President Kassym-Jomart Tokayev announced during a state-of-the-nation address. The date of the vote has yet to be determined.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 14:30:11 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Kazakh-people-to-decide-on-nuclear-plant-construct?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 58f171ad-42ca-4aef-98b4-9ce8a33305de </guid><title><![CDATA[Walking robot tested in Finnish repository]]></title><description><![CDATA[A four-legged robot designed for autonomous operation in challenging environments has been put through its paces at a depth of more than 400 metres in the tunnels of the Onkalo underground used nuclear fuel repository near Olkiluoto, Finland.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 31 Aug 2023 15:33:02 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Walking-robot-tested-in-Finnish-repository?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 54e28ba5-07e8-453f-b803-44dc7aea4071 </guid><title><![CDATA[Peninsula unveils revised strategy for Lance]]></title><description><![CDATA[Peninsula Energy says it expects to commence uranium production at its flagship uranium project in Wyoming at the end of 2024 under a newly released revised Life-of-Mine plan which features a new on-site recovery plant.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 14:27:14 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Peninsula-unveils-revised-strategy-for-Lance?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>