<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> d81fbe7d-63c4-4681-96d4-b22f44ceba17 </guid><title><![CDATA[Fuel loading begins at Vogtle 4]]></title><description><![CDATA[The process of loading the 157 fuel assemblies into the core of the second AP1000 reactor at the site is pivotal for the reactor, which has a projected in-service date of late this year or early in 2024.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 13:52:07 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Fuel-loading-begins-at-Vogtle-4?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 21bafb65-bcdb-41f8-bb56-33c6bc274427 </guid><title><![CDATA[NRC completes Hermes environmental review]]></title><description><![CDATA[The US Nuclear Regulatory Commission has completed its Final Environmental Impact Statement on Kairos Power&#39;s application for a construction permit for the Hermes demonstration molten salt reactor in Oak Ridge, Tennessee. Based on their review, NRC staff have recommended that the permit should be issued.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 11:37:05 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/NRC-completes-Hermes-environmental-review?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 20997ca5-4682-419f-bba9-366dd3f89276 </guid><title><![CDATA[Eskom looks to November restart for Koeberg 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[South African utility Eskom has announced that unit 1 at its Koeberg nuclear power plant, which has been undergoing a long-term outage for maintenance and steam generator replacement, is now expected to return to service on 3 November. The start of similar work at Koeberg 2 has been postponed to 7 November to ensure that both units are not off line at the same time.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 15:15:33 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Eskom-looks-to-November-restart-for-Koeberg-1?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 99bdce9c-50ee-4deb-8b0c-194276e5dc71 </guid><title><![CDATA[Poland launches search for new repository site]]></title><description><![CDATA[Poland&#39;s Ministry of Climate and Environment is seeking municipalities interested in participating in the process of selecting a site for a new surface repository for low and intermediate-level short-lived radioactive waste. The country&#39;s existing national repository for such waste has been in operation since 1961.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 16:28:26 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Poland-launches-search-for-new-repository-site?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 75826c22-9cd4-4e43-aa09-90ead57676d0 </guid><title><![CDATA[Nuclear is 'bedrock' of Duke's energy roadmap]]></title><description><![CDATA[<strong>更新：杜克能源卡罗莱纳州和杜克能源进步公司建议延长现有核电站的使用寿命，并在 2035 年之前建造两座新的小型模块化反应堆，为北卡罗来纳州和南卡罗来纳州提供最审慎的能源组合。北卡罗来纳州一座即将退役的燃煤电厂被指定用于第一个 SMR。]]>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 12:15:59 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Nuclear-is-bedrock-of-Duke-s-energy-roadmap?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 1ce6ae6c-0e61-4747-8db0-cf50489893a6 </guid><title><![CDATA[Approval sought for second large Polish nuclear power plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[PGE PAK Energia Jądrowa has submitted an application to Poland&#39;s Ministry of Climate for a decision-in-principle on the construction of a nuclear power plant consisting of at least two Korean-supplied APR1400 reactors in the Patnów-Konin region of Wielkopolska province in central Poland.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 12:54:06 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Approval-sought-for-second-large-Polish-nuclear-po?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f8efafee-e5c7-4240-b497-fe94c15fc3ce </guid><title><![CDATA[Kazakhstan regions to hold public hearings on nuclear plans]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Ministry of Energy has issued an update on progress towards the construction of Kazakhstan&#39;s first nuclear power plant, confirming the selection of Ulken in the Zhambyl district of Almaty region as the most suitable area for the plant for which four potential suppliers have been shortlisted.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 15:16:19 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Kazakhstan-regions-to-hold-public-hearings-on-nucl?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7570d23c-fa0d-42a8-800b-1e5751d3911e </guid><title><![CDATA[US regulator OKs SMR emergency preparedness rule]]></title><description><![CDATA[The US Nuclear Regulatory Commission has directed its staff to issue a final rule and associated regulatory guide that applies risk-informed, performance-based emergency preparedness requirements to small modular reactors&nbsp; and other new technologies.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 14:24:37 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/US-regulator-OKs-SMR-emergency-preparedness-rule?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 530412c3-c00f-4e5e-af32-6d6a5778f8dd </guid><title><![CDATA[Waste retrieval begins at Sellafield silo]]></title><description><![CDATA[The first waste has been removed from the Pile Fuel Cladding Silo, one of the oldest waste stores and one of the highest hazard facilities on the UK&#39;s Sellafield site.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 13:22:54 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Waste-retrieval-begins-at-Sellafield-silo?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> d67d80b5-ccab-4d88-820e-8cdc139cb511 </guid><title><![CDATA[Construction of second Russian deconversion plant progresses]]></title><description><![CDATA[The installation of equipment has begun at TVEL&#39;s JSC Electrochemical Plant in Zelenogorsk in Russia&#39;s Krasnoyarsk Region for W2-ECP, the country&#39;s second plant for the processing of depleted uranium hexafluoride. The plant is part of a long-term project to manage and make use of depleted uranium stocks in Russia.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 14:56:52 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Construction-of-second-Russian-deconversion-plant?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> c8468c21-08bc-4130-a921-51a51ebf933d </guid><title><![CDATA[Gorleben mine to be backfilled]]></title><description><![CDATA[A contract has been awarded for the backfilling of the former salt mine in Gorleben, Lower Saxony - previously considered a possible site for geological disposal of Germany&#39;s high-level radioactive waste.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 10:56:23 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Gorleben-mine-to-be-backfilled?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>