<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> d3a171f9-a38c-41c0-9529-13ed4fb61020 </guid><title><![CDATA[Drones put into use at Sellafield site]]></title><description><![CDATA[Drone pilots have successfully completed two flight firsts on the UK&#39;s Sellafield site which are expected to lead the way to increased safety of employees during decommissioning. Sellafield has now become the first UK nuclear site to employ a drone equipped with a radiation monitor.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 04 Aug 2023 10:18:48 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Drones-put-into-use-at-Sellafield-site?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> e37cde37-5e9d-428f-a20a-1ed7df62cfd4 </guid><title><![CDATA[Reactor vessel arrives for Tianwan 7]]></title><description><![CDATA[The reactor vessel for unit 7 of Tianwan nuclear power plant in Jiangsu province, China, has arrived at the site after a two month journey by sea from Russia.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 04 Aug 2023 10:54:09 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Reactor-vessel-arrives-for-Tianwan-7?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 58f946d6-c00d-4817-96ff-52889f5cd161 </guid><title><![CDATA[India eyes SMRs but focuses on large reactors]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Indian government is exploring options for small modular reactors, but large-size plants are still the mainstay of the country&#39;s plans to expand its nuclear generating capacity, Minister of State Jitendra Singh has told the country&#39;s parliament.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 13:59:36 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/India-eyes-SMRs-but-focuses-on-large-reactors?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> cacef9eb-8b7f-4f74-b127-579d47b4b041 </guid><title><![CDATA[Uranium results reflect market improvements]]></title><description><![CDATA[Cameco and Kazatomprom have increased their sales and revenue guidance for 2023 upwards as market fundamentals continue to improve.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 15:38:19 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Uranium-results-reflect-market-improvements?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 60e12043-3249-4135-b8ba-9e58df3b81d1 </guid><title><![CDATA[Chugoku, Kansai consider joint development of used fuel store]]></title><description><![CDATA[Japanese utilities Chugoku Electric Power Company and Kansai Electric Power Company plan to jointly investigate the construction of a used fuel interim storage facility in Kaminoseki town in Yamaguchi prefecture. The facility would be built on land Chugoku acquired to build a nuclear power plant, plans for which have stalled.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 12:03:51 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Chugoku,-Kansai-consider-joint-development-of-used?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> d6bd6108-fae6-4b3b-b8d2-d9ab7acfef98 </guid><title><![CDATA[Argentina and India continue to develop nuclear cooperation]]></title><description><![CDATA[A variety of meetings and tours, including to nuclear fuel producer Combustibles Nucleares Argentino and the site of the RA-10 reactor, have taken place within the framework of the second meeting of India and Argentina&#39;s Joint Coordination Committee.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 12:35:34 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Argentina-and-India-continue-to-develop-nuclear-co?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 23aba5c8-65ef-4b11-b1ee-56349adc9704 </guid><title><![CDATA[Nuclear medicine project in Kyrgyzstan making progress]]></title><description><![CDATA[Kyrgyzstan&#39;s Ministry of Health and Rosatom are working together on a new nuclear medicine diagnostic centre at the National Centre for Oncology and Haematology in Bishkek, with the latest stage being the delivery of a technetium-99m GT-4K generator.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 14:39:39 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Nuclear-medicine-project-in-Kyrgyzstan-making-prog?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 76b45e51-68a1-4956-b14a-2368f52de001</guid><title><![CDATA[Tender issued for removal of Italian reactor vessel]]></title><description><![CDATA[Societa Gestione Impianti Nucleari SpA, the Italian state-owned company responsible for decommissioning the country&#39;s nuclear power plants, has announced the launch of a tender for the dismantling of the reactor vessel and internals of the Garigliano nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 08:39:27 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Tender-issued-for-removal-of-Italian-reactor-vesse?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 97fc53b1-b6d7-4aa8-82de-d6cb67bed448 </guid><title><![CDATA[TerraPower selects suppliers for Natrium demo project]]></title><description><![CDATA[TerraPower has awarded contracts to four companies to supply services and equipment for the Natrium reactor demonstration project being developed in Kemmerer, Wyoming.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 02 Aug 2023 14:25:26 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/TerraPower-selects-suppliers-for-Natrium-demo-proj?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 07ddd621-89c2-4bc5-918c-36ec6380fddd </guid><title><![CDATA[Fuel flexibility gives MMR range of power outputs]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ultra Safe Nuclear Corporation announced that a technology breakthrough in its patented Fully Ceramic Microencapsulated fuel allows a fuel geometry that results in both higher power and increased safety, enabling its Micro-Modular Reactor to produce three times more power.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 02 Aug 2023 13:36:24 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Fuel-flexibility-gives-MMR-range-of-power-outputs?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 35d88e06-5bfd-4339-9d3f-1c29654f5906 </guid><title><![CDATA[UK competition watchdog looks at Cameco-Westinghouse deal]]></title><description><![CDATA[The UK&#39;s Competition and Markets Authority has invited comments on the proposed Cameco and Brookfield Renewable Partners acquisition of Westinghouse Electric Company as it considers whether the deal &quot;may be expected to result in a substantial lessening of competition&quot; in the United Kingdom.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 02 Aug 2023 14:13:52 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/UK-competition-watchdog-looks-at-Cameco-Westinghou?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>