<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 8f75c501-5a08-46d6-9f52-5221d6be73a8 </guid><title><![CDATA[European Commission to create SMR Industrial Alliance]]></title><description><![CDATA[In response to calls from the nuclear industry, research community and nuclear safety regulators, the European Commission will establish an Industrial Alliance dedicated to small modular reactors in early 2024, European Commissioner for Energy Kadri Simson has announced.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 12:30:14 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/European-Commission-to-create-SMR-Industrial-Allia?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 2065e281-05ed-4df3-a224-2f07b981e29a </guid><title><![CDATA[Orano two-tier dry storage system in loading 'first']]></title><description><![CDATA[Orano has loaded the first used fuel into the upper modules of the two-tiered NUHOMS MATRIX horizontal dry storage system at the Wolf Creek nuclear power plant in Kansas.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 16:04:25 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Orano-two-tier-dry-storage-system-in-loading-first?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 8f2b1488-e6a5-4d72-86be-6a9f95344430 </guid><title><![CDATA[China completes ITER magnet support components]]></title><description><![CDATA[A ceremony was held on 3 November to mark the final shipment from China of assemblies for the magnet supporting system of the International Thermonuclear Experimental Reactor fusion machine under construction in Cadarache, southern France.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 15:02:40 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/China-completes-ITER-magnet-support-components?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 774c6b9d-a4fd-495f-a0dd-75c038c03254 </guid><title><![CDATA[Inaugural study completed for potential Canadian ISL project]]></title><description><![CDATA[The first in-situ leach field test programme carried out by Denison on Tthe Heldeth Túé uranium deposit at Waterbury Lake achieved its planned objectives and has confirmed expectations that the deposit can be amenable to mining using in-situ techniques.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 14:34:46 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Inaugural-study-completed-for-potential-Canadian-I?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 83a3ff15-c91d-4d68-8c50-4259b14af88f </guid><title><![CDATA[Containment shell in place for Chinese SMR]]></title><description><![CDATA[The steel containment dome was successfully hoisted into place at the ACP100 small modular reactor demonstration project at the Changjiang site on China&#39;s island province of Hainan, China National Nuclear Corporation has announced.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 12:29:18 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Containment-shell-in-place-for-Chinese-SMR?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a449f60f-8d9a-431a-b940-caf8b3435076 </guid><title><![CDATA[Planning permission sought for new reactors at Ringhals]]></title><description><![CDATA[Vattenfall is applying to the municipality of Varberg for a detailed plan to enable the construction of new reactors on the Värö Peninsula, to the west of the existing Ringhals nuclear power plant in Sweden. The announcement came as the government launches a review of the permitting process.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 15:04:53 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Planning-permission-sought-for-new-reactors-at-Rin?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> bb429b1f-7411-4bbd-82c3-e7dc42d5feb9 </guid><title><![CDATA[Kazatomprom updates on shipments and plans]]></title><description><![CDATA[Sanctions on the transport of products through Russian territory have not restricted Kazatomprom&#39;s activities, the company said in its quarterly update, and production remains in line with plans. Separately, Kazatomprom&#39;s shareholders have approved a major sale of natural uranium concentrates to China&#39;s State Nuclear Uranium Resource Development Company.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 14:35:49 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Kazatomprom-updates-on-shipments-and-plans?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 996902ad-3288-4631-bce9-床6b7652261 </guid><title><![CDATA[Doosan Enerbility to design used fuel storage system]]></title><description><![CDATA[South Korean engineering firm Doosan Enerbility has signed a contract with Korea Hydro &amp; Nuclear Power to carry out the overall design of a used nuclear fuel dry storage system.&nbsp;]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 15:47:04 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Doosan-Enerbility-to-design-used-fuel-storage-syst?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 33876254-f428-4bf7-b3f9-4fc763b965a1 </guid><title><![CDATA[Staff levels at Zaporizhzhia in spotlight]]></title><description><![CDATA[The International Atomic Energy Agency says it is continuing to monitor the status, training and condition of staff at the nuclear power plant - while the Russian operators say that there are enough staff to maintain it in &quot;self-sufficiency&quot; mode.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 14:56:10 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Staff-levels-at-Zaporizhzhia-remain-in-spotlight?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> d9bf876b-77ef-4cde-828e-5d44e5f98a09 </guid><title><![CDATA[SMR power plant proposed in Norway]]></title><description><![CDATA[Norsk Kjernekraft has submitted a proposal to Norway&#39;s Ministry of Oil and Energy for an assessment into the construction of a power plant based on multiple small modular reactors in the municipalities of Aure and Heim. The company said it marks the first formal step towards the possible construction of the country&#39;s first nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 12:43:17 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/SMR-power-plant-proposed-in-Norway?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 412a60ca-a060-4f28-86c0-1d6433fad9ae </guid><title><![CDATA[Agreements, declarations mark Macron visits to Kazakhstan, Uzbekistan]]></title><description><![CDATA[France and Kazakhstan have pledged cooperation on minerals and the nuclear fuel cycle, while in Uzbekistan there was agreement to raise the level of bilateral relations, during official visits by President Emmanuel Macron this week. The French president was accompanied by a large delegation including representatives from French industry.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 15:03:44 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Agreements,-declarations-mark-Macron-visits-to-Kaz?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>