<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f6e49ed5-7e54-4946-861a-fb52e4959fac </guid><title><![CDATA[Bruce Power to start impact assessment process for Bruce C]]></title><description><![CDATA[Bruce Power has formally notified Canadian regulators of its intent to launch an Impact Assessment for potential new nuclear generation on the Bruce Power site.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 15:08:30 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Bruce-Power-to-start-impact-assessment-process-for?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 64467de1-fc1a-46d9-b572-2e38761d8581 </guid><title><![CDATA[Fuel loading begins at Kakrapar 4]]></title><description><![CDATA[Nuclear Power Corporation of India Ltd started loading the first fuel into the core of the pressurised heavy water reactor unit on 20 October, after receiving permission from India&#39;s Atomic Energy Regulatory Board.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 14:11:17 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Fuel-loading-begins-at-Kakrapar-4?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ccdc7d6a-6d95-4c45-b71e-034071f685aa </guid><title><![CDATA[SMRs would provide economic boost to Ontario, says report]]></title><description><![CDATA[The construction and operation of four small modular reactors by Ontario Power Generation at its Darlington site will contribute about CAD15.3 billion (USD11.2 billion) to Canada&#39;s GDP, including CAD13.7 billion to Ontario&#39;s GDP, according to a report by the Conference Board of Canada. The units will create and sustain 2000 jobs each year in Canada over the next 65 years, it says.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 13:56:58 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/SMRs-would-provide-economic-boost-to-Ontario,-says?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 53a502de-3616-4397-8205-e09f8b17eb99 </guid><title><![CDATA[LED lights developed specifically for nuclear facilities]]></title><description><![CDATA[Whitecroft Lighting has supplied LED lighting to the Hinkley Point C nuclear power plant project in Somerset, UK - its first nuclear energy lighting contract. The company says that through the contract it has developed a new, specialist LED lighting solution for the nuclear energy sector.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 14:48:59 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/LED-lights-developed-specifically-for-nuclear-faci?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 3219ac95-dcdc-4432-bf31-b2de4cf397c1 </guid><title><![CDATA[Safety systems tests at Kursk II]]></title><description><![CDATA[The flushing of the active and passive safety systems with the open reactor are described as a key moment in the pre-start-up checks for the first reactor at Kursk II nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 14:10:00 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Flushing-of-safety-systems-at-Kursk-II?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 9efd5b14-ed76-47ca-b6e6-f6732efe144a</guid><title><![CDATA[Orano to expand capacity of French enrichment plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[The board of directors of Orano has approved an investment of some EUR1.7 billion (USD1.8 billion) to raise the production capacity of the Georges Besse II uranium enrichment plant at the Tricastin site in southern France by more than 30%.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 12:56:21 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Orano-to-expand-capacity-of-French-enrichment-plan?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ec12433b-68f1-4efe-b85e-b39a35f2d3d2 </guid><title><![CDATA[Podcast: World Nuclear Symposium 2023 special report]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>核燃料报告、融资、招聘、工厂寿命优化和净零核启动都是在伦敦举行的行业全球聚会上举行的高级别小组讨论的总结。</p> ]]>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 08:46:58 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Podcast-World-Nuclear-Symposium-2023-special-repor?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 28f598db-2ad3-4801-bef6-e737c71e5f10 </guid><title><![CDATA[Nuclear companies sign up for space technology missions]]></title><description><![CDATA[With nuclear technology set to underpin new developments in space travel, NASA has awarded Ultra Safe Nuclear Corporation a contract to manufacture and test fuel and develop the design of a nuclear thermal propulsion engine for near-term missions. Separately, Space Nuclear Power Corporation has partnered with Lockheed Martin Corporation and BWX Technologies for the US Space Force/Air Force&#39;s JETSON nuclear electric propulsion demonstration project, while Framatome has announced the creation of a new brand, Framatome Space.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Nuclear-companies-sign-up-for-space-technology-mis?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 19e9c8b7-4726-4c1a-9109-59bac1306cd1 </guid><title><![CDATA[Ukraine brings in new pre-licensing assessment for nuclear projects]]></title><description><![CDATA[The large increase in proposed new nuclear energy projects has led the State Nuclear Regulatory Inspectorate of Ukraine to establish a pre-licensing system based on the approach used by the Canadian Nuclear Safety Commission.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 13:39:40 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Ukraine-brings-in-pre-licensing-assessment-for-nuc?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ee4eb5d0-1aa0-4f76-8231-69827de0d91a </guid><title><![CDATA[European Council agrees stance on electricity market reform]]></title><description><![CDATA[Following months of negotiations, the European Council has reached an agreement on a proposal to amend the EU&#39;s electricity market design, agreeing to include existing nuclear plants in the reform. The agreement could result in France dropping a scheme forcing state-controlled utility EDF to sell a portion of its nuclear energy production to competitors below market-level prices.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 12:25:42 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/European-Council-agrees-stance-on-electricity-mark?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> d953b8a8-1f5a-42c3-90e5-0d0513cf900d </guid><title><![CDATA[Westinghouse signs Bulgaria supplier MoUs]]></title><description><![CDATA[A series of memorandums of understanding have been signed by Westinghouse Electric Company with suppliers in Bulgaria for the proposed new units at the Kozloduy nuclear power plant and other potential projects.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 14:57:09 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Westinghouse-signs-Bulgaria-supplier-MoUs?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>