<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 8eb8beec-5706-4f7e-8396-8dc2b7eaa4aa </guid><title><![CDATA[Bangladesh joins nuclear club as first fuel delivered]]></title><description><![CDATA[Bangladesh&#39;s Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, Russian President Vladimir Putin and International Atomic Energy Agency Director General Rafael Mariano Grossi have taken part in a ceremony to mark the arrival of the first batch of nuclear fuel at the Rooppur nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 10:41:19 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/First-nuclear-fuel-delivered-as-Bangladesh-joins-n?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> db47523d-7cf2-4c44-9ee2-2eaf97af9ee7 </guid><title><![CDATA[Release of second batch of Fukushima water begins]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tokyo Electric Power Company has begun releasing the second batch of treated water at the damaged Fukushima Daiichi nuclear power plant into the ocean. During the latest discharge, expected to last about 17 days, some 7800 cubic metres of treated water will be diluted and released into the sea.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 14:01:42 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Release-of-second-batch-of-Fukushima-water-begins?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 351fbbfd-f8fe-4024-900b-4566fd5f7b1d </guid><title><![CDATA[Australian government funding to 'futureproof' radioisotope supplies]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Australian government has officially outlined plans for a new nuclear medicine manufacturing facility at ANSTO&rsquo;s Lucas Heights campus, replacing an existing facility that is now reaching the end of its operating life. The new facility is expected to be completed by the early to mid-2030s.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 13:48:06 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Australian-government-funding-to-futureproof-radio?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f6d88cdc-e356-40be-9a64-8dfa19d13bca </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA seeks access to all Zaporizhzhia turbine halls on same day]]></title><description><![CDATA[International Atomic Energy Agency experts at the occupied Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant &quot;continue to request&quot; access to all the six turbine halls &quot;one after the other to be able confirm the absence of any materials and equipment&quot; that contravenes the agreed safety and security principles.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 13:33:17 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-seeks-access-to-all-Zaporizhzhia-turbine-hall?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 07195c28-f363-474b-8dba-dad12b0c487c </guid><title><![CDATA[Swedish nuclear: Government moves to change law]]></title><description><![CDATA[A bill to amend Sweden&#39;s legislation on nuclear power has been introduced by the country&#39;s government in parliament. It aims to remove the current law limiting the number of reactors in operation to ten, as well as allowing reactors to be built on new sites, rather than just existing ones.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 11:33:00 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Swedish-nuclear-Government-moves-to-change legisl?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> c85ffeef-7bcc-45e3-a803-dd631ec2486b </guid><title><![CDATA[ABS approves Korean SMR power barge design]]></title><description><![CDATA[A design for a floating offshore nuclear power barge from HD Korea Shipbuilding &amp; Offshore Engineering and Kepco Engineering &amp; Construction has received approval in principle from the American Bureau of Shipping.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 13:56:16 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/ABS-approves-Korean-SMR-power-barge-design?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ab5d6d22-2b70-4704-b6e7-eff3bcd258d0 </guid><title><![CDATA[Operations begin at US chloride salt test system]]></title><description><![CDATA[Southern Company, TerraPower and Core Power have started pumped-salt operations in the Integrated Effects Test facility at TerraPower&#39;s laboratory in Everett, Washington. The facility will be used in the development of the Molten Chloride Fast Reactor.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 11:23:24 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Operations-begin-at-US-chloride-salt-test-system?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 9a0d60fa-abd1-4d50-8abd-0c0ecc8f71d8 </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA unveils nuclear security training centre]]></title><description><![CDATA[The International Atomic Energy Agency&#39;s new Nuclear Security Training and Demonstration Centre<em>让参与者了解核材料和其他放射性材料的实物保护，以及涉及核材料和设施的犯罪行为的侦查和应对。]]>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 13:07:07 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-unveils-nuclear-security-training-centre?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 690db276-7e45-4d27-9a53-e4aaaae7e195 </guid><title><![CDATA[Clean-up of Tajik uranium legacy site completed ahead of schedule]]></title><description><![CDATA[Rosatom says that it has completed the work to reclaim the low-grade uranium ore factory and tailings dumps at Taboshar, near the city of Istiklol in western Tajikistan. The company also said Russia and Tajikistan are considering wider cooperation in the nuclear sector.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 14:09:42 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Clean-up-of-Tajik-uranium-legacy-site-completed-ah?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f965674b-09e2-4336-bfdd-943eaa0a5da7 </guid><title><![CDATA[TRIGA fuel supply resumes after 10-year hiatus]]></title><description><![CDATA[The first shipment of research reactor fuel elements under a nine-year contract between the US Department of Energy and TRIGA International has arrived at Pennsylvania State University. Meanwhile, the original developer of the TRIGA research reactor has been awarded a design development services contract in support of a conceptual research reactor design for a new facility at Sandia National Laboratory.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 22:28:56 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/TRIGA-fuel-supply-resumes-after-10-year-hiatus?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 5d540dcc-0214-46c5-b7c8-6b89df98d6f0 </guid><title><![CDATA[US unit cleared to use higher-enriched fuel]]></title><description><![CDATA[Southern Nuclear has announced it has received authorisation from the US Nuclear Regulatory Commission to use advanced nuclear fuel enriched up to 6% uranium-235 at Vogtle unit 2. This is the first time a US commercial reactor has been authorised to use fuel with over 5% enrichment.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 14:50:13 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/US-unit-cleared-to-use-higher-enriched-fuel?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>