<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 8dbf059e-8955-4152-8ce7-4be26fd4891f </guid><title><![CDATA[Innovation is driving nuclear optimism, panel findsar innovation driving optimism, panel finds]]></title><description><![CDATA[Innovation has been, and will continue to be, an essential driver in propelling the nuclear energy sector forward - but the industry must be prepared to embrace innovation in all areas, not just technological innovations. These were the messages from speakers in the high-level closing panel at the International Atomic Energy Agency&#39;s <em>2023 年科学论坛。]]>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 15:49:16 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Innovation-is-driving-nuclear-optimism,-panel-find?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b1380777-a3fb-4a96-92ac-ca4090df63ad </guid><title><![CDATA[IEA sees greater role for nuclear in attaining net-zero by 2050]]></title><description><![CDATA[In an update to its<em>国际能源署于 2021 年发布的净零路线图表示，鉴于最近的政策支持，核电的作用已被向上修改。在更新的净零排放情景中，核发电量到 2050 年将达到 916 GWe，高于 2021 年版本中给出的 812 GWe。]]>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 15:08:06 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IEA-sees-greater-role-for-nuclear-in-attaining-net?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> e5587af1-c10a-4d60-8c03-3f69805853fc </guid><title><![CDATA[Human cost stressed as action planned to tackle delay and denial of shipments]]></title><description><![CDATA[A broader global effort is planned to ensure the smooth transportation of nuclear products, such as those used in vital medical diagnosis and treatment and in food safety, as well as in the nuclear energy sector, delegates at the <em>第 67 届国际原子能机构大会获悉。]]>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 19:01:19 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Human-cost-of-delay-and-denial-of-nuclear-shipment?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 84ae902d-3c5c-4cec-8b5b-92e650d0078d</guid><title><![CDATA[Vessel for third Akkuyu reactor ready to be shipped]]></title><description><![CDATA[The manufacture of the reactor pressure vessel for unit 3 of Turkey&#39;s Akkuyu nuclear power plant has been completed in Russia. This brings the number of RPVs supplied by Russia so far this year to a record five, Russian state nuclear corporation Rosatom noted.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 11:48:07 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Vessel-for-third-Akkuyu-reactor-ready-to-be-shippe?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> cbb2e35a-c215-4c04-bd80-4ed812e0b5bf </guid><title><![CDATA[Tribal council, First Nations take stake in SMR companies]]></title><description><![CDATA[The North Shore Mi&#39;kmaq Tribal Council and its seven First Nation member communities are making financial investments in small modular reactor developers Moltex Energy Canada Inc and ARC Clean Technology Canada Inc under historic equity agreements.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 14:22:50 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Tribal-council,-First-Nations-take-stake-in-SMR-co?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b1f282d3-fd3c-4a9c-b2bf-94034c6a1910 </guid><title><![CDATA[Hot testing starts of second CGN Hualong One unit]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tests that simulate the temperatures and pressures which the reactor systems will be subjected to during normal operation have begun at unit 4 of the Fangchenggang nuclear power plant in China&#39;s Guangxi Autonomous Region. The unit is the second of two demonstration China General Nuclear-designed Hualong One (HPR1000) reactors at the site.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 14:11:24 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Hot-testing-starts-of-second-CGN-Hualong-One-unit?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 6ee51380-2373-4abd-943b-e370382d9341 </guid><title><![CDATA[New Slovak reactor reaches full power]]></title><description><![CDATA[The power output of unit 3 at the Mochovce nuclear power plant in Slovakia has been increased from 90% to 100% as energy start-up tests continue, Slovenské elektrárne announced.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 13:55:59 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/New-Slovak-reactor-reaches-full-power?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 91d96daf-b820-4079-80a7-12b29041f076 </guid><title><![CDATA[More countries set to join Nuward SMR joint early review]]></title><description><![CDATA[The pilot phase of the joint early regulatory review of France&#39;s Nuward small modular reactor design has led to positive lessons for all sides, and three more European regulators are set to join the next phase, a meeting at the <em>第 67 届国际原子能机构大会已获悉。]]>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 11:30:39 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/More-countries-to-join-Nuward-SMR-joint-early-revi?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 718b8bfa-b1c8-4620-98b2-0ec3ddfb4da9 </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA assesses operational safety at Penly plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[The operator of the two-unit Penly nuclear power plant in Normandy, France, has demonstrated a commitment to operational safety, an International Atomic Energy Agency mission has concluded. The team also encouraged the operator, EDF, to continue improvements in areas such as the implementation of maintenance work.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 13:45:33 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-assesses-operational-safety-at-Penly-plant?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 3698e885-6cb2-4d83-9899-c1daabc86204 </guid><title><![CDATA[Grossi stresses positive role of nuclear at IAEA General Conference]]></title><description><![CDATA[Director General Rafael Mariano Grossi opened the <em>第 67 届国际原子能机构大会表示，民意调查显示公众对核能的态度“潮流正在转变”，但各国“仍然需要公开、主动地让利益相关者参与”其核电计划。]]>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 09:29:54 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Grossi-urges-vocal-backing-of-nuclear-as-IAEA-gath?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 006d8ceb-47f0-45fd-ae31-a75d9aab06a8 </guid><title><![CDATA[Outer containment dome in place at Rooppur 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[The installation of the steel structures of the outer containment dome has been completed in record time at unit 2 of the Rooppur nuclear power plant in Bangladesh, Russia&#39;s state nuclear corporation Rosatom announced.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 11:02:36 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Outer-containment-dome-in-place-at-Rooppur-2?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>