<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> cba5d59c-ea31-4eac-8360-cda360627d51 </guid><title><![CDATA[Alaska simplifies microreactor regulations]]></title><description><![CDATA[The US state of Alaska has adopted regulations to streamline the regulatory process for the siting of microreactors. The new regulations, which waive some requirements imposed on larger nuclear facilities, come into effect in August.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 15:00:12 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Alaska-simplifies-microreactor-regulations?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false">爸爸776d8-cc67-42f1-be0c-3a7b4d07fd12 </guid><title><![CDATA[Eleventh Japanese reactor resumes operation]]></title><description><![CDATA[Unit 1 of the Takahama nuclear power plant in Japan&#39;s Fukui Prefecture has been restarted after being taken offline more than 12 years ago. Kansai Electric Power Company plans to return the 780 MWe (net) pressurised water reactor to commercial operation at the end of August.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 13:22:15 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Eleventh-Japanese-reactor-resumes-operation?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a29c53d3-3ef5-458e-84de-c69e1f9cb387 </guid><title><![CDATA[Zimbabwe and Ethiopia sign nuclear energy cooperation agreements with Russia]]></title><description><![CDATA[Two more countries - Zimbabwe and Ethiopia - have signed agreements with Russia to cooperate on the peaceful use of nuclear technology on the sidelines of the <em>俄罗斯-非洲经济和人道主义论坛，已在圣彼得堡举行。]]>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 14:25:54 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Zimbabwe-and-Ethiopia-sign-nuclear-energy-cooperat?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ddaa2262-23b9-42ed-a52f-8f743c9e15dd </guid><title><![CDATA[Westinghouse to expand fuel offerings from UK facility]]></title><description><![CDATA[Westinghouse has been awarded three grants totalling GBP10.5 million (USD13.6 million) from the UK government&#39;s Nuclear Fuel Fund to upgrade and expand the Springfields fuel fabrication facility in Lancashire in northwest England.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 13:33:37 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Westinghouse-to-expand-fuel-offerings-from-UK-faci?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 33dfa9ae-3a2c-47fd-8fd9-944b426a38db</guid><title><![CDATA[British-Japanese partnership for fusion development]]></title><description><![CDATA[UK-based nuclear fusion company Tokamak Energy and Japan&#39;s Sumitomo Corporation have agreed to collaborate on the development, implementation and scaling-up of commercial fusion energy in Japan and worldwide.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 11:31:06 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/British-Japanese-partnership-for-fusion-developmen?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 116d7178-5a18-444c-8a89-8ddbd3daa645</guid><title><![CDATA[Burundi and Russia agreement on nuclear cooperation]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Republic of Burundi and Russia have signed a memorandum of cooperation on peaceful uses of nuclear technology. It was signed as the&nbsp;<em>俄罗斯-非洲经济和人道主义论坛在圣彼得堡举行。]]>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 10:29:26 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Burundi-and-Ethiopia-among-Russia-Africa-nuclear-c?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 56e5ee39-6811-480b-床1-8bbab964e9d6 </guid><title><![CDATA[CNL eyes dramatic increase in Ac-225 production]]></title><description><![CDATA[Canadian Nuclear Laboratories has announced an agreement with the Sylvia Fedoruk Centre for Nuclear Innovation - part of the University of Saskatchewan - that will enable it to increase by more than 30 times its current production of the rare actinium-225 radioisotope.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 14:50:11 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/CNL-eyes-dramatic-increase-in-Ac-225-production?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> c1b8d95e-25a9-48de-9305-34a3d42f53ad</guid><title><![CDATA[Podcast: The prospects for nuclear energy in Africa]]></title><description><![CDATA[The main interview is with Lassina Zerbo, who discusses the current situation, and the emerging future plans, for nuclear energy in Africa. There are also reports on China&#39;s molten salt reactor and the USA&#39;s HALEU fuel supply initiatives.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 14:51:56 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Podcast-The-prospects-for-nuclear-energy-in-Africa?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 226751e2-1999-466b-ba7b-71ed02a48fa8 </guid><title><![CDATA[BWXT to begin work on cislunar nuclear rocket engine and fuel]]></title><description><![CDATA[The USA&#39;s Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency has finalised an agreement with Lockheed Martin to begin work on the fabrication and design of an experimental nuclear thermal rocket and its engine. BWX Technologies, one of Lockheed Martin&#39;s partners in the effort, will develop the nuclear reactor and fabricate the HALEU fuel.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 14:27:21 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/BWXT-to-begin-work-on-DRACO-engine-and-fuel?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 62457a56-1476-4851-b412-86f5efa1d501 </guid><title><![CDATA[Dome hoisted into place on Xudapu 3]]></title><description><![CDATA[The dome has been hoisted into place on the reactor building of Xudapu unit 3 in a single stage process, six months ahead of schedule, with China National Nuclear Corporation describing the project as &quot;a model of global energy cooperation&quot;.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 13:49:17 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Dome-hoisted-into-place-on-Xudapu-3?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> feac4774-feba-40b4-9274-379329aabbdd </guid><title><![CDATA[Framatome EATF completes first cycle in US reactor]]></title><description><![CDATA[A lead assembly of Framatome&#39;s 100% Enhanced Accident Tolerant Fuel has successfully completed its first cycle of operation at a US nuclear power plant. The assembly was inserted into unit 2 of the Calvert Cliffs plant in Maryland during a refueling outage in early 2021.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 11:56:57 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Framatome-EATF-completes-first-cycle-in-US-reactor?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>