<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 185087ec-6732-4bf1-955f-45067ac34459</guid><title><![CDATA[Illinois to lift moratorium on nuclear construction]]></title><description><![CDATA[Governor JB Pritzker has said he will sign a new bill lifting Illinois&#39; ban on the construction of new nuclear reactors, after the state&#39;s lawmakers passed new legislation that will allow the construction of small modular reactors of up to 300 MWe capacity from 2026.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 15:37:32 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Illinois-to-lift-moratorium-on-nuclear-constructio?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 07a97a1c-4f34-47d2-b77f-f861b94deb77 </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA and ICAO enhance cooperation]]></title><description><![CDATA[The International Atomic Energy Agency and the International Civil Aviation Organization have agreed to enhance their cooperation around the transport of radioactive materials by air. In particular, they aim to improve the efficiency and speed of these shipments.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 15:29:27 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-and-ICAO-enhance-cooperation?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 1c392046-1666-40e7-89e2-ef2976efc49f </guid><title><![CDATA[Work starts to permanently secure UK nuclear waste vaults]]></title><description><![CDATA[More than 60 years after disposal of low-level radioactive waste began at the repository site in Cumbria, work has started on the capping and securing of trenches and vaults which are full and ready for permanent closure.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 15:01:51 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/NWS?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 329a0e8a-e9d1-45cb-946e-2911021e98bc </guid><title><![CDATA[Foundation in place for first mega cooling tower at Lianjiang]]></title><description><![CDATA[The foundation for the world&#39;s first nuclear power ultra-large high-level seawater cooling tower has been laid at unit 1 of the Lianjiang plant in China&#39;s Guangdong province, State Power Investment Corp announced.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 14:46:50 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Foundation-in-place-for-first-mega-cooling-tower-a?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 63bda1b6-f305-419a-b2b0-af09cf748d63 </guid><title><![CDATA[Agreement to consider SMR for Norilsk region]]></title><description><![CDATA[Russia&#39;s Rosatom and Norilsk Nickel are to study possible options and sites for a small nuclear power reactor.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 12:05:26 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Agreement-to-consider-SMR-for-Norlisk-region?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 30ee7511-1c22-470f-bba1-0b4bcfa51576 </guid><title><![CDATA[Study to consider SMR deployment at Halden]]></title><description><![CDATA[A new company, Halden Kjernekraft AS, has been founded by Norsk Kjernekraft, Østfold Energi and the municipality of Halden to investigate the construction of a nuclear power plant based on small modular reactors at Halden. A research reactor once operated in Halden, in Norway.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 14:17:23 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Study-to-consider-SMR-deployment-at-Halden?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a0120318-f135-4896-bf74-f78554606ca8 </guid><title><![CDATA[UK regulators consider application of AI in nuclear sector]]></title><description><![CDATA[The UK&#39;s Office for Nuclear Regulation and the Environment Agency have completed a project piloting a nuclear regulatory sandbox process, using artificial intelligence as the test case. This project, which has reported its conclusions, will help inform the development of a regulatory approach to AI.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 15:43:39 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/UK-regulators-consider-application-of-AI-in-nuclea?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 9c2a5c95-4f11-4315-9ffb-a55288410b9a </guid><title><![CDATA[Former US reactor site released for unrestricted use]]></title><description><![CDATA[The US Nuclear Regulatory Commission has released most of the site of the former Zion nuclear power plant in Illinois for unrestricted use, marking the completion of decommissioning at the site. A storage facility for the plant&#39;s used fuel will remain under NRC licence and oversight.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 15:04:56 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Former-US-reactor-site-released-for-unrestricted-u?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> c8c9c95f-6216-4dec-a234-d28528ad7d98</guid><title><![CDATA[Hungary says Romania to continue to allow nuclear fuel transport]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hungarian Foreign Minister&nbsp;Peter Szijjarto has said after talks in Romania that the country will continue to allow the transport of Russian nuclear fuel to Hungary&#39;s Paks nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 15:02:37 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Hungary-says-Romania-to-continue-to-allow-nuclear?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a8da1625-01e6-4fc8-a3c4-478520eccf40 </guid><title><![CDATA[UK and USA team up on fusion development]]></title><description><![CDATA[The US Department of Energy and the UK Department for Energy Security and Net Zero have announced a new strategic partnership to accelerate the demonstration and commercialisation of fusion energy.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 15:55:58 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/UK-and-USA-team-up-on-fusion-development?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ba0f291f-f3a0-4e07-a7ba-05906a08aed5 </guid><title><![CDATA[Idaho SMR project terminated]]></title><description><![CDATA[Utah Associated Municipal Power Systems and NuScale Power Corporation have mutually agreed to terminate the Carbon Free Power Project. The project to build NuScale small modular reactor units at a site near Idaho Falls had been pencilled in for operation by 2029.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 07:59:01 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Idaho-SMR-project-terminated?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>