<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 83a3ff15-c91d-4d68-8c50-4259b14af88f </guid><title><![CDATA[Containment shell in place for Chinese SMR]]></title><description><![CDATA[The steel containment dome was successfully hoisted into place at the ACP100 small modular reactor demonstration project at the Changjiang site on China&#39;s island province of Hainan, China National Nuclear Corporation has announced.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 12:29:18 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Containment-shell-in-place-for-Chinese-SMR?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a449f60f-8d9a-431a-b940-caf8b3435076 </guid><title><![CDATA[Planning permission sought for new reactors at Ringhals]]></title><description><![CDATA[Vattenfall is applying to the municipality of Varberg for a detailed plan to enable the construction of new reactors on the Värö Peninsula, to the west of the existing Ringhals nuclear power plant in Sweden. The announcement came as the government launches a review of the permitting process.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 15:04:53 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Planning-permission-sought-for-new-reactors-at-Rin?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> bb429b1f-7411-4bbd-82c3-e7dc42d5feb9 </guid><title><![CDATA[Kazatomprom updates on shipments and plans]]></title><description><![CDATA[Sanctions on the transport of products through Russian territory have not restricted Kazatomprom&#39;s activities, the company said in its quarterly update, and production remains in line with plans. Separately, Kazatomprom&#39;s shareholders have approved a major sale of natural uranium concentrates to China&#39;s State Nuclear Uranium Resource Development Company.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 14:35:49 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Kazatomprom-updates-on-shipments-and-plans?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 996902ad-3288-4631-bce9-床6b7652261 </guid><title><![CDATA[Doosan Enerbility to design used fuel storage system]]></title><description><![CDATA[South Korean engineering firm Doosan Enerbility has signed a contract with Korea Hydro &amp; Nuclear Power to carry out the overall design of a used nuclear fuel dry storage system.&nbsp;]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 15:47:04 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Doosan-Enerbility-to-design-used-fuel-storage-syst?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 33876254-f428-4bf7-b3f9-4fc763b965a1 </guid><title><![CDATA[Staff levels at Zaporizhzhia in spotlight]]></title><description><![CDATA[The International Atomic Energy Agency says it is continuing to monitor the status, training and condition of staff at the nuclear power plant - while the Russian operators say that there are enough staff to maintain it in &quot;self-sufficiency&quot; mode.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 14:56:10 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Staff-levels-at-Zaporizhzhia-remain-in-spotlight?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> d9bf876b-77ef-4cde-828e-5d44e5f98a09 </guid><title><![CDATA[SMR power plant proposed in Norway]]></title><description><![CDATA[Norsk Kjernekraft has submitted a proposal to Norway&#39;s Ministry of Oil and Energy for an assessment into the construction of a power plant based on multiple small modular reactors in the municipalities of Aure and Heim. The company said it marks the first formal step towards the possible construction of the country&#39;s first nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 12:43:17 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/SMR-power-plant-proposed-in-Norway?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 412a60ca-a060-4f28-86c0-1d6433fad9ae </guid><title><![CDATA[Agreements, declarations mark Macron visits to Kazakhstan, Uzbekistan]]></title><description><![CDATA[France and Kazakhstan have pledged cooperation on minerals and the nuclear fuel cycle, while in Uzbekistan there was agreement to raise the level of bilateral relations, during official visits by President Emmanuel Macron this week. The French president was accompanied by a large delegation including representatives from French industry.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 15:03:44 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Agreements,-declarations-mark-Macron-visits-to-Kaz?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b2ccfe8b-f41d-415e-9454-450b0e80f4e4 </guid><title><![CDATA[Partners to study hydrogen production using Rolls-Royce SMR]]></title><description><![CDATA[ULC-Energy of the Netherlands has signed an agreement with Denmark&#39;s Topsoe and the UK&#39;s Rolls-Royce SMR to jointly investigate the production of hydrogen using Topsoe&#39;s Solid Oxide Electrolysis Cell technology with both electricity and heat produced by a Rolls-Royce SMR nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 16:03:09 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Partners-to-study-hydrogen-production-using-Rolls?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> af19ce95-65a2-4f3d-88de-1d9d5a4ce6e3 </guid><title><![CDATA[Cold testing completed at first Zhangzhou unit]]></title><description><![CDATA[Cold hydrostatic testing has been completed at unit 1 of the Zhangzhou nuclear power plant in China&#39;s Fujian province, the first of two Hualong One reactors under construction at the site. The tests mark the first time the reactor systems are operated together with the auxiliary systems.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 15:05:22 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Cold-testing-completed-at-first-Zhangzhou-unit?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 86c0425a-df46-4b36-91c9-fb2de5ae30a7 </guid><title><![CDATA[Czech SMR development roadmap approved]]></title><description><![CDATA[Plans for small modular reactors in the Czech Republic are to be included in <em>在由部长领导的工作组审查其潜力后<em>，捷克共和国制定了国家能源政策和空间发展政策，</em>概述了许多潜在地点，并呼吁在 2030 年代上半叶开始建设。]]>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 15:01:06 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Czech?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> d692b351-f79e-4778-98ad-0dd315fc1684 </guid><title><![CDATA[South Ukraine unit 1 gets 10-year extension]]></title><description><![CDATA[The State Nuclear Regulatory Inspectorate of Ukraine has said unit 1 of the South Ukraine nuclear power plant can operate safely for a further 10 years.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 12:20:26 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/South-Ukrainian-plant-s-unit-1-gets-10-year-extens?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>