<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 4bfcd14a-14be-4756-a0e6-43f9f4ed0a7f </guid><title><![CDATA[Construction of first unit at Lianjiang under way]]></title><description><![CDATA[The first safety-related concrete has been poured for the nuclear island of unit 1 at the Lianjiang nuclear power plant in China&#39;s Guangdong province. It is the first of two CAP1000 units planned as the initial phase of the plant, which will eventually house six such reactors.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 11:26:50 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Construction-of-first-unit-at-Lianjiang-under-way?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 6a63919d-7fc6-4487-a468-81e4a3469199 </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA raises nuclear growth projections]]></title><description><![CDATA[As the International Atomic Energy Agency raises its projections for global nuclear generating capacity in 2050, speakers at the Agency&#39;s <em>第二届气候变化和核电作用国际会议表示，核工业需要克服许多挑战才能充分发挥其潜力。]]>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 14:47:30 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-raises-nuclear-growth-projections?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 23acce67-b93a-4218-80d3-22e41a3a3a6a </guid><title><![CDATA[Vogtle 4 start-up moved to 2024]]></title><description><![CDATA[The in-service date for the second AP1000 plant at the site near Waynesboro, Georgia, has been revised after a motor fault was discovered in a reactor coolant pump. Meanwhile, Georgia Power has agreed to pay the plant&#39;s co-owner Oglethorpe Power Corporation USD308 million in settlement of an ongoing dispute.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 14:26:07 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Vogtle-4-start-up-moved-to-2024?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 0cbd913b-e121-460c-b017-86f3fbd2f56d </guid><title><![CDATA[Argentina and Brazil sign MoU on radioisotopes and research]]></title><description><![CDATA[Argentina&#39;s National Atomic Energy Commission and Brazil&#39;s&nbsp;National Nuclear Energy Commission have signed a memorandum of understanding which they say will strengthen their on-going collaboration in the area of peaceful uses of nuclear technology relating to their planned new research reactors.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 13:19:28 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Argentina-and-Brazil-sign-MoU-on-radioisotopes?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 2467f366-cc4f-4019-ad17-fe6caedb7b81 </guid><title><![CDATA[US computing infrastructure provider announces SMR plans]]></title><description><![CDATA[Standard Power plans to develop small modular reactor facilities in Ohio and Pennsylvania using NuScale&#39;s reactor technology to power nearby data centres.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 15:34:55 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/US-computing-infrastructure-provider-announces-SMR?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7ebb4a4f-e24a-4110-b5e1-79c9cc6a590e</guid><title><![CDATA[Holtec applies to restart shuttered Palisades plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Palisades plant in Michigan could become the first successfully restarted nuclear power plant in the USA following Holtec International&#39;s submission of a filing with the Nuclear Regulatory Commission to formally begin the process of seeking reauthorisation of power operations at the plant, which was shut down in May 2022.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 15:29:21 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Holtec-applies-to-restart-shuttered-Palisades-plan?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 84bb1da8-3eae-44fd-b10c-ae7313e83bb9 </guid><title><![CDATA[Egypt's first nuclear unit has core catcher installed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Officials from Egypt&#39;s Nuclear Power Plants Authority and Russia&#39;s Rosatom have held a ceremony to mark the installation of the core catcher in the first unit at the El Dabaa nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 13:22:57 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Egypt-s-first-nuclear-unit-has-core-catcher-instal?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 4d232096-8086-4621-8348-4c73c4397ebb </guid><title><![CDATA[Edison eyes SMR deployment in Italy]]></title><description><![CDATA[Leading Italian energy player Edison has announced its ambition to construct two nuclear power plants based on EDF&#39;s small modular reactor technology between 2030 and 2040, if the conditions are created for the return of nuclear energy to Italy.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 13:07:55 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Edison-eyes-SMR-deployment-in-Italy?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 598624a8-d849-4666-a787-91acc0d1ae82 </guid><title><![CDATA[Canadian integrated radioactive waste management strategy accepted]]></title><description><![CDATA[The strategy for radioactive waste other than used nuclear fuel will see Canada&#39;s Nuclear Waste Management Organization take responsibility for the disposal of intermediate-level waste and non-fuel high-level waste in a deep geological repository. Low-level waste will be disposed of in near-surface disposal facilities.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 12:37:49 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Canadian-integrated-radioactive-waste-management-s?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 852858e7-6a12-4d22-aba6-e791ed133b8e </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA assesses Jordanian plans for SMR deployment]]></title><description><![CDATA[An International Atomic Energy Agency expert mission has concluded that reports compiled by the Jordan Atomic Energy Commission will provide a good basis for a feasibility study into the country&#39;s use of small modular reactors for electricity generation and seawater desalination.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 15:15:28 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-assesses-Jordanian-plans-for-SMR-deployment?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 8eb8beec-5706-4f7e-8396-8dc2b7eaa4aa </guid><title><![CDATA[Bangladesh joins nuclear club as first fuel delivered]]></title><description><![CDATA[Bangladesh&#39;s Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, Russian President Vladimir Putin and International Atomic Energy Agency Director General Rafael Mariano Grossi have taken part in a ceremony to mark the arrival of the first batch of nuclear fuel at the Rooppur nuclear power plant.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 10:41:19 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/First-nuclear-fuel-delivered-as-Bangladesh-joins-n?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>