<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 8438c92a-0c89-4559-9e5d-3eca96cb9527 </guid><title><![CDATA[Indian reactor reaches first criticality]]></title><description><![CDATA[The controlled self-sustaining fission chain reaction began at Kakrapar unit 4 in the early hours of 17 December, Nuclear Power Corporation of India Ltd has announced. The Indian government has also confirmed it has completed the land purchase for the construction of two 700 MWe reactors at Chutka.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Dec 2023 15:13:35 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Indian-reactor-reaches-first-criticality?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 1add004a-d59f-4926-ab95-5716dee501c2 </guid><title><![CDATA[No centralised logistics centre for German repository]]></title><description><![CDATA[Plans for a centralised low- and intermediate-level radioactive waste logistics centre at the former Würgassen nuclear power plant have been shelved by the German Federal Environment Ministry due to &quot;too many legal and planning risks&quot;. The waste would then have been sent to the Konrad repository for disposal.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Dec 2023 14:30:12 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/No-centralised-logistics-centre-for-German-reposit?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 4270137b-5d60-4e60-b4ad-2ac0afd3372c </guid><title><![CDATA[Ukraine and Westinghouse sign agreement for Khmelnitsky AP1000]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ukraine&#39;s Energy Minister Herman Halushchenko, Energoatom President Petro Kotin and Westinghouse CEO Patrick Fragman have signed an agreement on the purchase of equipment for what is to become&nbsp;Khmelnitsky nuclear power plant unit 5.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Dec 2023 13:23:55 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Ukraine-and-Westinghouse-sign-agreement-for-Khmeln?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 6f75ec61-9fae-4ddb-b5e9-75e345b5f14b </guid><title><![CDATA[SMuRFs to help in nuclear decommissioning]]></title><description><![CDATA[Teams of autonomous robots known as SMuRFs (for Symbiotic Multi-Robot Fleet) could assist in the future decommissioning of nuclear power plants, according to researchers from four British universities.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Dec 2023 15:38:27 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/SMuRFs-to-help-in-nuclear-decommissioning?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> bcc4dad2-738e-4e93-8295-633bcd67096d </guid><title><![CDATA[Podcast: Making nuclear power plants look great]]></title><description><![CDATA[We hear from an award-winning architect on the benefits of designing nuclear power plants that make people feel good ... plus Sweden&#39;s nuclear expansion features in the news round-up.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 10:44:45 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Podcast-Building-beautiful-nuclear-power-plants?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 21ad3f3f-f23a-479c-b873-953b8928623b </guid><title><![CDATA[Hinkley Point C landmark dome lift - in pictures]]></title><description><![CDATA[Construction of the first EPR unit at the Hinkley Point C nuclear power plant in Somerset, UK, has reached a major milestone with the installation of the reactor building dome.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Dec 2023 10:37:36 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Hinkley-Point-C-landmark-dome-lift-in-pictures?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> fd59cdd8-8c33-46d2-9583-aa47f64a363e </guid><title><![CDATA[Bannerman granted mining licence for Etango]]></title><description><![CDATA[Namibia&#39;s Ministry of Mines and Energy has granted Bannerman Energy a mining licence for its Etango uranium project. Initial contracts have been awarded for the Etango early works programme.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Dec 2023 15:26:20 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Bannerman-granted-mining-licence-for-Etango?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 6929f139-e9ef-490c-b575-f5db4e1e5c64 </guid><title><![CDATA[Agreement reached on EU electricity market reform]]></title><description><![CDATA[The European Council and Parliament have reached a provisional agreement to reform the European Union&#39;s electricity market design. The agreement now needs to be endorsed and formally adopted by both institutions.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Dec 2023 14:41:52 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Agreement-reached-on-EU-electricity-market-reform?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ca8273c3-9bc9-4658-a7d6-8df0d0f91198 </guid><title><![CDATA[New Brunswick releases energy strategy with SMR focus]]></title><description><![CDATA[The strategy outlining how the province aims to transition to clean energy calls for the addition of 600 MWe of capacity at the Point Lepreau Nuclear Generation Station by 2035, doubling New Brunswick&#39;s current nuclear capacity.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Dec 2023 15:45:15 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/New-Brunswick-releases-energy-strategy-with-SMR-fo?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> bab6af67-4f57-4626-ab8a-b5561f8731cf </guid><title><![CDATA[MOX fuel with minor actinides produced for BN-800 reactor]]></title><description><![CDATA[The first three fuel assemblies with uranium-plutonium mixed oxide fuel containing transuranic elements americium-241 and neptunium-237 have been produced by Rosatom&#39;s Mining and Chemical Combine.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Dec 2023 13:27:36 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Mixed-oxide-fuel-with-minor-actinides-produced-for?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 43fc9280-1bb3-4a48-871a-df4103fc4522 </guid><title><![CDATA[Feasibility study for Korean reactors at Borssele]]></title><description><![CDATA[Korea Hydro &amp; Nuclear Power has been contracted to conduct a feasibility study into the construction of two Korean-supplied reactors at the Borssele nuclear power plant site in the Netherlands. The contract comes as the South Korean and Dutch governments sign a memorandum of understanding to cooperate on nuclear energy.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Dec 2023 14:13:51 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Feasibility-study-for-Korean-reactors-at-Borssele?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>