<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ee4eb5d0-1aa0-4f76-8231-69827de0d91a </guid><title><![CDATA[European Council agrees stance on electricity market reform]]></title><description><![CDATA[Following months of negotiations, the European Council has reached an agreement on a proposal to amend the EU&#39;s electricity market design, agreeing to include existing nuclear plants in the reform. The agreement could result in France dropping a scheme forcing state-controlled utility EDF to sell a portion of its nuclear energy production to competitors below market-level prices.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 12:25:42 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/European-Council-agrees-stance-on-electricity-mark?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 804d181b-5553-49b1-900f-f3466892e80a </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA reviews Italy's management of radioactive waste]]></title><description><![CDATA[Italy is committed to addressing the challenges of safely managing its radioactive waste, an International Atomic Energy Agency team of experts has concluded. The review identified areas for additional efforts.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 14:54:48 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-reviews-Italy-s-management-of-radioactive-was?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 5677181e-c5f5-454a-a459-ef511c9efe33 </guid><title><![CDATA[Bruce Power explores technology options for nuclear expansion]]></title><description><![CDATA[Bruce Power announced it is launching an Expression of Interest process to &quot;further understand nuclear technologies that could help meet growing demand for clean electricity and advance decarbonisation efforts in Ontario&quot;. In July, the provincial government said it was starting pre-development work to build up to 4800 MWe of new nuclear capacity at Bruce Power&#39;s existing site.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 11:31:41 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Bruce-Power-explores-technology-options-for-nuclea?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b1e98979-f38f-4891-9577-4358715faddd </guid><title><![CDATA[Newcleo, Nuclear AMRC collaborate on LFR fabrication]]></title><description><![CDATA[Newcleo has signed a memorandum of understanding with the UK&#39;s Nuclear Advanced Manufacturing Research Centre to collaborate on manufacturability, supply chain and development studies for its small modular lead-cooled fast reactor technology.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 13:45:17 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Newcleo,-Nuclear-AMRC-collaborate-on-LFR-fabricati?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 975e92d9-82ac-4d58-8952-66a6148ffd3e </guid><title><![CDATA[Reactor vessel in place at Tianwan 7]]></title><description><![CDATA[The reactor vessel has been installed at unit 7 of the Tianwan nuclear power plant in China&#39;s Jiangsu province. Russia is constructing two VVER-1200 reactors as units 7 and 8 of the plant.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 14:34:13 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Reactor-vessel-in-place-at-Tianwan-7?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> dde597fa-c79b-4a73-916b-808854ccba1a </guid><title><![CDATA[Russia and Belarus radioactive waste disposal agreement]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><font><font>俄罗斯TVEL和白俄罗斯放射性废物管理组织签署了一项长期合作协议，内容涉及</font>白俄罗斯放射性废物最终隔离的基础设施建设和开发，以及近地表废物操作培训人员处置设施。</font></p> ]]>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 11:21:25 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/TVEL-and-Belarus-sign-radwaste-disposal-agreement?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 86cf4af2-d451-453d-80fb-36fef03e3ad7 </guid><title><![CDATA[Canadian provinces announce collaborative coal phase-out plans]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Government of Canada has announced nearly CAD20 million (USD15 million) in federal funding to support the provinces of Nova Scotia and New Brunswick to help enable a phase-out of coal-fired electricity generation by 2030. The funding includes CAD7 million to support pre-development work for a small modular reactor at Point Lepreau in New Brunswick.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 14:59:15 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Canadian-provinces-announce-collaborative-coal-pha?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 6d682682-e0c6-43c2-8095-d65848bb8b8a </guid><title><![CDATA[Study to evaluate Lightbridge Fuel use in Candu reactors]]></title><description><![CDATA[Advanced nuclear fuel technology company Lightbridge Corporation is collaborating with Romania&#39;s Institutul de Cercetări Nucleare Pitești to perform an engineering study to assess the compatibility and suitability of its Lightbridge Fuel for use in Candu pressurised heavy water reactors.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 13:46:23 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Study-to-evaluate-Lightbridge-Fuel-use-in-Candu-re?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ec12433b-68f1-4efe-b85e-b39a35f2d3d2 </guid><title><![CDATA[Podcast: World Nuclear Symposium 2023 special report]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>核燃料报告、融资、招聘、工厂寿命优化和净零核发射都是在伦敦举行的行业全球聚会上举行的高级别小组讨论的总结。</p> ]]>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 08:46:58 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Podcast-World-Nuclear-Symposium-2023-special-repor?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 97ad47dc-b7b0-46b9-88d1-fa633af6fdd9 </guid><title><![CDATA[MBIR reactor block roof completed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Construction of Russia&#39;s MBIR multipurpose sodium-cooled fast neutron research reactor has reached a fresh milestone with the installation of the building&#39;s dome.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 13:42:51 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/MBIR-reactor-block-roof-completed?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 5c31e559-3fcf-4370-ac78-1c8ce850ac38 </guid><title><![CDATA[Mochovce 3 successfully completes commissioning process]]></title><description><![CDATA[Slovenské elektrárne has announced that the new Mochovce 3 unit has successfully completed a 144-hour demonstration run at full reactor power - and been welcomed into their nuclear fleet.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 12:10:58 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Energy-start-up-of-Mochovce-3-completed?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>