<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b1f88d60-91c3-4052-946f-40b20e4d0080 </guid><title><![CDATA[Core module installed at Chinese SMR]]></title><description><![CDATA[The core module has been installed within the reactor building of the ACP100 small modular reactor demonstration project, China National Nuclear Corporation has announced.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 10 Aug 2023 11:06:35 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Core-module-installed-at-Chinese-SMR?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 94a9db98-3508-413e-9c1a-e54d1e594a61 </guid><title><![CDATA[General Fusion announces new fusion demo machine]]></title><description><![CDATA[Canadian private fusion developer General Fusion has announced plans for a new Magnetised Target Fusion machine designed to achieve fusion conditions of over 100 million degrees Celsius by 2025, and progress toward scientific breakeven by 2026.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 10 Aug 2023 15:00:20 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/General-Fusion-announces-new-fusion-demo-machine?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 467ef2e8-13f8-474b-b370-2fe371ca1437 </guid><title><![CDATA[Rooppur fuel passes inspection as onsite work progresses]]></title><description><![CDATA[The first fuel for Rooppur 1&#39;s initial load has been formally accepted by the Bangladesh Atomic Energy Commission after an inspection at the Novosibirsk Chemical Concentrates Plant in Russia. Meanwhile, installation of the unit&#39;s eight heat exchangers has been completed at the plant site in Bangladesh.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 10 Aug 2023 14:37:29 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Rooppur-fuel-passes-inspection-as-onsite-work-prog?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 385566a5-f6e7-4c20-b8ce-fc22e38c3a0e </guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA conducts first mission on disused sources]]></title><description><![CDATA[The International Atomic Energy Agency has carried out the inaugural mission, in Thailand, of the Disused Sealed Radioactive Sources Technical Centre peer review service. This new service aims to enlarge the global pool of resources and support for countries in the sustainable management of these sources.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 10 Aug 2023 13:33:18 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-conducts-first-mission-on-disused-sources?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a3e7f629-e598-4b3c-ad94-2b6b0f20cbe5 </guid><title><![CDATA[Swedish regulator proposes framework for expansion of nuclear]]></title><description><![CDATA[Sweden&#39;s Radiation Safety Authority has presented its final report to the government on how the regulatory framework for nuclear power should be developed and what other measures may be needed for nuclear power to be expanded in the country.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 11:56:38 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Swedish-regulator-proposes-framework-for-expansion?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> efb84472-a350-436b-9d52-05cf8501181c </guid><title><![CDATA[Bruce 6 restarted following refurbishment]]></title><description><![CDATA[Unit 6 of the Bruce nuclear power plant in Ontario has resumed operation following its Major Component Replacement project, Bruce Power announced. The Candu reactor, which was taken offline for the work in January 2020, is scheduled to resume commercial operation later this year.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 14:23:08 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Bruce-6-restarted-following-refurbishment?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 25a12e1d-d76f-498b-82e1-ae2ed71a00e4 </guid><title><![CDATA[First Light Fusion and Tractebel Machine 4 development agreement]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tractebel and First Light Fusion have signed a framework agreement for the development of the Machine 4 project designed to demonstrate net energy gain.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 14:43:21 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/First-Light-Fusion-and-Tractebel Machine-4-develop?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 0690cb58-b7e3-4b04-a77a-1644b36b8a82 </guid><title><![CDATA[Foundation slab completed at Akkuyu 4]]></title><description><![CDATA[The pouring of concrete for the foundation slab of the reactor building at Turkey&#39;s Akkuyu unit 4 has been finished - it involved 17,500 cubic metres of concrete mix.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:29:43 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Foundation-slab-concreting-completed-at-Akkuyu-4?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> c4188e30-5c44-4ad5-87ac-3d737e52615f </guid><title><![CDATA[Groups call on US regulator to finalise advanced reactor rules]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Breakthrough Institute, Clean Air Task Force, ClearPath, Nuclear Innovation Alliance, and Third Way say delays in finalising a regulatory rulemaking on risk-informed emergency preparedness has already caused significant regulatory uncertainty for developers.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 15:01:38 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Groups-call-on-US-regulator-to-finalise-advanced-r?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a02c27b2-5d2a-41b3-bd4b-ec28d1b61588 </guid><title><![CDATA[Marvel Fusion and CSU partner on US laser facility]]></title><description><![CDATA[German laser fusion developer Marvel Fusion and the USA&#39;s Colorado State University are to create a public-private partnership for the construction of a USD150 million high-power laser and fusion research facility on the CSU Foothills Campus.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 13:20:57 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Marvel-Fusion-and-CSU-partner-on-US-laser-facility?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 22bfaaa2-bf41-4f3f-b4b3-41e7e3e32062 </guid><title><![CDATA[LLNL researchers achieve fusion ignition for second time]]></title><description><![CDATA[Researchers at the National Ignition Facility at the Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory in California have reportedly achieved net energy gain in a fusion reaction for the second time. The milestone was first achieved last December.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 14:23:01 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/LLNL-researchers-achieve-fusion-ignition-for-secon?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>