<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 21ad3f3f-f23a-479c-b873-953b8928623b </guid><title><![CDATA[Hinkley Point C landmark dome lift - in pictures]]></title><description><![CDATA[Construction of the first EPR unit at the Hinkley Point C nuclear power plant in Somerset, UK, has reached a major milestone with the installation of the reactor building dome.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Dec 2023 10:37:36 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Hinkley-Point-C-landmark-dome-lift-in-pictures?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 6929f139-e9ef-490c-b575-f5db4e1e5c64 </guid><title><![CDATA[Agreement reached on EU electricity market reform]]></title><description><![CDATA[The European Council and Parliament have reached a provisional agreement to reform the European Union&#39;s electricity market design. The agreement now needs to be endorsed and formally adopted by both institutions.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Dec 2023 14:41:52 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Agreement-reached-on-EU-electricity-market-reform?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> ca8273c3-9bc9-4658-a7d6-8df0d0f91198 </guid><title><![CDATA[New Brunswick releases energy strategy with SMR focus]]></title><description><![CDATA[The strategy outlining how the province aims to transition to clean energy calls for the addition of 600 MWe of capacity at the Point Lepreau Nuclear Generation Station by 2035, doubling New Brunswick&#39;s current nuclear capacity.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Dec 2023 15:45:15 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/New-Brunswick-releases-energy-strategy-with-SMR-fo?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> bab6af67-4f57-4626-ab8a-b5561f8731cf </guid><title><![CDATA[MOX fuel with minor actinides produced for BN-800 reactor]]></title><description><![CDATA[The first three fuel assemblies with uranium-plutonium mixed oxide fuel containing transuranic elements americium-241 and neptunium-237 have been produced by Rosatom&#39;s Mining and Chemical Combine.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Dec 2023 13:27:36 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Mixed-oxide-fuel-with-minor-actinides-produced-for?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 43fc9280-1bb3-4a48-871a-df4103fc4522 </guid><title><![CDATA[Feasibility study for Korean reactors at Borssele]]></title><description><![CDATA[Korea Hydro &amp; Nuclear Power has been contracted to conduct a feasibility study into the construction of two Korean-supplied reactors at the Borssele nuclear power plant site in the Netherlands. The contract comes as the South Korean and Dutch governments sign a memorandum of understanding to cooperate on nuclear energy.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Dec 2023 14:13:51 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Feasibility-study-for-Korean-reactors-at-Borssele?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> bcc4dad2-738e-4e93-8295-633bcd67096d </guid><title><![CDATA[Podcast: Making nuclear power plants look great]]></title><description><![CDATA[We hear from an award-winning architect on the benefits of designing nuclear power plants that make people feel good ... plus Sweden&#39;s nuclear expansion features in the news round-up.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 10:44:45 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Podcast-Building-beautiful-nuclear-power-plants?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> eadf62dc-6ce4-423a-9393-fabd6244cd86 </guid><title><![CDATA[Urenco to expand capacity at Dutch facility]]></title><description><![CDATA[Uranium enrichment services provider Urenco has announced plans to increase capacity at its plant in Almelo in the Netherlands by 15% in response to new commitments from customers.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Dec 2023 15:45:23 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Urenco-to-expand-capacity-at-Dutch-facility?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7e8cf296-e60c-44a4-9cfb-9006b764aad1 </guid><title><![CDATA[Indian regulator gives go-ahead for reactor start-up]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Atomic Energy Regulatory Board has given its permission for the first approach to criticality of unit 4 at the Kakrapar nuclear power plant. The unit is the second of two Indian-designed 700 MWe pressurised heavy water reactors being built at the site in Gujarat. &nbsp;]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Dec 2023 13:20:21 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Indian-regulator-gives-go-ahead-for-reactor-start?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 6e983b5c-606a-457a-9e06-63bc83f253c8 </guid><title><![CDATA[COP28 agreement recognises nuclear's role]]></title><description><![CDATA[The 28th UN Climate Change Conference of the Parties has ended in Dubai with a Global Stocktake - unanimously agreed by all parties - calling for a transitioning away from fossil fuels and an acceleration of zero- and low-emission technologies, including nuclear.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Dec 2023 15:13:04 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/COP28-agreement-recognises-nuclear-s-role?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 70daddd0-a992-4452-8b0d-3c1541665280 </guid><title><![CDATA[Final accord reached on Belgian reactor operations]]></title><description><![CDATA[A final agreement has been signed between the Belgian government and French utility Engie to extend the operation of the Tihange 3 and Doel 4 nuclear power reactors by 10 years and on all obligations related to radioactive waste.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Dec 2023 12:37:17 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Final-accord-reached-on-Belgian-reactor-operations?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 4cc2b2da-cb80-4e8c-bd1b-4adb51c08935 </guid><title><![CDATA[NRC approves Hermes construction permit]]></title><description><![CDATA[Kairos Power will build the Hermes molten salt-cooled demonstration reactor at the Heritage Center Industrial Park in Oak Ridge, Tennessee. It is the first non-water cooled reactor to be approved for construction in the USA in more than 50 years.<br /> ]]>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:24:05 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/NRC-approves-Hermes-construction-permit?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>