<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 448d4fcd-d9f9-4a49-ab65-77fe24055e6a</guid><title><![CDATA[BWXT to evaluate microreactor deployment in Wyoming]]></title><description><![CDATA[BWX Technologies Inc has been contracted by the Wyoming Energy Authority to assess the viability of deploying microreactors in the state. The value of the contract was not disclosed.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 11:13:45 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/BWXT-to-evaluate-microreactor-deployment-in-Wyomin?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> f03abb47-41b7-4032-833a-8bc9d0279ea0 </guid><title><![CDATA[Palisades restart takes 'giant step' with Holtec-Wolverine deal]]></title><description><![CDATA[A long-term power purchase agreement signed between Holtec Palisades Energy and the non-profit Wolverine Power Cooperative is described as a &quot;significant milestone&quot; towards restarting the 800 MW Palisades nuclear power plant in the USA.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 11:08:13 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Palisades-restart-takes-giant-step-with-Holtec-Wol?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> c86d971d-8226-4142-b7a9-67a0434947d9 </guid><title><![CDATA[UK nuclear workforce at highest for 20 years, says NIA]]></title><description><![CDATA[The number of people employed in the civil nuclear sector in the UK has risen to 77,413, according to the Nuclear Industry Association&#39;s annual Jobs Map survey.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 14:55:50 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/UK-nuclear-workforce-at-highest-for-20-years,-says?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> b96e5b2d-5191-4171-834f-c874abb28e9d </guid><title><![CDATA[Clean-up work begins at Uzbek legacy uranium sites]]></title><description><![CDATA[Remediation work at legacy uranium mining sites in Uzbekistan is under way, bolstered by a EUR9 million (USD11 million) grant from the Environmental Remediation Account for Central Asia set up on the initiative of the European Union and managed by the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 15:26:56 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Clean-up-work-begins-at-Uzbek-legacy-uranium-sites?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 9b4b88a2-a7d0-4026-8a2b-145a36f7651e</guid><title><![CDATA[IAEA to run out of money within weeks, Grossi warns]]></title><description><![CDATA[Member states of the International Atomic Energy Agency now owe more than EUR200 million (USD214 million), and Director General Rafael Mariano Grossi has warned that unless payments are made, then in a month&#39;s time &quot;we will run out of money ... I will not be able to pay salaries or for the lights ... we will grind to a halt&quot;.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 12:22:48 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/IAEA-to-run-out-of-money-within-weeks,-Grossi-warn?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> a075b64c-cb65-41a0-9167-27df027f8a8a </guid><title><![CDATA[ENEC, OSGE cooperate to advance SMRs in Europe]]></title><description><![CDATA[A memorandum of understanding between Polish company Orlen Synthos Green Energy and the Emirates Nuclear Energy Corporation will see the parties work together to support decarbonisation efforts in Poland and Europe through investments in in small modular reactors.<br /> ]]>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 14:34:50 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/ENEC,-OSGE-cooperate-to-advance-SMRs?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> e86b073a-0e55-4d9a-89dd-94c160ff5aea </guid><title><![CDATA[Westinghouse and Energoatom agree AP300 SMR cooperation]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ukraine&#39;s Energoatom and the US firm Westinghouse have signed a memorandum of understanding relating to the development and deployment of AP300 small modular reactors in Ukraine.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 13:45:19 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Westinghouse-and-Energoatom-agree-AP300-SMR-cooper?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> FC781CBF-5E15-4070-8456-670A3E7C7691</guid><title><![CDATA[Seaborg power barge considered for use in Indonesia]]></title><description><![CDATA[Indonesian power company Pertamina NRE has signed a memorandum of understanding with Denmark&#39;s Seaborg to investigate the deployment of Seaborg&#39;s compact molten salt reactor Power Barge in Indonesia.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 11:44:26 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Seaborg-power-barge-considered-for-use-in-Indonesi?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 7ffeb997-2358-4920-90c6-97b3a820c963 </guid><title><![CDATA[Joint UK-Japanese research on waste and decommissioning]]></title><description><![CDATA[Two research projects are to receive funding totalling GBP1 million (USD1.2 million) from UK and Japanese research councils to develop technologies to detect and process radioactive waste. The research will support work to decommission the UK&#39;s Sellafield plant and remove radioactive debris from the Fukushima Daiichi accident in Japan.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 13:57:03 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Joint-UK-Japanese-research-on-waste-and-decommissi?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 0780c5f5-1986-49cb-86c6-333e0cbd740a </guid><title><![CDATA[Energoatom and ConverDyn sign uranium conversion MoU]]></title><description><![CDATA[Energoatom and ConverDyn have signed a confidentiality agreement and memorandum of understanding relating to uranium conversion which the Ukrainian company says can help the country towards a complete fuel cycle.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Sep 2023 14:44:17 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Energoatom-and-ConverDyn-sign-uranium-conversion-M?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> c9b39652-5220-45a0-a22c-5662a22e1254 </guid><title><![CDATA[Orano gives updates on uranium enrichment plans and Niger situation]]></title><description><![CDATA[Orano has revealed plans to extend enrichment capacity at its Georges Besse II uranium enrichment plant, and has begun the regulatory process to produce HALEU there. Separately, the company has confirmed it is &quot;reorganising&quot; work at its Niger operations to mitigate logistical impacts following the recent coup.]]></description><pubDate> Mon, 11 Sep 2023 14:54:06 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Orano-gives-updates-on-uranium-enrichment-plans-an?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>