<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><title><![CDATA[World Nuclear News]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/?rss=feed]]><description><![CDATA[World Nuclear News recent stories]]></description><language><![CDATA[en-GB]]></language><item><guid ispermalink="false"> aca01563-a4bd-4c80-82e3-3a3a76711704 </guid><title><![CDATA[Nuclear groups propose ‘stepwise’ approach to increased regulatory efficiency]]></title><description><![CDATA[A new joint report from World Nuclear Association, the Nuclear Energy Institute and the Canadian Nuclear Association proposes regulatory steps which can be taken to minimise the time and cost for large-scale deployment of a fleet of standardised reactor designs that are acceptable in multiple countries around the world.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 11:35:48 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Nuclear-groups-propose-stepwise-approach-to-increa?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 38f721a7-0305-402e-8e3c-4a67134eb5d6</guid><title><![CDATA[Environmental permit granted for first Polish plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[Poland&#39;s General Director for Environmental Protection has issued to Polskie Elektrownie Jadrowe its decision on the environmental conditions for the construction of a nuclear power plant in the province of Pomerania.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 14:58:30 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Environmental-permit-granted-for-first-Polish-plan?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 336f9d0c-9b54-47a1-b04d-ed2fe2ca12e5 </guid><title><![CDATA[BWXT, Crowley to work together on power plant vessel concept]]></title><description><![CDATA[BWX Technologies, Inc has teamed up with global shipping and maritime, energy and logistics solutions company Crowley to develop new shallow-draft hull ships to supply energy from onboard microreactors to shoreside locations.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 21:20:05 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/BWXT,-Crowley-to-work-together-on-power-plant-vess?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 2f555bf1-7190-4b24-91e3-597e17922ea4 </guid><title><![CDATA[Funding announced for Pallas research reactor]]></title><description><![CDATA[Minister of Health, Welfare and Sport Ernst Kuipers has confirmed full funding has been allocated for the EUR1.68 billion (USD1.79 billion) estimated public investment required for the Pallas research reactor in Petten, the Netherlands.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 13:52:24 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Full-funding-announced-for-Pallas-research-reactor?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 071d8c04-490b-4ca3-af69-95c006004b92 </guid><title><![CDATA[Milestone in restoration of Zorita plant site]]></title><description><![CDATA[Work to fill in the hole left following the demolition of the containment building of the José Cabrera nuclear power plant has been completed, Spanish decommissioning and waste management firm Enresa announced. The plant - also known as Zorita - is the first to be fully dismantled in Spain.]]></description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 10:25:53 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Milestone-in-restoration-of-Zorita-plant-site?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> dfa34975-4319-48ee-bcab-960b89c9de53 </guid><title><![CDATA[Regulatory changes needed for new nuclear for maritime]]></title><description><![CDATA[Nuclear will be needed to help decarbonise the shipping industry - whether by having nuclear-powered ships or using nuclear to produce alternative fuels - a conference organised by Core Power has heard. However, speakers noted that regulatory issues must be resolved before this can happen.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 13:56:26 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Regulatory-changes-needed-for-new-nuclear-for-mari?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 92aedbc1-fb85-43e3-a559-96f83223b496</guid><title><![CDATA[Westinghouse, Bechtel sign consortium agreement for Polish plant]]></title><description><![CDATA[Westinghouse Electric Company and Bechtel have signed a formal agreement to partner on the design and construction of Poland&#39;s first nuclear power plant at Lubiatowo-Kopalino. They expect to sign an engineering services contract with Polskie Elektrownie Jądrowe within the next week.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 15:00:47 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Westinghouse,-Bechtel-sign-consortium-agreement-fo?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 9ec371b2-7b38-4abf-a9a7-9e869878989e </guid><title><![CDATA[Fuel removed from first Hunterston B reactor]]></title><description><![CDATA[The defueling of the first of two reactors at the Hunterston B advanced gas-cooled reactor nuclear power plant in the UK has been completed on time and on budget, EDF Energy announced.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 10:22:13 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Fuel-removed-from-first-Hunterston-B-reactor?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> e12856d7-05b3-4f42-9a22-4cfdbfabcf80 </guid><title><![CDATA[Alberta funds SMR deployment study]]></title><description><![CDATA[The province has announced it is investing CAD7 million (USD5 million) in a multi-year study to explore how small modular reactors could be safely, technically and economically deployed for oil sands operations. It is also working on putting a regulatory framework in place to allow private industry to pursue SMRs.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 13:57:03 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Alberta-funds-SMR-deployment-study?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> 12b0c0f9-b4e2-43fe-a234-6c0319142734 </guid><title><![CDATA[Temelín switching to 18-month fuel cycle]]></title><description><![CDATA[Operator&nbsp;ČEZ says that the transition from a 12-month to an 18-month fuel cycle has begun at&nbsp;Temelín&#39;s second unit, part of the company&#39;s investment programme to boost efficiency and pave the way for the planned 60-year operation of the plant.]]></description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 11:34:03 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Temelin-switching-to-18-month-fuel-cycle?feed=feed]]></item><item><guid ispermalink="false"> fff03455-1bb1-4162-9189-378a23224ff4 </guid><title><![CDATA[World needs nuclear for net zero: John Kerry]]></title><description><![CDATA[Nuclear will be essential for the world to accelerate its transition away from fossil fuels, US Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry said at a New York summit this week. He also praised the recently launched Net Zero Nuclear Initiative - which has now welcomed GE Hitachi Nuclear Energy as its first corporate partner.]]></description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 21:34:04 GMT</pubDate> <link/><![CDATA[https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/World-needs-nuclear-for-net-zero-Kerry?feed=feed]]></item></channel></rss>